<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0025.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Daphne, Mary, Adam, Comfort, Tom, Ned, and Stephen v. Frederick Causey. Judgment Record.</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Chen, Ellis" xml:id="ec">Ellis Chen</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0025.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0679</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Earle, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Caroline County (Md.)</term> 
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgment for Petitioner</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>    

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Adam</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Comfort</persName> 
</person>
        
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Daphne</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mary</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ned</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Stephen</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tom</persName> 
</person>

<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Causey, Frederick</persName>
</person>

<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Goldsborough, Robert</persName>
</person>

<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-09" who="#ec">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8160.jpg"/>

<p>
Mulattoes Daphne 
Mary Adam Comfort
Tom Ned &amp;Stephen
against
Frederick Causey.
</p>

<p>
The State of Maryland. Be it remembered 
That Mulattoes Daphne, Mary, 
Adam, Comfort, Tom, Ned, and Stephen 
to the Court here prefers the following Petition 
to wit. To the Honourable the Judges of the
General Court for the Eastern Shore of Maryland
in Court now sitting The Petition of Mulattoes Daphne, Mary, Adam, 
Comfort, Tom, Ned, and Stephen Humbly Showeth That your Petitioners
are held and unjustly detained as Slaves by a certain Frederick Causey
of Caroline County. Your Petitioners therefore pray your Honors to Issue
Subpena against the said Frederick Causey to answer unto your Petitioners
of and upon the Premisses. And that your Petitioner may have such
relief in the Premisses as to your Honors may seem <unclear>meet </unclear> and your Petitioners
will ever Pray. Robert Goldsborough Counsel for Petitioners. 
</p>

<p>
Which Petition being read and Granted. it is by the said Court ordered
that Summons issue against the said Frederick Causey for his immediate
appearance to answer the Complaint of the afd. Petitioners which said Summons
being Issued and return being made of the same by the Sheriff of Caroline 
County for the time being that he hath Summoned the afd Frederick 
Causey to appear and Answer according to the Exigence of the same Summons.
</p>

<p>
And the afd Frederick Causey by Gustavus Scott his Attorney comes
and defends the force and Injury when and so forth and produces to the
Court his several Witnesses to testify  on his behalf of and upon the Premisses
And the said Petitioners in like manner and so forth.
</p>

<p>
Whereupon all and singular the Premisses being seen and by the Court
here fully understood and mature deliberation thereon had.
</p>

<p>
Therefore It is considered by the Court here that the afd Mulattoes
Daphne, Mary, Adam, Comfort, Tom, Ned and Stephen be no longer held
and detained as Slaves by the said Frederick Causey but that they the
same Mulattoes Daphne, Mary, Adam, Comfort, Tom, Ned and Stephen 
be and are set by the Court free and at full Liberty from the said Frederick
Causey to all intents and Purposes whatsoever <unclear></unclear> James Earle Clk
</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
