<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0005.005"><!-- Insert file name inside quotes. Check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.reu.0011.015 -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title> Paul Jones v. George Jones<!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Edward Queen v. John Ashton. Deposition of Thomas Warfield) --></title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Williams, Zoe" xml:id="ZW">Zoe Williams</name><!-- Add your name where indicated. -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.reu.0005.005<!-- file name - same as xml:id above --></idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0690<!-- caseid number, check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.caseid.0323 --></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main"> Interrogatory of Lewis F Linn, Eloy Le Compte, and John Scott=<!--Name of Document; e.g. - Deposition of Thomas Warfield --></title>
<date when="1840-09-19">September 19th, 1840</date><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Interrogatory<!--Type of Document; e.g. - Deposition --></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1840-09">September 1840</date></term><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Eloy Le Compte, John Le Compte, S. Le Compte, Lewis F. Linn, Mary, John Scott</term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. Mary was also known was Caiwnin-->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Illinois, Missouri, Wisconsin, St. Genevieve, Kaskaskia, Prairie Du Rocher</term><!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term><!-- Was the outcome of the case stated in this document? What was it? e.g. - Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Jones, Paul<!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName> Jones George<!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName> Wisconsin Territory District Court (Grant County)<!-- Name of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore --></orgName>
<placeName>Lancaster, WI<!-- Location of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-17" who="ZW">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p> State of Missouri County of St Genevieve</p>
<p>Paul Jones man of color
vs
G W Jones</p>
<p>Trespass on premises in the
district county for the county
of Grant Territory of Wisconsin
We the undersigned two of commissiners 
in the annexed commission named &amp; to us directed
by the Honorable the District court for the county of
<unclear></unclear> in the Territory of Wisconsin did on the
19<hi>th</hi> day of September AD 1840 cause to come before
us as the court house in the town of the St Genevieve 
and State of Missouri Lewis F Linn John Scott and
Eloy Le Compte three of the persons in the caption
of said several interrogatives named being unable
to procure the attendance of the others as witnesses to
answer said interrogatories or the part of the defendant
in the above named suit and they bring duly
sworn upon this corporal oaths  by us examined
diligantly &amp; faithfully upon said interrogatives
in the order in which they propounded and
the answer of each of them thereto annexed in the
order in which the same was given</p>
    
<p>Conrad L. Ziegler
La. Grafton</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p002"/>
    
<p>of these interrogatives named or either of them
and how long have you known them respectively</p>
    
<p>2<hi>nd</hi> Interrogatory- Are you acquainted with the 
hand writing of S. La Compte John H Le Compte
and Eloy Le Compte the vendors whose names
are signed to the annexed Bill of sale marked
A. if so pleae state;</p>
    
<p>3 interrogatory- Were you present when the said
Bill of Sale or instrument in writing was executed
and delivered to George W. Jones the defendant and
did you sign the same as subscribing witnesses</p>
    
<p>4<hi>th</hi>interrogatory- Is the signature of Lewis F Linn
attached to the said instrument of writing as
a subscribing witness to the same your own signature,
if so state when you signed the same
and at whose request?</p>
    
<p>5<hi>th</hi> interrogatory Are you or either of you acquainted
with the coloured man named Paul sold
and transferred in the said bill of sale and do
you or either of you know was  his mother
whether she was or is a slave so called under
the right of property secured to the ancient inhabitants
of the vilage of Kaskaskia and Prairie Du 
Rocher then north western territory now Illinois
by the orderance of congress of the thirtennth day
of July AD 1787 for the governemntof the 
Territory of the United States north west of the
Ohio river if so pleae state all you know in
relation to as fully as if particularly interrogated
thereto?-</p>
    
<p>6<hi>th</hi>interrgatory Do you know where and</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p003"/>
    
<p>mentioned in the said bill of sale and the plantiff
in this suit was born and whether before the
sale to the defendant George W Jones as aforesaid
he was bound to vendor service to this former
owner for life as a slave so called according
to the ancient usages and customs governing 
French and Canadian inhabitants of said
vilages</p>
    
<p>7 interrogatory Do you know if the sale of 
the said colored man called Paul mentioned
in the said bill of sale to the defendant was
with or against the wish &amp; request of the said
Paul and did or not the said Paul go willingly
into the service of the said defendant</p>
    
<p>8<hi>th</hi> interrogatory Do you known of any other matter
or thing further that may tend to the benefit
and advantages of the defendant in this cause
in the elucidation of this subject if so please
state fully &amp; particularly</p>
    
<p>When Lewis F Linn who being first duly sworn
answers to said interrogatories as follows to the
first he answers &amp; says that he knowns both the 
parties plaintiff and defendant that he has known
the plantiff &amp; defendant that he has known
the plaintiff about seventeen years and the defendant
since he was a small boy</p>

<p> And to the second interrogatory he answers &amp; says
that he is acquainted with the handwriting of S Le Compte
John H Le Compte &amp; Eloy Lecompte that the signatures
of said persons to the bill of sale marked A
is in the proper hand writing of said persons that
his knowledge of this handwriting is derived from
the part of having seen them often write &amp; also
from having seen them sign &amp; acknowledge</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p004"/>
    
<p>Said Bill of sale
and to the third interrogatory he answers &amp; says
that he was present when said instrument of writing
was executed &amp; delievered to George W Jones and that
he signed the same as a subscribing witness</p>

<p>And for answers to the fourth interrogatory
he answers &amp; says that the signatures of Lewis F
Linn to said instrument is his proper handwriting
&amp; signature and that he subscribed the same on the 
day and year it porports to be executed and at the
request of the parties thereto</p>

<p>And for answer to the 5<hi>th</hi>interrogatory he answers
and says that he has been acquainted with Paul
who was transferred by said bill of sale about
Seventeen years. that he (Paul) was brot to Missouri
from Illinois by the vendor as a slave that he was
by said bill of sale sold to George . W. Hones as a slave
and that Paul acknowledged to him <del></del> that he 
was a slave and that he was born in the family
of LE Compte in Illinois &amp; Prairie Du Rocher
and that <del>that<add>from part</add></del> of his own knowledge he believes that said
Paul was born in Illinois and that he always
understood that Paul was what was called 
a French slave. held under the ordinance
of the 13<hi>th</hi> July AD 1787 as to the mother of Paul
he say he knows nothing</p>
    
<p>And for the answer to the sixth interrogatory he says
that of his own knowledge he does not know when said
Paul was born but has always understood from
the family of Le compte &amp; from others that he was
born in Prairie Du Rocher Illinois as a French slave
And for answers to the the seventh interrogatory he 
answers &amp; says that the sale of Paul by the vendor
in the Bill of sale named to George. W. Jones was
made at the request and desire of Paul and
that Paul was very anxious that Jones </p>
    
<pb xml:id="p005"/>
    
<p>And for the answer to the 3<hi>d</hi>  interrogatory he
answers &amp; says that the mother of said Paul
was well known to him that she was a Slave
in Illinois prior to the year 1787 that she was purchased
of one Lacond resident of Illinois either a Canadian
by birth or <del><add></add></del> of Canadian parents that she resided
until within a few years in the village of Prairie Du Rocher
Illinois that she was sometimes called so mulle alias
Caiwnin that her right name is Mary that he always
understood from the family and others that she was
what was called a French slave for life she purchased
her freedom of S. Le. Compte between the years 1820 and
1824 for the sum of two hundred dollars as near as 
he can remember</p>

<p> And for answer to the 4<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he says
that Paul was born in the Village of Prairie
Du Rocher Illinois about the year 1805</p>
 
<p>And for answer to the 5<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he says
that Paul was held as a slave to service for life
in Illinois under the laws &amp; usages of the late North
Western Territory in favor of the ancient French
&amp; Canadian inhabitants of the villages of Kashkakia
Prairie Du Rocher &amp; Chahokia &amp; that said Paul was
born the property of the father of deponent who
always resided in Prairie Du Rocher Illinois and that
he never was Canadian other than a slave for life</p>

<p>And for answer to the 6<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he says
that from the information received from the family
and from others who were old enough to known
he always understood &amp; believes that the mother
of Paul was a slave in Prairie Du Rocher Illinois
prior to the 13 July 1787 held &amp; owned and such
by one of the Canadian inhabitants mentioned 
in the 5<hi>th</hi> interrogatory And for answer to
the 7<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he replies that from information
derived from the family that the mother of Paul
was held by the above named Lacond as a slave
for life prior to 13<hi>th</hi> July 1787</p>
   
<pb xml:id="p006"/>

<p>And for answer to the 8<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he answers
&amp; that he is in no wise directly or indirectly 
interested in the event of the said between Plantiff
&amp; defendant above named</p>

<p>And for answer to the 9<hi>th</hi> interrogatory he answers
 &amp; says that he does not now remeber
anything further that would tend to illucidate the
mother in controversy    Eloy Le Compte</p>

<p>We the undersigned two of the commissioners to
whom the annexed commission was directed do
herby certify that Lewis F Linn John Scott &amp; Eloy
Le Compte three if the witnesses in the caption of the
interrogatories named on the 9<hi>th</hi> day of september AD 1840
of the court house in the town of St Genevieve and
State of Missouri appeared before us to answer said
interrogatories which were then &amp; there propounded to
them in the order in which the same are herein set
forth and were by us first sworn on the Holy 
of almighty god to make true &amp; full answers to
interrogatories and the answers herein given &amp; set forth
are the answers given by said witnesses respectively and
the signatures of said witnesses <hi>to said depostiion</hi> in the proper hand writing
of said witnesses who subscribed the same in our
presence on the day and year aforesaid at the place
aforesaid and that said deponents were sworn to the court
of said depositions after the same were reduced to writing
&amp; subscribed by them of the time &amp; place aforesaid
In witness whereof we have herewith
set on hands this 9<hi>th</hi> day of september 1840
St genevieve State of Missouri</p>

<p>Conrad L. Ziegler
La. Grafton</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
