<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0029.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John and James v. Edward Harris. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Zuniga, Santiago" xml:id="sz">Santiago Zuniga</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0029.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0684</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1794-09-13">September 13, 1794</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1794-09">September 1794</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006942">Earle, James, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.007003">Harris, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.007004">Hirey, Thomas Hill</term>
<term xml:id="per.007005">Wright, Sam</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Delaware</term>
<term>Queen Ann's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Talbot County (Md.)</term>
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Dorchester County (Md.)</term>
<term>Chester Mills (Md.)</term>
<term>Easton (Md.)</term>
<term>Dover (De.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judement for Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.007006">John</persName>
<persName xml:id="per.007007">James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.007008">Harris, Edward</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.007009">Nicholson, Joseph Hopper</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.007010">Tilghman, William</persName>
<persName xml:id="per.004664">Martin, Luther</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-12" who="#SZ">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8144.jpg"/>

<p>Negroes John &amp; James against Edward Harris</p>

<p>The Plaintiffs by Joseph H Nicholson their attorney <unclear>impaliatid</unclear> the State's
unit of Ceriorari by virtue of which said writ the following accord was affiled on the
11th of Sept 1793, <unclear>org</unclear>.</p>

<p>"N. John &amp; James, Negroes</p>

<p>T. Edward Harris.</p>
    
<p>Petition for freedom.</p>

<p>Be it remembered that at
a Country Court held for Queen Ann's County at Chester Mills in the said Counthy on the <add>third</add> Monday in May
in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, Joseph Hopper Nicholson Attorney
for the Petitioners, presented to the Court then presentm and filed the following Petition, to writ:</p>

<p>To the honorable the Justices of Queen Ann's County Court, the Petition of Negroes John &amp; James humbly
sheweth that your Petitioners were sometime past brought into this State from the Town of Dover
in the Delaware state, that your Petitioners are now held by the Edward Harris Esq. as slaves and
do conceive themselves entitled by the laws of the State of Maryland to this freedom. Your Petitioners
therefore do humbly may your honors to take their case into consideration, and to order subpenas tofore
for their witnesses, and your petitioners will we pray &amp;c.</p>

<p>Joseph H Nicholson for Petitioners</p>
    
<p>Mr. Thomas <add><unclear> </unclear></add> Harris of 2 A County Thomas Hill Hirey Dorchester County.</p>

<p>At which, same Court, to writ, the third Monday in May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred
and ninety two, the aforesaid Edward Harris by William Tilghman his attorney comes and defends the
free and inquiry when and so forth, and prays leave of the Court here present to <unclear>imparle</unclear> thereunto at the
next County Court to be held at Chestser Mills in the County aforesaid on the second Monday on November
then must ensuing - which said prayer is by the Court here allowd, and ordered that the same day by
likewise given unto the Petitioners, who likewise have it, and so forth. At which same time, to writ:</p>
    
<p>The second Monday in November in the year seventeen hundred and ninety two, the Parties afd by their
Attornies aforesaid again comes before the Court here present and the said Edward Harris by his
Attorney aforesaid again prayer have further to imparle thereto until the next Court, and he hath it
and the same day is likewise given to the Petitioner who also have it soforth. At which, same time,
to writ, the third Monday in May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety
three then the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys afd, again come. And the Petitioners by Joseph
Hopper Nicholson their attorney, produce to the Court here the State's unit of certiorari which he
prays the Court may allow. Whereupon the same Court after mature consideration do allow the
same and order that a Transcript of the Record may be transmitted agreeably to the Command
thereof - and which said writ of Certioari is closed in there words following, to writ.</p>

<p>"The State of Maryland Ye! To the Justices of Queen Ann's County Court, Greeting: Whereas
Negro's John and James hath pursued a Petition before you our said Justices
humbly shewing that thy the said John and James are unjustly and unlawfully
detained as Slaves by Edward Harris of Queen Ann's County, which said Petition is still depending</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8145.jpg"/>

<p>before you in our said court, as it is said, and we being desirous for certain reason that the Record of the
said Petition should by you be certified to us to command you that you send under you seals the
Record of the Petition aforesaid and all the proceedinfs thereon, until all things touching the same
to the Judges of our General Court to be held for the Eastern Shore of this State, at Easton in
Talbot County the second Monday of September next, plainly &amp; distinctly and in as full and ample manner
as it now remains before you, together with this unit, so that we may be able thereon to proceed and
do what shall appear to us of right ought to be done. Witness the Honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief
Judge of our said Court the ninth day of April Anno Dom 1793. </p>

<p>Issued the 20th day of May 1793. (J H Nicholson)</p>

<p>James Earle junr Clk:</p>

<p>Queen Ann's County towit, I do hereby <unclear>ustify</unclear> that the written and aforegoing is a true Transcript from
the Records of Proceedings of Queen Ann's County Court. In Testimony where of I have hereto set my
<add>Seal</add> <gap></gap> Hand and affixed the public seal of Queen Ann's County afd this third day of September
in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three. Sam Wright Clk of Queen Ann's County Court.
At which said second Tuesday of September, in the year Seventteen hundred ninety three, towit the day of the
return of the aforementioned unit of Ceriorari, here came into Court as well the said Negroes John &amp; James
by their said Attorney, as the said Edward Harris by William Tilghman &amp; Luther Martin Esquire
his Attorneys and thereupon the process of &amp; upon the premises afd between the Parties afd <unclear>wascention</unclear>
by the court till the second Tuesday of April then next following &amp; soforth.--</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of April, towit in the year of our Lord Seventeen hundred ninety four
here came again into Court the Parties afd, by their Attorney afd, whereupon the Process upon the
premises between the said Parties was further continued by the Court until the second Tuesday of
September then next &amp;c.</p>

<p>And now at this day towit. The said second Tuesday of September in
the year <del>year</del> seventeen hundred and ninety four, here come again into Court the Parties afd by their
Attorneys afd; whereupon all &amp; singular the premises as well on the part &amp; behalf of the said Plaintiffs
as the Defendant being by the Court here seen, heard &amp; fully understood and mature deliberation been
had, it is considered by the Court that the Petition be dismissed, and that the said Negroes John &amp;
James return to the services of the said Edward Harris their Master. </p>

<p>Test James Earle junr Clk</p>

<p>Judgement rendered as above on the 13th day of September Anno Domini 1794.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
