<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0250.010
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Davis v. Hezekiah Wood</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>Autumn Green</resp>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0250.010</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0210</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Davis v. Hesekiah Wood</title>
<date when="<!-- yyyy-mm-dd -->"><!-- June 25, 1810 --></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 267</collection>
<idno>Box # 33 Folder 691</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term><!-- Document Type. See list on website. --></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="yyyy-mm"><!-- Month Year --></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term></term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term></term><!-- Organize by largest place entity first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed; consult website list of attorneys for help; link on Trello. -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed; consult website list of attorneys for help; link on Trello. -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2022-06" who="#ini">#AG.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_3525.jpg"/>

<p>District of Columbia Court</p>
<p>As a Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Columbia and County of Washington begun and held in and for the County of Washington at the City of Washington on the first monday of June being the <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough" </gap> seventh day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and thirteen and of the independence of the United States the 37th.</p>
<p>The Honorable 
<lb>Wiliam Cranch esq. Chief Judge </lb><lb>Nicholas Fitzhugh</lb><lb>Buckmen Thrusten Esq. Assistant Judge</lb><lb>Washington Boyd Esq. Marshal</lb><lb>William Brent, Clerk</lb>

In the record of proceedings of the same Court among them is the following tort. 

<lb>John Davis, Terese Davis, and Mary Davis Petitioners</lb>
<lb>against</lb>
 <lb>Hezekiah Wood, Defendants</lb>
 
 Be it remembered that heretofore tourt on the twenty sixth day of January in the year of our Lord Eighteen hundred and thirteen the following writ of the United States was <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough" </gap> filed in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Columbia and County of Washington towt, "United States of America SS. The President of the United States, to the Judges of the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Columbia in the County of Washington Greetings: Whereas lately in the Circuit
    
 <pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_3528.jpg"/>
 <p> Court of the United States for the District of Columbia in the County of Washington in a cause whrein John, Terese, and Mary Davis were plaintiff, or petitioners, and Hezekiah Wood was defendant on a petition for freedom judgement was rendered by the said Circuit Court for the said plaintiff, or petitioners by the inspection of the Transcript of the record of the said Circuit Court which was brought into the Supreme Court of the United States, agreeably to teh Act of Congress in such case made and provided fully and at large appears. And whereas in teh Term of Takeaway in the year of our lord one thousand eight hundred and twelve the said cause came on to be heard before the said Supreme Court on teh said Transcript of the record of the said Circuit Court and was argued by counsel, on consideration whereof. It is  the opinion of the Court that the said Circuit Court erred in giving the direction prayed by the counsel for the petitioners. It is-therefore adjudged ordered and decreed that teh judgement of the said Circuit Court in the case be and the same is hereby reversed and annulled, and the said cause is hereby remanded to the said Circuit Court for further proceedings to be had therein according to law. and the same is hereby remanded accordlingly. 
     You therefore are hereby commanded that such proceedings be had in said cause as according to right and justice and the Laws of the United States, and agreeably to the said opinion and judgment of teh said Supreme Court- ought to be had, the said writ of error notwithstanding. Wittness the Honorable John Marshall Chief Justice of Said Supreme Court, this first monday in August, in the year of our Lord one 

</p>
    
 <pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_3533.jpg"/>
 <p>thousand eight hundred and twelve, </p>
 
 <lb>E.B. Caldwell, Clerk, Sup. Ct. U.S</lb>
 
 <p>And now here at the day towt the first monday of June 1813comes again into Court here as well <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough" </gap> the said <gap extent="three words" reason="Strikethrough" </gap> by Edmund L. Lee and James S. Morsell Esquire, their attornies as the said Hezekiah Wood by Walter Jones Lund &amp Thomas S. Key his attornies 
    Whereupon for trying the issue joined between the parties aforesaid. It is ordered by the Court here that twenty persons from the panel of petit jurors returned to teh Court here by the Marshal of the District aforesaid be drawn by ballot according to the act of Assembly in such case made and provided, and thereupon the twenty persons being so drawn by ballot, and witten upon two lists one of which said lists is delivered to the Counsel for the respective parties, and the counsel for each of the said parties having others out for persons from the said lists, thereupon the remaining twelve persons bring called come towrt: Archabald Lee William Duwall Benjamin Bryar Lehiel Crassfield George StClair, Thomas Reynolds, Jeremiah Mudd, Walter B. Beall, Joseph Clarke, Joseph Ward, Alexander McCormick, and William Emack, who being enpannelled, and sworn to say the truth in the promise, upon their oath do say, that <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough" </gap> teh said John Davis, Terese Davis, and Mary Davis are not free as they by their petition aforesaid have alleged. Therefore it is considered by the Court here that the said Hezekiah Wood go thereof without delay and soforth 
 <lb>Wits. Wm. Brent Clerk. </lb>
 Memorandum Before teh jurors aforesaid returned from the Bar of the Court here to consider of and upon their verdict aforesaid the said John Davis, Terese Davis, and Mary Davis by their attornies aforesaid filed in Court here this following
</p>
    
 <pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_3535.jpg"/>
 <p>Bill of exceptions which is signed sealed and <gap extent="one word" reason="smudged ink" </gap> accordingly to the Act Assembly in such case made and provided and which is as follows towt, </p>
 <lb>John Davis</lb>
<lb>Terese Davis</lb>
<lb>Mary Davis</lb>
 <lb>v.</lb>
 <lb>Hezekiah Wood</lb>
    
<p>Memorandum, upon the trial of this cause the Petitioenrs offered to prove by competent witnesses that they the said witnesses have heard old persons who are now dead declare that a certain Mary Davis now dead, was a white woman born in England, and such was teh general report in the neighborhood where the said Mary Davis lived- and also offered the same kind of testimony to prove that Susan Davis the mother of the petitioners was lineally descdended in the female line from the said Mary Davis, and it was admitted that the said Susan Davis was at the time of the commencement of this peition for and acting in all respects as a free woman which evidence by hearsay and general reputation as aforesaid teh Court reused to admit-except so far as it was applicable to the facts o fpedigree of the peitioners to which reusal the petitioners except and this their bill of exceptions is signed sealed and enrolled htis sixth July 1813.</p>
 <lb> W. Cranch Seal </lb>
  <lb> N. Fitzhugh Seal</lb>
 <lb>John Davis</lb>
  <lb>Therese Davis</lb>
 <lb>Mary Davis</lb>
 <lb>v.</lb>
 <lb>Hezekiah Wood</lb>
    
<p>In the trial of this cause the petitioners to support the issue on their part joined proved that the petitioners are the Children of Susan Davis that the said Susan Davis is the same person named in the following record (here insert it) they their offered to read the said record in evidence to the Jury as prima facie evidence that the said petitioners are the descendants of the </p>
    
 <pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_3536.jpg"/>
<p>female line from a free woman who was born free and are of free condition connected with the fact that the defendant in this case sold the said Susan Davis to Coll. Susan the person- mentioned as the defendant in the aforesaid record, But the Court refused to suffer the petitioners to read the said record to the jury as evidence in this cause. To which refusal the petitioners except &amp this their bill of exceptions is signed sealed and enrolled this 6th of July 1813. </p>
 <lb>W. Cranch</lb>
 <lb>N. Fitzhugh</lb>
 <p>And thereupon teh said John Davis Terese Davis and Mary Davis by their attornies aforesaid pray on Appeal from the judgment aforesaid, so as aforesaid rendered to the Supreme Court of the United States and it is granted them whereupon the said John Davis, Terese Davis, and Mary Davis by their attornies aforesaid, filed in Court here a certain writing obligating commonly called an Appeal Bond and which is concurred in the following words cont. Throw all men by these present, that we Daniel Renner and Joel Brown are held and firmly bound unto Hezekiah Wood in the full and just sum of two hundred dollars to be paid to the said Hezekiah Wood certain attorney, executes, administers, or assigns: to which payment well and trully to be made, we bind ourselves, our heirs, executor, and administrator jointly and severally by those present, sealed with our seals and dated this twenty first day of February in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fourteen. Whereas lately at a Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Columbia in Washington County in June Term of said Court last past in a suit depending </p>
    
<pb xml:id="p006" facs="IMG_3541.jpg"/>
    
  <p> in said Circuit Court wherein John, Terese, and Mary Davis were petitioenrs and Hezekiah Wood was defendant. Judgement was rendered against the said Petitioners and the said Petitioners having obtained a writ of error and filed a copy thereof in the Clerks office of the said Circuit Court to reverse teh judgment in the aforesaid suit, and a citation directed to the said Hezekiah Wood citing and admonishing him to be and appear at a Supreme Court of the United States, to be holden at Washington on the first Monday of February instant . 
      Now the condition of the above obligation is such, that if the said Petitioners shall prosecute their writ to effect and answer all damages and costs if they fail to make their plea good, the the above obligation to be void else to remain in full force and viewed. 
  <lb>sealed and delivered in presence of Robert Brent Thomas B. Gilpin</lb>
 <lb>Danl. Renners Seal</lb>
 <lb>Jack Brown Seal</lb>
  
<p>which being read and heard and the securities in the said Bond being by the Court here approved it is therefore ordered by teh said Court here that the record and proceedings aforesaid in the plea aforesaid, with all things thereunto relating be transmitted to the said Supreme Court of the United States; and the same are transmitted to the said Court accordingly. </p>
 <lb>Test. Wm. Brent clerk</lb>
    
    
<pb xml:id="p007" facs="IMG_3543.jpg"/>
    
 <p><lb>United States</lb>
 <lb>The President Of the Untied States</lb>
 <lb>To the Judges of the Circuit Court of the United States for the district of:</p>   
 <p>Columia in the County of Washington Greetings: Because in the record and proceedings as also in the rendition of the judgment of a plea which is in the said circuit court before you, or some of you, between: John, Terese, and Mary Davis Petitioners and Hezekiah Wood Defedant</p>
<p>a manifest error hath happened, to the great damage of the said Petitioners as by their complaint appears. We being willing that error, if any hath been, should be judly corrected, and full and speedy justice done to the parties aforesaid in this behalf: Do command you, if judgment be therein given , that then under your seal distinctly and openly, you send the record and proceedingings aforesaid, with all things concerning the same to the Supreme Court of the United States, together with this writ, so that you have the same at Washington on the first Monday of February next, in the said Supreme Court, to be then and there held, that the record and proceedings aforesaid being inspected, the said Supreme Court may cause further to be done therein to correct that error, what of right and according to the law and custom of the United States should be done. 
    Witness, the honorable John Marshall chief justice of the said Supreme Court, this First monday of August in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and thirteen and of the Independence of the Untied States the thirty eighth. <lb>B. Caldwell Clk. Sup. Ct. U.S</lb></p>
    
    
<pb xml:id="p008" facs="IMG_3545.jpg"/>    
      
<p>Davis v. Wood Filed 22. Febry. 1814</p>
      
<pb xml:id="p009" facs="IMG_3547.jpg"/>
    
 <p>District of Columbia Towrt: 
     At a Circuit Court of the District of Columbia begun and held in and for the County of Washington at the City of Washington on teh fourth monday of december being teh Monday sicth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand Eight hundred and Eight , and of American Independence the thirty third.</p>
 <lb>Honorable</lb>
<lb>WIlliam Cranch Esquire, chief judge </lb>
 <lb>Nicholas Fitzhugh</lb>
 <lb>Allen B. Duckett, Esquire Assistant Judge</lb>
 <lb>Washington Boyd Esquire Marshal William Brent Clerk</lb>
 <p>In the Record of proceedings of teh same Court, amongst others in the following Towt. 
 <lb>Susan Davis, Then Daughter, Against Caleb Swann</lb> 
 <p>Be it remembered that heretofore towt on the fourth day of September in the year of our lord one thousand Eight hundred and seven the said Susan and any by Henry Robert their attorney filded in Court here teh following petition to teh Honbl. the judges of the Circuit Court of the County of Washington in teh District of COlumbia, teh humble Petn. of SUsan Davis &amp her daughter Amy humbly showeth that your petitioners are detained in slavery by Caleb Swann &amp as they were born free, they pray that prcoess may be awarded 
     
<pb xml:id="p0010" facs="IMG_3553.jpg"/>
     
<p> to compell the appearance of the said Caleb Swann to answer their complaint</p>
<lb>H. Hiort for Complle.</lb>
<lb>14th Sept. 1809</lb>
<p>Whereupon a suit of the United States of subpoena issued to the marshal of the District of Columbia, in the words and of the letter following, this is to say: 
    "District of Columbia Court: The United States of America to the marshal of the District of Columbia, Greetings: 
    You are hereby commanded to summon Caleb Swann that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before teh Circuit Court of the District of Columbia, to be held in and for the County of Washington at the City of Washington on teh fourth monday of december next then and there to answer teh petition of negro Susan Davis and her daughter Amy in the said Court exhibited against him for their freedom. Hereof fail not at your peril and have you then and there thiw writ. Witness William Cranch, Esq. Chief Judge fo the said Court the 31st day of August 1807. heard the 21st day of September 1807. Hiort. Wm. Brent Clerk. 
        At which said Fourth monday of december being the Twenty eigth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and seven, and the return day of the aforegoing writ of subpoena come into the Circuit Court here, the said Susan and Amy by their </p>
        
 <pb xml:id="p0011" facs="IMG_3556.jpg"/>
     
 <p>said attorney; and the marshal of the District of Columbia aforesaid, to whom the said Subpoena was in form aforesaid decided, makes return thereof to the Court here, thus endorsed</p>
 <lb> Swn. 4th Sept. 1807</lb>
 <p>Danl. Brent marshal. and the said Caleb Swann being called appears in court here by Francis S. Key and Elias B. Caldwell his attornies: whereupon the Court here, on motion of the said Petitioners by their said attorney orders the said Caleb Swan to enter unto recognization in the sum of eight hundred dollars current money, conditioned that the said Caleb Swan, do not remove the said petitioners out of the District of Columbia nor obstruct them from attending this court from time to time in support of their said petition; Thereupon the said Caleb Swann present here in court, acknowledges himself to owe and stand justly in debted unto the United States of America in the sum of Eight hundred dollars current money to be levied up his body goods and chattels. <unclear>consideration</unclear> to and for the use of the United States on condition that he the said Caleb Swan do not remove Susan Davis and her daughter Amy out of the District of Columbia no obstruct them from attending this court from time to time, in support of their petition for freedom exhibited in the said Court against him the said Caleb Swan and in the mean time to feed cloath and see them well. And thereupon, on motion of the said Petitioners by their attorney aforesaid, it is ruled by the Court here that the </p>
 
 <pb xml:id="p0012" facs="IMG_3559.jpg"/>
     
 <p>said Caleb Swan answer to the petition aforesaid, of the said petitioners on the plea aforesaid or judgment by the Court here will be remembered against him by defailt, and the said Caleb Swan by his said attornies, defends the force and injury when to and prays leave of the Court here to imparte untill the first monday of June next to answer to the petition of the said Petitioners in the plea aforesaid and he hath it, the same day is given, to the said petitioners then vc. At which mentioned first monday of June being the sixth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and eight untill which day the said Caleb Swan had lease to imparts and then to answer to the Petition of the said Petitioners in the plea aforesaid, come as well the said Petitioners by their said attorney; as the said Caleb Swan by his said attorney. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by counsel of said parties, and their attornies aforesaid and by laws of the Court herethereon is further continued untill the fourth monday of december next.  
     And now here at the day towrt. the fourth monday of December being the twenty sixth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand Eight hundred and eight come again into the Circuit Court for as well the said Petitioners by Henry Hurt and Walter Jones Junner their attornies: as the said Caleb Swan by his attornies aforesaid. 
     And the said Caleb Swan by his said attornies come and defends the force and injury when he and says that the </p>
     
 <pb xml:id="p0013" facs="IMG_3561.jpg"/>
 
 <p>the said Susan and her daughter Amy are the proper slaves of him the said Caleb without that that the said Susan &amp Amy are free women &amp of free condition &amp that he is ready to verify, wherefore he pray sjudgment if the said Susan &amp Amy &amp their action aforesaid to have or maintain ought by anything before by the said Caleb in pleadings alleged , they ought not to be precluded from having said maintaining their action aforesaid against the said Caleb, because protesting, that they are not slaves, but are free born, and this they pray may be enquard of by the Country he and the said Caleb in like manner &amp c. 
     Therefore let a jury therefore appear before the Court here immediately by when &amp c and who neither &amp c to recognize &amp c Because as well &amp c who being calleld come that is to say- James Veitch, Charles King, Alexander C. Sncherez, Jeremiah Boothe, David Wharn, Griffith Coonber, John Hollinghead, Adam Lindsay, Nicholas L. Queens, George Moore, <unclear>Nathanial Newton</unclear> and to him thereupon who being Subpoenaed and worn to say the truth in the premises upon their oath do say, that they find for the Petitioners; Therefore It is considered by the Court here, that the said Susan davis and her daughter Amy, the petitioners aforesaid, recover their freedom of and against the said Caleb Swan and that they before and discharged of and from the service of the said Caleb Swan and that they Therese Susan Davis and her daughter Amy go thereof freed and </p>
 
 <pb xml:id="p0014" facs="IMG_3564.jpg"/>
     
<p>discharged without day &amp c. It is also considered by this Court here, that the said Susan Davis and her daughter Amy recover against the said Caleb Swan the sum of thirty seven dollars sixty two and one half cents and the quantity of one hundred and Eighty six pounds of tabacco by the Court here unto the said Susan Davis &amp c her daughter Amy, adjudged on their assent for their costs and charge by them about the <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"</gap> prosecution of their petition aforesaid did out and expended and that they have thereof their of their execution, &amp c. 
    Memorandum, judgement rendered in this cause for the petitioners for their freedom an dcosts of prosecution on the eighteenth day of January Amno Domini One thousand Eight Hundred and Nine-Wm. Brent Clerk. </p>
     <lb>District of Columbia, Tourt: </lb>
  <p>I William Brent Clerk of the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia for the County of Washington do hereby certify that the aforegoing is truly taken from the words and proceedings of this said court. 
      Be testimony whereof I hereunto subscribe my name and affix the seal of the said Court this Monday seventh day of March Amno Domini 1809. </p>
     <lb> Wm. Brent Clerk</lb>
     <p>District of Columbia towt. I William Cranch Chief jduge of the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia do hereby certify that the aforegoing attestation by WIlliam Brent clerk of the said court for the County of Washington and from the City of Washington. 29th day of September 1812 W. Cranch</p>
         
  <pb xml:id="p0015" facs="IMG_3568.jpg"/>
     
<p>Susan Davis &amp her daughter Amy against Caleb Sswan: Petition for Freedom and judgment therin for the petitioners  Transcript. District of Columbia Term -</p>
     
<pb xml:id="p0016" facs="IMG_3570.jpg"/>
     
<p>District of Columbia Washington County set. </p>
<p>I William Brent Clerk of the Circuit Court of teh District of Columbia and County aforesaid hereby certify that the aforegoing is herby taken and copied from the record of proceedings of the County aforesaid in the aforesaid mentioned suit wherein John Terese and Mary Davis are petitioners and the said Hezekiah Wood is defendant. 
    In Testimony whereof I hereunto subscribe my name and affix the seal of said Court this 26th day of July 1814. 

Wm. Brent clerk</p>
     
<pb xml:id="p0017" facs="IMG_3571.jpg"/>
     
 <p>Negro John Davis v. Hezekiah Wood <gap extent="one word" reason="damaged document" </gap> 
 filed 14th August 1814. S. Court. 1816</p>
     
 <pb xml:id="p0018" facs="IMG_3574.jpg"/>
     
  <p>To the Honorable John Brown, Judge of the Closest District Court <gap extent="three words" reason="faded document" </gap> petitions of John Davis and his sisters to the Court complaint exhibits <gap extent="four words" reason="faded ink" </gap> your honorable Court against this respondent, <gap extent="three" reason="faded ink" </gap> George <gap extent="one word" reason="faded ink" </gap> John <gap extent="one word" reason="faded ink" </gap> Thomas <gap extent="four words" reason="faded ink" </gap> Alexander <gap extent="five words" reason="faded ink" </gap> Kinkaid, by Counsel <gap extent="one word" reason="faded ink"" </gap> complaintant, your respondent having gone to the <unclear>Virginia </unclear> territory to transact some <gap extent="one word" reason="faded ink </gap> in which he was <gap extent="one word" reason="faded ink" </gap> intested in the <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt document" </gap> to return as soon as he could with considerable proprioty to his residence in the County of <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document" </gap> of Virginia the aforesaid until <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document" </gap> restituted against him and the other defendant he's agrieved, by the complaintant in your honorable Court and finding that the said Alexander <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document" </gap> who had given a partner in <gap extent="two words" reason="damaged documetn"</gap> with your respondent and stood largely indebted respondent, and been possessed of considerable <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> at Saint Genevieve in the the aforesaid Territory <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> aforesaid this life, with the view of reasoning procure some part of Wilsons <gap extent="one word" reason="damaged document"</gap> to incomining respondent for the cases and injurious was sustained by his management, was, if practical to obtain some widening out of the estate of Wilson for the claims your respondent had against him, he was in <gap extent="three words" reason="damaged document"</gap> is said territory there he assigned <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> where he first realised the plan of which evidence and very little asail as matters heard <gap extent="two words" reason="faded document"</gap> calculating his purpose reversing his stay as which is for the aforesaid suit was instituted against him, and he then defendant and a decree promised by <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> honorable Court in favor of the complaintant who will now fully and at large appear by reference to the record and proceedings still remain</p>
     
 <pb xml:id="p0019" facs="IMG_3577.jpg"/>
     
<p>Your honorable Court Restates that he has now returned to his residence in the County of Batts and brings to be permitted to give his answer to the complaintants bill in this Court and to be permitted to respond the aforesaid bill. as for answer to said bill, he begs Court to <gap extenet="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> the following- He admits that he together with Alexander Wilson executed a writ of land to the complaintant, bearing date the 30th day of June in this year 1810 for payment of Nine hundred and ninety dollars and thirty five cents six months after the aforesaid nine, as set forth in teh Circ. He admits that <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> judgements had been obtained by him and Alexander <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> against said Thomas L. Lowes before the expected <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> respondent to the Missouri Terriroy where<gap extent="one word" reason="burnt documetn"</gap> made a large amount- sent said Lewis had <gap extent="one word"reason="burnt document"</gap> adn was permitted by the sheriff to <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt documenrt"</gap> from process and that a suit was there depending <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt edges"</gap> the Sheriff of Bath and his securties on account <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt paper"</gap> escape. He states that he had a large amount, the <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt document"</gap>people in the County of Bath at the time of his <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document</gap>and cept a valuable zeal people it is said owing a rent, a part of which real property has <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> himself. He states that the complaint has <gap extetn="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> in a most <unclear>pedantic</unclear> and oppressive measure against him. That he and his agents have, as he <gap extentt="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> persecuted him with relentless energy. That it satisfied unto proceeding to recover said deor by process of this Court, not of the estate of your respondent aforesaid Wilson which remained in the County of Baths has, which your respondent was in the Missouri Territory aforesaid, at Saint Genevieve, sum preceeding account for the very identure goods in a <gap extend="two words" reason="burnt document"</gap> for which said letter was executed, of the <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> date and for the same amount, which account need in the hands of a Wiliam W. Scott. </p>
     
 <pb xml:id="p0020" facs="IMG_3580.jpg"/>
     
<p> attorney at law practising at Saint Genevive in said Territory re which Suit in re George <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> indexed against your respondent for the sum of $11-41.59 cents log this with costs, notwithstanding in all to the sum of $1212.59 cents to satisfy which your respondents body together with his property were taken by the Sheriff. <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> satisfying and paying the sum first the attorney aforesaid complaintant and the Sheriff your respondent body was released from confinement- all which unto fully and at large appear by reference to an authenticated copy of the record &amp proceedings which suit at Saint Genevieve in the name of said complaint against your respondent and said Alexander w. which is hereto annexed and prayed to be taken as part of this answer- He denies that ever he contained or became liable either individually or jointly said Wilson to pay any debt to said complaintant than that contained in said note aforesaid which positively and to be the same debt for which <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> bear and raising had against him as aforesaid <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> the aforesaid account, in the action retaining him at Saint Genivieve, and of then, and he <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap>: by news that hte whole amount of said judgement paid with all costs will satisfied and paid by him are of his property before his departing from Saint Genevieve on his return to homes- By the complaint made of proceeding at Law and equity he has compelled your respondent to pay the same debt twice over, who in a <unclear> special </unclear> of paid and opposition your respondent feels satisfied will not be <unclear>locmailed?</unclear> by this honorable Court. He states that he has had <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt document"</gap> with the complaintant, when in argument become <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> to him since the 30th of June 1810 Nor was he <gap extent="two words" reason="burnt document"</gap> his pursuant empacting a jointly with Wilson indebted to him that Tenet in any other issue than that contained in said note of hand. He states that Wilson has departed this life greatly indebted</p>
     
 <pb xml:id="p0021" facs="IMG_3583.jpg"/>
     
<p> your respondent , but from the damaged situations in which he found the <unclear> handwritten</unclear> of Wilson at Saint Genevieve <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"></gap> he expects to receive little or no compensations thereupon.  He prays that the Escrow <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> against him in this cause may be set aside by this honorable Court, that the cases decided against your respondent in favor of the complaintants may <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"></gap> required to your respondent as also the amount of said debt with not least 80-another he may be heard <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> with his costs in this behalf most <gap extent="two words" reason="faded and burnt document"</gap> 80. <p>
 <p>On the County Touit-
 John Davis personally appears before Chas A Lewis a Justice of the peave in and for said <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt documetn"</gap> and made oath that the statements contained in <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> answers are to the best of his knowledge <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt documetn"</gap> Given under my hand this 25th day of Nove. 
 Chas. A. Lewis</p>
  <p> Letter of Doring Kill of St. Genevieve afixxed with this <gap extent="one word" reason="gap"</gap> marked D. </p>
 <p>Territory of Missouri County of Saint Genevieve <gap extent="one word"reason="burnt documetn"</gap> Waters against Alexander Wilson &amp John Davis</p>
 <p>Please contained <gap extent="one word" reason="faded document"</gap>the Town of Saint Genevieve in and for the County of Saint Genevieve on the second monday of July one thousand eight hundred and thirteen. Before the Honorable Wm. Thomas Clark <gap extent="four words" reason="faded document"</gap> esquires as judges </p>
 <p> Be it remembered that heretofor a court on the monday following one thousand eight hundred and thirteen <gap extent="one word" reason="burnt document"</gap> Waters by John Siou his attorney filed here in the clerks office of one said Court according to law as 
    
</text>
</TEI>
