<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0007.001"><!-- Insert file name inside quotes. Check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.reu.0011.015 -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Amelia Thompson v. William R. Jouett. Deposition of James D. Doty<!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Edward Queen v. John Ashton. Deposition of Thomas Warfield) --></title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Arneal, Thomas G." xml:id="TGA">Thomas G. Arneal</name><!-- Add your name where indicated. -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.reu.0007.001"><!-- file name - same as xml:id above --></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0692"><!-- caseid number, check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.caseid.0323 --></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of James D. Doty<!--Name of Document; e.g. - Deposition of Thomas Warfield --></title>
<date when="1844-11-25">November 25, 1844</date><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition<!--Type of Document; e.g. - Deposition --></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1844-11">November 1844</date></term><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term></term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term></term><!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term><!-- Was the outcome of the case stated in this document? What was it? e.g. - Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Kentucky. Louisville Chancery Court<!-- Name of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore --></orgName>
<placeName>Louisville (Ky.)<!-- Location of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-07" who="#TGA">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p>Deposition</p>

<p>of James D. Doty, of Taycheedah in the Territory of Wiskonsan, to be
read in evidence in the case of Amelia Thompson &amp;c of Calor, Complainants
and William (R.) Jouett, defendent, in the Louisville Chancery Court, in
the State of Kentucky, taken by Charles Doty under and by virtue of a
Commission issued to him by the said Court, bearing date the 2nd day
of November 1844 amd hereunto annexed.</p>

<p>I, the Said James D. Doty being duly sworn do testify, depose and
say, in reply to the several interrogatories annexed to the said
Commission as follows, to wit:</p>

<p>To the 1st Intertogatory</p>
<p>That I am acquainted with the parties to this Suit</p>

<p>To the 2nd Interrogatory</p>
<p>That I have no knowledge of their purchase by the defendent</p>

<p>To the 3d Interrogatory</p>
<p>That I have known the Said Jouett as an officer in the Army of</p>

<pb xml:id="p002"/> 

<p>the United States for thirteen years (and more) last part: That I have
frequently seen him on Service as such officer, at the United States
Garrisons at Fort Crawford and at Fort Winnebago in the Territory of
Wiskonsan</p>

<p>To the 4th Interrogatory</p>
<p>That since the latter part of the year 1841 or the beginning
of the year 1842 (or thereabouts) the said Jouett has been stationed at
said Fort.Winnebago, in command of that post: That his quarters are 
and at all times been within the pickets of the Garrison: That the
said Fort is on land which is reserved by the United States for Military
purposes, over which the Territorial authorities exercise no civil
jurisdiction otherwise than in the execution of the laws of the United
States: That I have frequently visited the said Jouett at his quarters
in the in the said Garrison, on some of which  occasions I have seen (as I
suppose) the said Complainanrs, who were engaged in domestic service
in the quarters of the said Jouett. That they were regarded in the family
of the said Jouett, and spoken of by him and them, as his slaves: That
I understood he had brought them with him from Kentucky when he came
to this Post.</p>

<p>To the 5th.Interrogatory</p>
<p>That the reply is contained (so far as I know) in my answer</p>

<p>To the 6th Interrogatory</p>
<p>That during the time the deft. held the Complainants
in his service as his slaves in this Territory, he resided and kept them (as
before stated) within the said Garrison of Fort Winnebago, on the
Military Reservation of the United States; and that the said Jouett
has continued to occupy quarters in the said garrison from that time to
the present.</p>

<p>To the 7th.Interrogatory</p>
<p>That the defendant has not to my knowledge been in the said
Territory, during the period I have known him, for any other purpose
than to obey the orders of his superior officers as he had during the
whole of that time been a member of the army: That such officer as</p>

<pb xml:id="p003"/>

<p>aforesaid, acting under the orders of his superior, he had not, in my
opinion, the choice of a place of residence either here or elsewhere;
it being contrary to Military usage, as I understand, for an officeer
to select his station--- of course it cannot be optional with him how
long he shall remain at any post; he comes to a Post, and remains there,
at the wish of his government. If he refuse to obey he may be punished
for his disobedience-- and the committing this offence can give him no civil
rights when it occurs; he may seek to avoid an order to move to or from
a Post by tendering a resignation of his commission; but the President
may refuse to accept his resignation; and if the officer attempts to
exercise his own will he becomes liable to be tried for his disobedience.
The defendant therefore could not have come to this Territory "to reside,"
he came in the Military service, and for the purpose expressed in his
orders: he came for the purpose of the government and not for his own, and
could have legally had no other intention than to comply with and to
execute them. To acquire residence in a country I understand that it is
necessary that the person should have liberty to remain or go to
another--- that he should have the will to choose --- and that he
should actually determine for himself whether his domicil shall be at
the place where he is or continue at the place where he previously dwelt.
These remarks I have deemed necessary that my reply to this and to
the 10th interrogatories may be correctly understood --- which is that
Jouett did not come "to reside permanently in Wiskonsan" </p>

<p>And I will add farther, in reply, that Jouett has, during the time
he held the complainants in his service in this Territory, dwelt upon a
Military Reservation which is under the sole and exclusive jurisdiction
of the United States; and that no man can obtain a "permanent" residence 
on such a reservation as every person there is under a Military juris-
diction and subject to be removed at any moment. The Acts of Congress,
also, prohibit all settlement upon lands so situated, and indeed upon
all public lands except such as are subject to pre-emption. No residence
therefore, either permanent or otherwise can be acquired on such lands.</p>

<pb xml:id="p004"/>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
