<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id=""><!-- Insert file name inside quotes. Check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.reu.0011.015 --> "oscys.reu.0005.001"
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title><!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Paul Jones v. George Jones) --></title>
<principal n="Brinkley, Roshawnna K., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">Roshawnna K. Brinkley</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Brinkley, Roshawnna K.," xml:id="RKB">FULL NAME</name><!-- Add your name where indicated. -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project"><!-- file name - same as xml:id above --></idno>
<idno type="case"><!-- caseid number, check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.caseid.0323 --></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main"><!--Name of Document; e.g. - Deposition of Thomas Warfield --></title>
<date when="yyyy-mm-dd">MONTH DAY, YEAR</date><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term><!--Type of Document; e.g. - Deposition --></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="yyyy-mm">MONTH YEAR</date></term><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term></term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term></term><!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term><!-- Was the outcome of the case stated in this document? What was it? e.g. - Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName><!-- Name of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore --></orgName>
<placeName><!-- Location of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="yyyy-mm-dd" who="#ini">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p>Interrogations to the propounded to the Elroy Le Compte Francis Baptist Valle, Bartholomew <unclear/> Durreher and Joseph Bogy of the Lou of St. Genevieve and State of Missouri with helps to the produced sworn and examined in a certain cause at common law now pleading and undetermined in the United States district court for the County of Grant and territory of Wisconsin wherein Paul Jones a colored man is plantiff and  George W. Jones is defendant on the part and in behalf of the laid defendant.</p>

<p>Interrogatory 1st Do you know the parties plaintiff and defendant in the title of these interrogations named or either of them and which of them and how long have you known them respectively?</p>

<p>2 Are you or either of you acquaintances with a colored man called Paul who was sold as a slave by Elroy LeCompte John H. LeCompte and S. LeCompte to the defendant George W. Jones. If so state all you know about the raid state and at what time it took place?</p>

<p> 3 Do you or either of you know who was the mother of the said colored man Paul? Where did he reside by what name called whether she was not heed as a slave in the state of Illinois if so by what tennure or rights?</p>

<p> 4 Do you or either of you know where and when the before named Paul was born if so please state?</p>

<p> 5 Do you or either of you of you know whether the service Paul was held to service for life as a slave in Illinois under the laws and usages in force in the North Western territory now state of Illinois in favor of the ancient french and canadian inhabitants of the villages of Kaskaskia and Prarie Du Rocher Cahokia and other villages in the former NorthWestern territory now state of Illinois aforesaid if so please state all you know in relation to it as fully as if particularly interrogated there to?</p>

<p> 6 Do you or either of you know whether the mothers of the said colored man Paul, was or was not on or before the 13th of July A.D. 1787 held and owned as a slave bound to the service to one of the Canadian or French inhabitants mentioned in the fifth interrogatory, if so please state what you know in relation to it?</p>

<p>7 Do you or either of you know whether the said Paul was a slave in the state of illinois according to any law or uasge then in force if is, state by whome held and by what right and tennure</p>

<p> 8 Are you or either of you interested directly or indirectly in the event and termination of this suit?</p>

<p> 9 Do you know anything further that may tend to the benefit and advantage of the defendant in this cause or the elucidation of this subject if so please state fully and particularly</p>

<p> George W. Jones by Hempstead &amp; Dunn his attorney 
Examined &amp; approved 6th, August 1840 
Chas Dunn, Judge 1st, Jud: Dis: W.T.
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
