<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0092.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Mason and Alexander Moore v. Matilda Derrick. Transcript</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp><name> n="Martin, Heidi K." xml:id="hkm">Heidi K. Martin</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0091.015</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0092</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Transcript</title>
<date when="1825-02-07">February 7, 1825</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 267</collection>
<idno>Box 144, Folder 1332</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Transcript</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1825-02">February 1825</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Adams, Samuel W</term>
<term>Brent, William</term>
<term>Cheshire, Archibald</term>
<term>Clark, Joseph S</term>
<term>Craik, James</term>
<term>Craik, Maria D</term>
<term>Craik, Marianne</term>
<term>Cranch, William</term>
<term><unclear>Crofs, Elie</unclear>,</term>
<term>Davis, Richard</term>
<term>Dawson, Alfred R</term>
<term>Forrest, John B</term>
<term>Frost, John T</term>
<term>Gassaway, Hanson</term>
<term>Harrison, Ann Louisa</term>
<term>Harrison, Gustavus</term>
<term>Hyatt, Seth</term>
<term>Mason, Louisa</term>
<term>Moore, Ann</term>
<term>Morsell, James S</term>
<term>Pyfer, Henry</term>
<term>Ridgely, William G</term>
<term>Reintzel, Daniel</term>
<term>Rhodes, William</term>
<term>Ringgold, Tench</term>
<term>Ritchie, John T</term>
<term>Sandiford, Thomas</term>
<term>Semmes, Raphael</term>
<term>Smith, Henry</term>
<term>Talbott, William</term>
<term>Thompson, William</term>
<term>Thruston, Buckner </term>
<term>Washington, Baily</term>
<term>Washington, William</term>
<term>Wilson, James</term>
<term>Wittberger, Charles H</term>
<term><unclear></unclear>, Henry</term>
  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>United States of America</term>
<term>Virginia</term>
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>District of Columbia</term>
<term>County of Alexandria</term>
<term>County of Fairfax</term>
<term>County of Washington</term>
<term>City of Washington</term>
<term>George Town</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Derrick, Louisa</persName> 
<persName>Derrick, Lucy</persName>
<persName>Derrick, Matilda</persName>
<persName>Derrick, Matilda</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Mason, George</persName> 
<persName>Moore, Alexander</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Jones, Walter</persName>
<persName>Key, Francis Scott</persName>
<persName>Taney, Augustus</persName>
<persName>Turner, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Jones, Walter</persName>
<persName>Lear, Benjamin L</persName>
<persName>Sampson</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2022-06" who="#hkm">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_3676.jpg"/>

<p>District of Columbia <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>As a Circuit Court of the District of
Columbia begun and held in and for the County of Washington at the
City of Washington on the Second Monday of April being the fourteenth
day of the same Month in the year of our Lord one thousand eight
hundred and twenty three and of American Independence the 
forty seventh</p>
<p>Present
The Honble William Cranch Esquire Chief Judge
Buckner Thurston and
James S Morsell Esquires Assistant Judges
Tench Ringgold Esquire Marshal William Brent Clk</p>
<p>In the Record and proceedings of the same
court amongst <sic>thers</sic> is the following towit</p>
<p>Negro Matilda Derrick for
herself and Children
ags.
George Mason and
Alexander Moore</p>
<p>petn for
freedom</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit
on the fifth day of October in the ear one
thousand eight hundred and twenty two
Matilda Derrick for herself and children
by Thomas Turner Esquire her attorney
filed in Court here her petition for
freedom against George Mason and Alexander Moore in the
words following towit; "To the Honourable the Judges of the Circuit
"towit for the County of Washington, humbly complaining howeth
unto your Honors your petitioners Negress Matilda calling herself
Matilda Derrick for herself and her children Lucy, Matilda, and
Louisa infants under 21 years old that they are entitled to their
freedom and to all the privileges secured by the benefits of the laws
of this country to the class of people to which your petitioners conceive
themselves belonging. That for the last six or seven years she Matilda
has resided and hired herself as a free woman within the District of
Columbia for the last two years within Washington County. That no one has
ever claimed the services or anything therefor within the said six or seven
years until within a few days passed. That she has been promised
from time to time her free papers by a certain Alexander Moore of 
Alexandria County, District aforesaid who married into the family
of a certain Doctor Craik late of Virginia to whom your petitioners
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_3683.jpg"/>
formerly belonged. That she has always understood herself (if belonging
to any one) to be the property of Mrs. Louisa Mason the late deceased
wife of a certain George Mason of Washington County District aforesaid;
who now as she understands makes claim to her that she <sic>founds</sic> particularly
their claim to freedom by reason of her the said Matilda's removal from Charles
County in the state of Maryland to Fairfax County in the State of Virginia
in or about the year 1792 or within the year or two of that period, sooner
or later by the said Doctor Craik her former Master and being then
continued and held as a slave for more than one year contrary to the
acts of assembly and the laws of the said State of Virginia and the
provisions thereof. To the end therefore that a decision in the premises 
may be had from your Honourable Court your petitioner prays that
a subpoena or subpoenas may issue from your Honourable Court directed
to the said George Mason and Alexander Moore commanding them
to be and appear before your Honourable Court &amp;c And then <unclear>as</unclear> thereby
made Defendants to this petition &amp;c. </p>
<p>And as in duty bound your petitioner will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Tho. Turner for Pet.</p>
<p>District of Columbia County of Washington Sct.</p>
<p>On this 5th October
1822 personally appears before the subscriber one of the Justices of
the peace in and for the County and District aforesaid Matilda
Negress, the petitioner within named and makes oath on the
holy Evangely of Almighty God that the matters therin contained as
stated of her own knowledge are true and as stated of the knowledge
of others are true to the best of her knowledge and belief</p>
<p>Sworn before Daniel Reintzel</p>
<p>A summons was issued accordingly against the said George Mason
and Alexander Moore to answer the petition aforesaid and directed
to the Marshal of the District of Columbia in the words and of the
<unclear></unclear> following towit, "District of Columbia towit the United States
of America. The Marshall of the District of Columbia Greeting: <del>We</del>
"You are hereby commanded to summon George Mason and Alexander
Moore if they shall be found in the county of Washington that all
excuses set aside they be and appear before the Clerk of the Circuit Court
of the District of Columbia at Rules to be held for the County of Washington
in the City of Washington on the first Monday of November next to
answer the petition for freedom of Negro Matilda Derrick for herself
and children filed in the Circuit Court here against them. Hereof fail not 
<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_3687.jpg"/>
at your peril and have you there this precept witness who
Cranch Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court freed the 5th day of 
October 1822 (Turner)</p>
<p>Wm Brent clk</p>
<p>At which said first Monday of November in the year of our
Lord one thousand eight hundred and twenty two being the day of
the return of the subpoena aforesaid come before the clerk here
at Rules the Petitioner aforesaid by their said Attorney and the
Marshal to whom the said subpoena was directed makes return
thereof thus endorsed towit "Summoned Tench Ringgold Marshall" and
the said George Mason and Alexander Moore by B. Lincoln Lear Esquire
their Attorney come and defend the complaint aforesaid when and
where the said Court and consent of the parties the said cause is placed
on the trial docket of the said Circuit Court for the County aforesaid at 
October term eighteen hundred twenty two and the parties aforesaid by
their said attorneys appear before said Court; and the said George
and Alexander by their said Attorney as before defends the compliment
aforesaid when and where the said Court shall take the same into
consideration and for plea they say that the said petitioners are not
entitled to their freedom as is alleged and of this they put themselves
upon their Country and the said petitioners in like manner and so forth.</p>
<p>Whereupon for trying the issue aforesaid between the parties aforesaid
above joined to be tried by their country it is ordered by the Court here
that a Jury thereon appear before the Court here immediately by whom &amp;c
and who neither &amp;c to recognize &amp;c because as well &amp;c. Thereupon
twelve persons being called come towit, John T. Frost, Henry Pyfer, William
Talbott, Seth Hyatt, William Thompson, <unclear>Elie Crofs</unclear>, William Rhodes, Henry
Smith, Gustavus Harrison, Charles H Wittberger, Thomas Sandiford, &amp; John T
Ritchie who being duly elected empanelled and sworn to say the truth
in the premises upon their oaths do say that the said petitioners are
not entitled to their freedom as the said Defendants above in pleading
hath alleged; Thereupon the said petitioners by their Attorney aforesaid
pray that the verdict aforesaid may be set aside because it is
erroneous and given against the directions of the Court to the said
Jury and that the issue aforesaid may be tried anew by other Jurors
Whereupon all and singular the premises being seen and by the
Court here more fully understood and <unclear>matine</unclear> deliberation being
<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_3690.jpg"/>
thereupon had for that it appease to the Court here that the verdict
aforesaid be set aside and held entitled as void and of no force or
effect and that the issue aforesaid be tried anew by other Jurors 
to be afresh empanelled. Therefore let a Jury thereon appear before 
the Court here on the second Monday of April next by whom &amp;c and who neither &amp;c because as well &amp; the
same day is given to the said parties then and there &amp;c</p>
<p>And at said second Monday of April in the year of 
our Lord one thousand eight hundred and twenty three come
again into Court here as well the said Petitioners by their Attorney
aforesaid as the said Defendants by their Attorney aforesaid.</p>
<p>Whereupon for trying the issue aforesaid between the parties aforesaid
it is ordered by the Court here that twelve persons be drawn by
ballot from the list of Petit Jurors returned by the Marshal of the 
District aforesaid to the Court here. Whereupon twelve persons being
so drawn and called come towit, Raphael Semmes, Alfred R Dawson,
Joseph S Clark, Baily Washington, Samuel W. Adams, James Wilson, Richard
Davis, Hanson Gassaway, William G Ridgely, Archibald Cheshire, Henry <unclear></unclear>
and John B Forrest who being empanelled and sworn to say the truth
on the premises upon their oath do say that the said petitioners
are entitled to their freedom as they in their petition above
have alleged. Therefore it is considered by the Court here that 
the said Matilda Derrick and her children Lucy, Matilda, and 
Louisa under the age of twenty one. The petitioners aforesaid recover 
their freedom of and against the said George Mason and Alexander
Moore and that they be free and discharged of and from the
service of the said George and Alexander and that the said
Petitioners go thereof freed and discharged without day &amp;c it is
also considered by the Court here that the said petitioners recover
against the said George and Alexander the sum of
&#160;&#160;;by the Court here unto the said petitioners
adjudged on their assent for their costs and charges by them about the
prosecution of their petition aforesaid laid out and expended &amp;c.</p>
<p>Negro Matilda and Children ag Moore and Mason Pet for free</p>
<p>Memorandum Before the Jurors aforesaid withdrew from the 
Bar of the Court here the said George Mason and Alexander Moore
by their Attorney filed in Court here the following Bill of Exceptions
towit. In this case the petitioners to support the issue on their 
part joined offered evidence to prove that some time in the year 
<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_3693.jpg"/>
1792 and before the month of December in that year, James
Craik removed from the state of Maryland into the County of 
Fairfax in the <del>County of Fairf</del> commonwealth of Virginia with
intent to settle in said County and become a Citizen of said
commonwealth and did then so settle and become such citizen and
continue to reside as such in said county till his death which
happened some time in the year 1814. that said Craik at the
time of his said removal brought the petitioner Matilda with 
him from Maryland aforesaid into the County aforesaid she being
then a Negro slave belonging to said Craik and continually held the
said petitioner and her children in said County as slaves till his death 
and at his death devised them as slaves to his widow who some
time in the year 1814 removed from said County of Fairfax into the
Town and County of Alexandria in this District bringing with her
the said petitioners and holding them as slaves in said Town
of Alexandria at her death demised the said petitioner to Ann the
late wife of the Defendant Moore and to Louisa the late wife of the
Defendant Mason by her last will hereto annexed that the said Ann
and Louisa were at the time of such demise for a long time before and
even after till their respective deaths, inhabitants of the District of
Columbia; the said Ann of Alexandria aforesaid and the said Louisa
of George Town in the County of Washington that the said Defendants
Mason and Moore were at the time of their respective inter<del><unclear>rogatorie</unclear></del> <add>marriage</add> with
said Ann and Louisa for a long time before and ever since inhabitants and
Citizens of said District the said Moore of Alexandria aforesaid the said
Mason of George Town aforesaid. That the said petitioners were kept
in Alexandria aforesaid for the space of Eighteen months after
the death of the said widow Craik and were then brought from 
Alexandria aforesaid to George Town aforesaid and there held by the
said Louisa as a slave till her intermarriage with the Defendant 
Mason in the month of October 1821 and ever since have been
held in George Town aforesaid by the said Mason as the joint property 
of himself and said Moore that the petitioners Matilda the younger
Lucy and Louisa are the children of said Matilda born after her
removal from Maryland as aforesaid and whilst she was held by 
said James Craik as a slave as aforesaid and within the last
<pb xml:id="p006" facs="IMG_3697.jpg"/>
twenty years. And it is admitted that at the time of the said removal
of the said Craik from Maryland into Fairfax as aforesaid in
Commission as Justices of the <del><unclear>Peace</unclear></del> said County of Fairfax; all of
whom have since departed this life. The last survivor of them having
died about five years ago; and that the said petitioners had not
been imported from Africa or any of the West India Islands and
was the slave and property of said James at the time of such
his removal and always before. The above admitted as the evidence
in the <unclear>ease</unclear></p> 
<p>(signed) B.L. Lear &amp; Walter Jones for Defts And Aug. Taney for pet.</p>
<p>And upon the facts so given in evidence and admitted as aforesaid
the petitioners prayed the opinion of the Court and an instruction 
to the Jury. That if the Defendant wishes to avail himself of the
benefit of the provisos in the &#160; sect of the act of &#160;
it is incumbent on him to produce competent testimony to prove that
the said &#160; Craik had complied with the terms and conditions
of the said proviso and that in the absence of all testimony no
presumption can arise from lapse of time or other facts in the
case agreed to supply the defect of sworn testimony which opinion
and instruction was accordingly given by the Court to the Jury: to which
opinion and instruction the Defendants by their counsel except and
thereupon the Defendants insisted and contended before the Jury
first that the facts given in evidence as aforesaid do not impose
upon the Defendants the necessity of proving by substantive evidence
that the said James Craik had taken the Oath prescribed by the
Act of General Assembly of Virginia passed in the year 1787
ch.77 within the time prescribed by the Act and that the Jury
upon the said statement of facts ought not to find the petitioners
for the want of such substantive proofs on the part of the Defendants.</p>
<p>2. That the Jury, under the circumstances so given in evidence
may presume that the said James Craik had taken the said
Oath in the prescribed time. But the Court, upon the
motion of the petitioners overruled all the points so insisted upon
and contended for by the Defendants and stopped the Defendants
Counsel from proceeding to maintain the points or any of the
points so insisted upon and contended for before the Jury by
the Defendants. To which opinion and instruction the
<pb xml:id="p007" facs="IMG_3699.jpg"/>
Defendants Counsel excepts and pray the Court to sign and seal
this their Bill of exceptions which is accordingly done this thirteenth 
day of June A.D. 1823</p>
<p>B Thruston</p> 
<p>seal</p>
<p>J L S Morsell</p>
<p>seal</p>
<p>Copy of the Will referred in the statement)</p>
<p>I Marianne Craik do acknowledge this to be my last will
and Testament. I give and bequeath to my Grand Daughters Ann
Moore and Ann Louisa Harrison my woman Myrtilla and her
children to be divided between them. If they are sold they must be
sold for a Term of years. They must not be sold for life out of the
family. In witness whereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal this
tenth day of April 1815</p>
<p>Witness William Washington, Maria D. Craik, Marianne Craik</p>
<p>seal</p>
<p>I give my desk to Ann Moore and my medical books to
Doctor Washington.</p>
<p>Be it remembered that on this 20th day of April 1815
before me Alexander Moore Register of Wills for the County of
Alexandria in the District of Columbia came William Washington
and Maria D. Craik and proved this last will and testament of
Marianne Craik Dece. is due form of law</p>
<p>A. Moore</p>
<p>Register of Will</p>
<p>District of Columbia Sct</p>
<p>I Alexander Moore Register of Wills for
the County of Alexandria in the District of Columbia do hereby
certify that the above is a true copy of Mrs. Marianne Craik's will.
Record in my Office. In testimony whereof I have hereunto 
set my hand and affixed my seal of Office this
4th Nov. 1822</p>
<p>A. Moore, Reg.</p>
<p><unclear>Test</unclear> William Brent clk
Ct.Ct. for Coty of Washn. D.C. </p>
<pb xml:id="p008" facs="IMG_3703.jpg"/>
<p>District of Columbia County of Washington Sct.</p>
<p>Whereas afterwards towit on the third day
of February 1823 the said George Mason and Alexander Moore by
their said Attorney produced the United States Writ for
Correcting of Errors upon the Judgement aforesaid directed to the 
judges aforesaid. In pursuance whereof and according to the
law in such cases made and provided a Transcript of
the Record of Proceedings of the Judgment aforesaid and all
things thereinto relating is truly and faithfully copied and
with the Writ of Error annexed and a Copy of the Appeal 
Bond is hereby transmitted to the said Supreme Court.
In Testimony whereof I have hereto subscribed
my name and affixed the sal of the Circuit Court for the County
aforesaid this Eighteenth day of June
in the year of our Lord 1824.</p>
<p>William Brent clk
of the 4th Coty of Washn. D.C.</p>
<pb xml:id="p009" facs="IMG_3704.jpg"/>
<p> 65 Washington</p>
<p>George Mason &amp;
Alexander Moore
Plaintiffs in Error
vs
Transcript
Matilda Derrick &amp;
her children</p>
<p>Filed Feb: 7 1825</p>
<p>No. 65
Reversed &amp;c
March 10 1827</p>
<p>1332</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
