<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.caseid.0681">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Bess v. Ruth Howard. Judgment Record.</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Krohn, Esme M." xml:id="emk">Esme M. Krohn</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.mdcase.0027.001"></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0681"></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1722-04">April 1722</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1722-04">April 1722</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term  xml:id="per.007049">Bess</term>
<term xml:id="per.007039">Beale, Jon </term>
<term xml:id="per.007051">Bordley, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.007040">Benson, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.007042">Chapman, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.007043">Dorsey, Caleb</term>
<term xml:id="per.007044">Forogood, Josias</term> 
<term xml:id="per.007050">Howard, Ruth</term>
<term xml:id="per.007045">Jones, Phillip</term>
<term xml:id="per.007046">Lambert, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.007047">Smith, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.007048"> Warman, Stephen</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Howard County</term>
<term>Ann Anrundell County</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgement for neither, but freedom not restored</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bess</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Ruth Howard</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName> Thomas Bordley</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName>Maryland Provincial Court, Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-07" who="emk">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8006.jpg"/>

<p>Ruth Howard vs. Negroe Bess</p>

<p>The Justices of his Lordship's County Court of <unclear></unclear>
Transmit to the Justices of the Provincial Court 
here the following Record on an Appeal made by the 
said Ruth Howard from Howard County Court the <unclear></unclear> whereof
follows in these words viz.–</p>

<p>In the Records and Proceedings of Ann Arundell County Court amongst
other things is Contained as follows viz.–</p>

<p>Ann Arundell County: At a County Court of the Most Honorable Charles 
Absolute Lord and <unclear>proxy</unclear> of the Provinces of Maryland and Avalon Lord
Baron of Baltimore and hold at the City of Annapolis for the County of 
Ann Arundele the Second Tuesday of June being the thirteenth day of
the June Month in the Sixth year of his Lordships Dominion
Anno Dom. 1721 </p>

<p>Present
The Worshipfull:
Mr. Josias Forogood
Mr. Edwd. Benson
Mr. Caleb Dorsey
Mr. Wm. Chapman
Lord Phillip Jones
Mr. Samuel Smith
Court Justices
J. Beale Clk.
Stephen Warman Sherr.</p>

<p>Negroe Bess....
v. 
Ruth Howard...</p>

<p>On the said Bess's Complaint against the said Ruth Howard 
to the Court here for her freedom the said Ruth Howard
being present in Court. And Whereupon all and Singular
the allegations <unclear>assailed</unclear> of the Negroe Bess as the said Ruth Howard
being fully heard in relation to the premises and Mature Deliberation.–
Moreupon had for that it Seems to the Court here that it was the Designe
of Mrs. Anne Lambert Deceased the former Mistress of the said Negroe Bess
that She Should be free at the Age of Twenty five years.– </p>

<p>It is therefore Considered by the Justices here that the said Negroe 
Bess be free at the Age of twenty five years.–</p>

<p>Whereupon the said Mrs. Ruth Howard the Mistress of the said Negroe 
Bess prays an Appeal from the Judgment of the Court to the next
Provincal Court to be held for this Province which is granted and the 
Record ordered to be Transmitted Accordingly–</p>

<p>In Testimony whereof the Seal of Ann Arundell 
County is hereunto affixed 
John Beale Clk. of Ann Arundell County</p>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8007.jpg"/>

<p> And now here at this day to wit the 10 day of October Anno Domini 1721 Comes the said
Ruth Howard by Thomas Bordley her attorney in to his Lordships Provinciall Court
of Maryland before the Justices thereof and Saith that in the Record and process
aforesaid <unclear></unclear> in the Pondering the Judgement aforesaid this Manifestly End to wit in this
that the Court having taken upon them to make a Negroe which is by Act of Assembly
<unclear>of</unclear> this province declared a Slave for Life to become free at Twenty five years–
<unclear></unclear> Ago Contrary to the Express words of the same Act and to the great
Annoyance of his Majestys Christian Subjects within this province by allowing these
Africans the Enjoyment of Liberty &amp; of Privledges Equal to those of English 
men whereas the Royall Charter of this province granted by his Majesty–
progenitors to those of the Lord <unclear>Proxy</unclear> appears to have been for the planting
an Ample Colony of the English Nation in these parts.–</p>

<p> In this that the Court Declared the reason of Setting her free was because it seemed 
to them it was the Design of her former Mistress Anne Lambert that She Should
be free <unclear>etc.</unclear>but that it appears not that the said Anne Lambert had Executed these
designes whilst it was in her Power to have rendered them Effectuale Nor that 
Ever she designed to <add>set</add> her free before she Disposed of her to the said Ruth Nor that
the said Negroe was set free or designed to be set free by her Mistress for that
time being but by her former Mistress whose Power was Determined.–
</p>

<p> In this that the said Court ought to have given Judgment against the said Bess
that She Should Continue a Slave and not that She Should be free at twenty five
years of Age for all which and many Other Errors in the Record and Process
aforesaid the said Ruth Howard prays that the Judgment be reverst and that She to
all that She Hereby Lost may be restored that the said Bess to the Errors– 
aforesaid may rejoin and that the Court will proceed to Examine the same according
to Law–</p>

<p>Whereupon the said Negro Bess in her proper person
appears and Says that in the Record and proceedings and also in the 
rendering Judgement therein it is in nothing Erred and prays that the same
Judgment may in all things be affirmed and there upon as well the said
Negroe Bess as the said Ruth Howard by her attorney aforesaid pray the Court of
the Lord <unclear>Proxy</unclear> here will proceed as well to the Equaniming of the Record
and proceedings aforesaid as of the Matters above for Errors assigned.
</p>

<p>Whereupon for that the Court here are not advised of their Judgment of
and upon the premises day is given to the said parties to hear thereof
their Judgment until next Court for that the said Court as yet are not
At which said next Court to wit 10 day of Anno Dom 1782 Come again in as well
the said Ruth Howard by her attorney and the said Negro Bess in hers.
</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_8008.jpg"/>

<p> And whereupon all and Singular the premises being by the Court now
soon heard fully understood and Mature Deliberation whereupon had 
It is Considered by the Justices here the 10 day of April Anno
Dom 1722 aforesaid that the Judgment aforesaid for the Error aforesaid be <unclear></unclear>
Annulled and altogether hold for None and that the said Ruth Howard
too all things that thereby She hath lost be Restored 
And it is further Considered that the Said Negroe Bess Continue a Slave
to the said Ruth Howard during her life. </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
