<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0007.001"><!-- Insert file name inside quotes. Check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.reu.0011.015 -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Amelia Thompson v. William R. Jouett. Deposition of James D. Doty<!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Edward Queen v. John Ashton. Deposition of Thomas Warfield) --></title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Arneal, Thomas G." xml:id="TGA">Thomas G. Arneal</name><!-- Add your name where indicated. -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.reu.0007.001"><!-- file name - same as xml:id above --></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0692"><!-- caseid number, check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.caseid.0323 --></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of James D. Doty<!--Name of Document; e.g. - Deposition of Thomas Warfield --></title>
<date when="1844-11-25">November 25, 1844</date><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition<!--Type of Document; e.g. - Deposition --></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1844-11">November 1844</date></term><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Doty, Charles</term>
<term>Dodge, Henry</term>
<term>Smith</term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Wiskonsan</term>
<term>Michigan</term>
<term>Kentucky</term>
<term>Fort Winnebago</term><!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term><!-- Was the outcome of the case stated in this document? What was it? e.g. - Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Amelia Thompson &amp;c of Color<!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>William (R.) Jouett<!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Kentucky. Louisville Chancery Court<!-- Name of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore --></orgName>
<placeName>Louisville (Ky.)<!-- Location of the Court listed on spreadsheet - e.g. Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-11" who="#TGA">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p>Deposition</p>

<p>of James D. Doty, of Taycheedah in the Territory of Wiskonsan, to be
read in evidence in the case of Amelia Thompson &amp;c of Color, Complainants
and William (R.) Jouett, defendent, in the Louisville Chancery Court, in
the State of Kentucky, taken by Charles Doty under and by virtue of a
Commission issued to him by the said Court, bearing date the 2nd day
of November 1844 amd hereunto annexed.</p>

<p>I, the Said James D. Doty being duly sworn do testify, depose and
say, in reply to the several interrogatories annexed to the said
Commission as follows, to wit:</p>

<p>To the 1st Intertogatory</p>
<p>That I am acquainted with the parties to this Suit</p>

<p>To the 2nd. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That I have no knowledge of their purchase by the defendent</p>

<p>To the 3d. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That I have known the Said Jouett as an officer in the Army of</p>

<pb xml:id="p002"/> 

<p>the United States for thirteen years (and more) last part: That I have
frequently seen him on Service as such officer, at the United States
Garrisons at Fort Crawford and at Fort Winnebago in the Territory of
Wiskonsan</p>

<p>To the 4th. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That since the latter part of the year 1841 or the beginning
of the year 1842 (or thereabouts) the said Jouett has been stationed at
said Fort.Winnebago, in command of that post: That his quarters are 
and at all times been within the pickets of the Garrison: That the
said Fort is on land which is reserved by the United States for Military
purposes, over which the Territorial authorities exercise no civil
jurisdiction otherwise than in the execution of the laws of the United
States: That I have frequently visited the said Jouett at his quarters
in the in the said Garrison, on some of which  occasions I have seen (as I
suppose) the said Complainanrs, who were engaged in domestic service
in the quarters of the said Jouett. That they were regarded in the family
of the said Jouett, and spoken of by him and them, as his slaves: That
I understood he had brought them with him from Kentucky when he came
to this Post.</p>

<p>To the 5th. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That the reply is contained (so far as I know) in my answer</p>

<p>To the 6th Interrogatory</p>
<p>That during the time the deft. held the Complainants
in his service as his slaves in this Territory, he resided and kept them (as
before stated) within the said Garrison of Fort Winnebago, on the
Military Reservation of the United States; and that the said Jouett
has continued to occupy quarters in the said garrison from that time to
the present.</p>

<p>To the 7th. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That the defendant has not to my knowledge been in the said
Territory, during the period I have known him, for any other purpose
than to obey the orders of his superior officers as he had during the
whole of that time been a member of the army: That such officer as</p>

<pb xml:id="p003"/>

<p>aforesaid, acting under the orders of his superior, he had not, in my
opinion, the choice of a place of residence either here or elsewhere;
it being contrary to Military usage, as I understand, for an officeer
to select his station--- of course it cannot be optional with him how
long he shall remain at any post; he comes to a Post, and remains there,
at the wish of his government. If he refuse to obey he may be punished
for his disobedience-- and the committing this offence can give him no civil
rights when it occurs; he may seek to avoid an order to move to or from
a Post by tendering a resignation of his commission; but the President
may refuse to accept his resignation; and if the officer attempts to
exercise his own will he becomes liable to be tried for his disobedience.
The defendant therefore could not have come to this Territory "to reside,"
he came in the Military service, and for the purpose expressed in his
orders: he came for the purpose of the government and not for his own, and
could have legally had no other intention than to comply with and to
execute them. To acquire residence in a country I understand that it is
necessary that the person should have liberty to remain or go to
another--- that he should have the will to choose --- and that he
should actually determine for himself whether his domicil shall be at
the place where he is or continue at the place where he previously dwelt.
These remarks I have deemed necessary that my reply to this and to
the 10th interrogatories may be correctly understood --- which is that
Jouett did not come "to reside permanently in Wiskonsan" </p>

<p>And I will add farther, in reply, that Jouett has, during the time
he held the complainants in his service in this Territory, dwelt upon a
Military Reservation which is under the sole and exclusive jurisdiction
of the United States; and that no man can obtain a "permanent" residence 
on such a reservation as every person there is under a Military juris-
diction and subject to be removed at any moment. The Acts of Congress,
also, prohibit all settlement upon lands so situated, and indeed upon
all public lands except such as are subject to pre-emption. No residence
therefore, either permanent or otherwise can be acquired on such lands.</p>

<pb xml:id="p004"/>

<p>To the 8th. Interrogatory I answer that I do not know.</p>
<p>To the 9th. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That I believe the defendants home and citizenship are in
Kentucky, and that they were there when he entered the Army; and that
his rank is now that of a Captain.</p>

<p>To the 10th. Interrogatory</p>
<p>That the deft. Jouett was not a citizen of Wiskonsan when he
entered the army, and that he is not now a citizen of this Territory.
Residence, with the intention to become a citizen, having the liberty
to form such intention, I consider requisite to obtain citizenship.
An officer of the army can have no such residence and intention: and
I regard him as being in the same condition as an officer of the navy
on the high seas, or in the ports of the United States, or those of
foreign countries. His residence in this or any other country can only be
temporary whilst he is in the service. To-day he may be ordered to a
Post within this Territory, and before reaching it, or before he has
been here six months, he may be ordered to another beyond its limits.</p>
<p>The law in this Territory is well settled, that no officer or
Soldier has the right to vote at elections, for the reason that he is
not regarded as a citizen or inhabitant, or required to perform any
civil duty. This I consider the only test of citizenship in this
territory. This opinion was confirmed by the Report of the Committee
on Elections in the House of Representatives of the Congress of the
United States in the year 1826, in the case of Wing, Bidal and Richard,
which was accepted by the House. The following is a true extract from
that Report as published by the Printer for that House, to wit:</p>
<p>"The second class [of voters] to which objections are made, consists
"of soldiers of the army, discharged from service within one year next
"preceeding the election. the committee must consider it entirely unnecessary
"to enter into an argument to prove that officers and soldiers of the
"army, by being long quarterred in the Territory, do not by that means
"acquire the right to vote at an election, whilst they remain in the
service; nor do they consider it any more necessary to attmept to prove
"that, after being discharged, they must acquire the rights of the elctors.</p>

<pb xml:id="p005"/>

<p>"in the same way that other persons would who had not been in the
"service."</p>
<p>The act of Congress entitled "An act establishing the Territorial
Government of Wiskonsan," approved April 25, 1836, provides in the 5th
Section as follows, to wit:"</p>
<p>"That every free, white male citizen of the United States, above the
"age of 21 years, who shall have been an inhabitant of said Territory at
"the time of its organization, shall be eligible to any office within the said Territory;
"but the qualifications of voters shall be determined by the legislive Asssembly&amp;c."</p>
<p>At "the first election" held for members of the Assembly under the
above act, officers and soldiers who were stationed at said Fort
Winnebago "at the time of the organization" of the Territory, voted.
Their right was contested and their votes rejected by the House of
Representatives of said Territory as will appear by the Journal of said
House, of the First Legislative Assembly of Wiskonsan. The said election
was held at the Sutlers Store on the said Military Reservation, under
the authority of a proclamation issued by Governor Dodge. The legality
of said election was also contested for this reason, and the objection
sustained. </p>

<p>On the 4th. of July 1839. an act was passed by the Legislature of
said Territory, entitled "An act to provide for and regulate general
elections; the 12th. section of which provides as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>"No person shall be entitled to vote at any election in this
"Territory who has not attained the age of 21 years, who is not a free,
"white, male citizen, or a foreigner duly naturalized according to the
"acts of Congress on that subject, and who has not resided in this
"Territory with the bona fide intention of becoming a citizen, for art least
"six months &amp;c."</p>

<pb xml:id="p006"/>

<p>The opinion that officers and soldiers of the army are not
regarded as citizens of the Territory, but merely as transient persons,
having a temporary residence only, is sustained by the act of the Legis-
lature of said Territory, entitled, "An Act to provide for the taking the
"census of the inhabitants of the Territory of Wiskonsan, and to authorise
":the Governor to apportion the members of the Council and House of
"Representatives," approved February 18. 1842. The 1sr sec. of this act
provides --- "That the sheriffs of the several Counties of the Territory
"are hereby authorised and required to cause the number of inhabitants
"of their respective Counties and districts to be taken, omitting in
"their enumeration Indians not Citizens and pffocers and soldiers of
"the United States army." And the 10th. sec. provides, that "In making
"said apportionment the Governor shall proceed in the manner following,
to wit:</p>
<p>1st. The whole number of representative population of the Territory,
"excluding soldiers and officerts of the United States Army, and Indians
"not citizens, shall be divided by the number 52, the whole number of
"units of representation, the quotient shall be the ratio, or the number
"of population entitled to a unit of representation." At the time of the
passage of said act I was Governor of the Said Territory and
approved it; and did also make the apportionment in the manner required
thereby. The officers and soldiers therefore stationed within the
Territory--- although several of them had been here several years were
not considered citizens or as any part of the population of the Territory.</p>

<p>To the 11th. Interrogatory I answer</p>
<p>That there is no other law in the force in this Territory prohi-
biting slavery than the provision in the 6th. Article of the Ordinance
of 1787, which is entitled "An Ordinance for the government of the
"Territory of the U. S. northwest of the River Ohio." The Legislature
of this Territory (W) has passed no law on the subject of slavery, nor
made any provision to carry this article into effect.</p>

<pb xml:id="p007"/>

<p>That my opinion being asked in this Interrogatory upon the law of
this Country as applicable to the facts of this case, I reply that
having seen the Compts. bill &amp; defts. answer (or copies of them) and
from the facts known to me and hereinbefore stated, I am of the opinion
that the complainants did not become ffree (if they were slaves in
Kentucky) in consequence of their being held to service by him at Fort
Winnebago. The defendant, being an officer in the U. S. army, ordered
to a post within the Territory for the sole purpose of performing a
military duty, and liable to be removed at any moment to any other
station, can only be regarded as a transient person, incable of
acquiring a domicil here, and is as much entitled to the possession
of his slaves whilst tarrying here as he is to the possession of any
other property. I consider that he is entitled to hold while he is in
the performance of his duties any and every species of property which
he has lawfully acquired and held in any of the United States, and that
he is protected therein by the constitution and laws of the United States.</p>
<p>The defendant is required to be here by the United States, and it
cannot be supposed that the U. S. would permit him to hold a slave in
Florida, or in any other place under their executive jurisdiction, and
not allow him the same privilege at the Military Stations in this
Territory; or that it would compel him to give his slaves freedom by
ordering him from a southern to a northern Post. Places under the ex-
clusive jurisdiction of the U. S. are legislate dfor specially by
Congress. It is perhap needless to remark that ist has passed no law
prohibiting slavery within the garrison of the U. S., or by officers of the army.</p>
<p>I think therefore the deft. had a right to hold the Complainants
as his slaves at Fort Winnebago, if they were slaves before they were
brought to said Post, because he is not a citizen or resident of this
Territorym and because he is an officer of the U. S. Army.</p>

<pb xml:id="p008"/>
<p>This opinion I entertained and considered it the law of this
country while I was the additional Judge of the United States for the
Michigan Territory (of which this country was then a part)---that is
from the year 1823 ot the year 1832. In the year 1828 I expressed this
opinion to the defendant and to Captn. Smith also of the army. And I
have known several officers in the army who held slaves for years past
whilst stationed at posts in this Territory; amd I have never heard
that their right to do so was questioned, or have myself doubted this
right.</p>
<p>To the said 11th. Interrogatory I further answer that I am now a
Farmer; that I was the sole judge of the U. S. for the district of
country now embraced within the limits of Wiskonsan, during the period
above stated; that I have been a member of the legislature from this
district when it was a portion of Michigan, the Delegate in Congress
from this Territory and the Governor of the Territory for the last
three years.</p>
<p>To the 12th. and 13th. and 14th Interrogatories -</p>
<p>That I can give no farther answer or information (that I am
aware of) than such as is contained in my answer to the preceding
interrogatories.</p>
<p>This depostion is written and signed by me with my own hand this
twenty fifth day of November A.D. 1844.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
