<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0020.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Adam v. Andrew F. Leverton. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hayes, Sophia F." xml:id="sfh">Sophia F. Hayes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0020.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0674</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1789-09-11"> September 1789</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1789-09-08">September 8, 1789</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.006986">Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.006987">Cluthame, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006988">Costin, Elizabeth</term>
<term xml:id="per.006989">Costin, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.006990">Costin, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006991">Costin, Nancy</term>
<term xml:id="per.006992">Costin, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006993">Earles, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006994">Emory, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.006995">Hannah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006996">Layton, S.M.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006997">Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006998">Sevey, Jonathan</term>
<term xml:id="per.006999"> Sherwood, Hugh</term>
<term xml:id="per.007000">Susanna</term>
<term xml:id="per.007001">Tomlinson, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.007002">Wright, S.O.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Delaware</term>
<term>Queen Anne's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Easton (Md.)</term>
<term> Wilmington (Del.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term/><!-- What was the outcome of the case? e.g. Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006982">Adam</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.006983"> Leverton, Andrew F</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006984"> Wright, Robert </persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.006985"> Tilghman, James </persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-09" who="#sfh">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8199.jpg"/>
<fw>September Term 1789</fw>
<fw>103</fw>
<p>Negro Adam against Andrew F. Leverton</p>
<p>Be it remembered that Negro Adam tothe court 
here prefers the following Petition Towit, Tothe 
Honorable the Judges of the General Court of the state 
of Maryland forthe Eastern shore of said state now 
sitting. The Petition of negro Adam most humbly 
sheweth that he is illegally detained in slavery by a certain Andrew Foster Leverton
of Queen Anns County planter. He therefore prays your Honors to direct a subpoena 
out of your said to command said Andrew Foster Leverton to appear immediately
and answer tothe above complaint and that your Honors will take the premises into
your <unclear>humane</unclear> consideration and give your petitioner an early hearing inthe premises
and do therein what may be consistant with law and Justice and as is duty bound &amp;c
Robert Wright proplff. </p>
<p>Adam</p>
<p>which petition being read and granted. It is by the said court ordered that a summons
issued against the said Andrew Foster Leverton for his immediate appearance
to answer the complaint of the aforesaid Petitoner which said summons being
issued and return being made ofthesame by Jonathan Sevey Sheriff of Queen
 Anns County forthe time being that he had summoned the aforesaid Andrew Foster
Leverton to appear and answer according to the <unclear>exigence</unclear> ofthesame summons
and thereupon at thesame Court came the aforesaid Andrew Foster Leverton
by James Tilghman his attorney agreeable to the said summons thereupon
day was given as well tothe said Negro Adam as the said Andrew Foster
Leverton bytheir attorneys aforesaid totheir allegations and Evidence as well <unclear>on</unclear> 
the part and behalf of thesaid Negro Adam as the said Andrew Foster Leverton
ofand upon the premises aforesaid untill thesecond Tuesday of September next
following; At which day towit the second Tuesday of September annoDomini
one thousand seven hundred and eighty nine comes again as well the said negro
Adam by his attorney aforesaid as the said Andrew Foster Leverton by his 
attorney aforesaid. Whereupon all said singular thepremises aforesaid &amp;
the allegations and Evidences as well on the part and behalf ofthe said Negro
Adam <unclear>on</unclear> the said Andrew Foster Leverton being by the court have seen heard 
and fully understood and mature deliberation thereupon had It is considered 
by the court here that the Petition bedissmissed and that <unclear>aforesaid</unclear> negro Adam
return to the service of Andrew Foster Leverton his master again. </p>
<p>James Earles</p>
<p>And thesaid negro Adam byhis attorney prays that he may appeal</p>
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8200.jpg"/>
<fw>September Term 1789</fw>
<fw>104</fw>
<p>from the judgment aforesaid ofthe court here tothe States High Court of  appeals
and tohim thesame is granted by the Judges here: and it is ordered by the judges
aforesaid that the Record and proceedings aforesaid together with all things relating
tothesame be transmitted to the high court of appeals aforesaid that the judges ofthe
said court may further proceed therein as to Justice appertains and soforth
And be it remembered that the following State of the case was filed ofRecord 
at the trial of the above cause</p>
<p>Negro Adam against Andrew Foster Leverton</p>
<p>Petition for Freedom</p>
<p>This cause is submitted tothe court onthefollowing
State of facts, John Costin the late proprietor
of negro Adam in March seventeen hundred and eighty four, made his 
will a copy whereof is hereto annexed as part of the case and shortly after 
died that Elizabeth Costin his widow and <unclear>executive</unclear> proved the said will 
and took upon herself the <unclear>Burden</unclear> of the Execution thereof by taking 
sellers <unclear>testementary</unclear> and proceeding tothe settlement of the Estate that the 
said Elizabeth Costin shortly after moved to Wilmington in the Delaware 
state towit in seventeen hundred and eighty five, and carried with her negro 
Adam the Petitioner. That the said Elizabeth Costin shortly after her
removal to Wilmington intermarried with a certain Joseph Tomlinson
of Wilmington in said state where she has continued to reside ever since
her first removal, that she before her marriage aforesaid and she <unclear>&amp;</unclear>
said Tomlinson after the intermarriage aforesaid kept the said negro 
Adam in thestate of Delaware forthe space of one year and nine
months inthe whole after which thesaid Tomlinson and wife brought
the said negro Adam to Maryland to reside and remain in said state
and hired the said negro Adam with thesame <unclear></unclear> inthe said will 
of the said Tomlinson and wife to said Andrew Foster Leverton for <unclear>cause</unclear> 
during the year seventeen hundred and eighty eight, and also during 
the year seventeen hundred and eighty nine, where he still is. That 
the Estate ofthesaid John Costin is not yet settled that taxes have 
been paid inthis State regularly for said Adam during his twenty
one months Residence in Delaware and still are, that the 
personal Estate ofsaid John Costin is not sufficient to pay all his 
debts but his real and personal Esate fully sufficient</p>
<p>Robert Wright pro petr
Ja Tilghman for Joseph Tomlinson &amp;wife
Extr of John Costin who claim as Extr and 
for A H Leverton</p>
<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_8201.jpg"/>
<fw>September Term 1789</fw>
<fw>105</fw>
<p>and the following will of John Costin referred to inthe aforegoing case as being answered
thereto being also filed of Record in this Cause,</p>
<p>In the name of God amen
I John Costin of Queen Anne's county inthe state of Maryland being greatly
afflicted and wich in body but of sound and <unclear>disposing</unclear> mind memory and understanding 
and knowing the <unclear>uncertainlly</unclear> of human life and the certainty of death, do therefore
for the purpose of setting my temporal affairs and of being better prepared for
the time when it shall please God to call me, make this writing as and for my 
last will and Testament hereby making all former and other will by me made
Imprimis. I hereby resign my soul into the hands of almighty God in hope of a 
Joyful Resurrection at the last day <unclear>thro</unclear> the merits and meditation of my blessed savior
and Redemer Jesus Christ our lord and my body to be <unclear>decently</unclear> buried at the Discretion
ofmy Executive hereafter named and as to such <unclear>worldly</unclear> Estate wherewith it hath please
God to bless me I give and dispose thereof in manner following - I do will and divise
that the whole Rents and profits ofmy real and personal Estate shall be <unclear>assesed</unclear> bymy
Executive hereafter named tothe payment  &amp;and discharge ofmy lawful debts and
tothe support and maintainance ofherself and my four children until my said
debts are discharged not to exceed seven years from the day of my <unclear>decease</unclear> Item after
my lawful debts are paid and discharged in manner aforesaid. I give and devise unto 
my dear wife Elizabeth Costin all my part of atract ofland called Kindal containing
one hundred acres with my Dwelling plantation and all the improvements therefor 
and during the term of her natural</p>
<p>Item I give and bequeath unto my 
two Daughters Susan and Hannah allthat part ofatract ofland called Timber 
such as Timberland which I purchased of Rachel <unclear>Cluthame</unclear> and all that part of 
atract ofland called <unclear>Causey's</unclear> addition whereof I stand <unclear>sured</unclear> and possessed and 
also the residual and remainder ofthe parcel ofland called Kindal and my
<unclear>Dwelling</unclear> plantation and ofmy Estate therein <unclear>whenever</unclear> happening by <unclear>and</unclear> after
the death ofmy wife tobe equally divided between my said two Daughters and the
issue of their Respective Bodies lawfully begotten forever but if either of my 
said Daughters should die without issue as aforesaid then I will and divise
thelands before divided to my daughter who should so die without issue as aforesaid
and also the Residual and Remainder aforesaid whenever happening unto my Daughter 
Ann and the issue ofher Body lawfully begotten forever and for want of 
such issue tomy daughter Sarah and the heirs of her Body lawfully begotten
forever and if both my said Daughters Susanna and Hannah should die without
issue as aforesaid then I will and divise all mylands <unclear>tenements</unclear> and the residual 
and remainder aforesaid <unclear>whenever</unclear> happening to my daughters Sarah and </p>
<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_8202.jpg"/>
<fw>September Term 1789</fw>
<fw>106</fw>
<p>Ann and the issue oftheir bodies lawfully begotten respectively tobe equally
divided between them and bethe survivor ofthem and the issue of such survivor
lawfully begotten ofthe body forever and forward ofsuch issue tomy nephew
Henry Costin theson of Richard Costin and his heir forever. Item. I give and 
divise my whole personal Estate ofwhat nature <unclear>sowen</unclear> after my just debts are 
discharged in manner aforesaid tobe equally divided between my aforesaid wife
and two Daughters Sarah and and Ann and their assigns forever but ifeither
of my Daughters shall die before the age of sixteen or day of marriage then
 that the survivor shall have the sisters part thereof toher and her assigns forever
Item. in order to save the portions ofmy two daughters Sarah and Ann
<unclear></unclear> to an Equality with their sisters landed estate it is my will and
desire that the Rents and profits ofmy real estate (except the part 
thereof divised to my wife) or in Case ofher death the Rents and profits ofmy whole
real Estate after the discharge ofmy Debts in manner aforesaid and the 
support and maintainance ofmy Daughters Susan and Hannah during
the times of three years shall befor the said term ofthree years added tomy
personal Estate divised tomy Daughters Sarah and Ann and paid tomy said
daughters Sarah &amp; Ann by my Executive at their age of sixteen or day of 
marriage, but if either ofthem dies before sixteen or day of marriage then
the whole tobe paid tothe survivor ofthem at her age ofsixteen or day of 
marriage. Item I do hereby consitute and appoint my said wife guardian
ofmy said Daughters and any ofthem and tohave the care oftheir respective
Estates until they respectively arrive tothe age of sixteen or day of marriage
and lastly I do constitute and appoint mysaid wife Executive of this my 
last will and testament. In witness whereof I have hereto set my 
hand and seal this twenty sixth day of March seventeen hundred and eighty
four, signed sealed and delivered by the testator
and published and pronounced as and for 
his last will and testament <unclear>inpursuance</unclear>
<unclear>ofus</unclear> who have signed our names as
witnesses inhis presence and at his request.</p>
<p> John Costin</p>
<p>Ann Emory - Nancy Costin
Hugh Sherwood  <unclear>So Wright</unclear>
Queen Anns County <unclear>ad</unclear>
the 19th day of June 1784</p>
<p>Here came Elizabeth Costin and made oath
on the holy Evangels of almighty God, that the 
within instrument of writing is the true and whole will and testament
of John Costin late of Queen Anns County deceased that hath come tothe house
in possession and that she doth not know of any other. <unclear>certificate</unclear><unclear></unclear><unclear>SMLayton</unclear> Regt of Wills</p>
<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_8203.jpg"/>
<fw>September Term 1789</fw>
<fw>107</fw>
<p>Queen Ann County <unclear>ad</unclear>
the 19th day of June 1784</p>
<p>Here came Ann Emory one ofthe subscribing witnesses
tothe within last will and testament of John Costin late of 
Queen Anns County deceased, and made oath onthe holy Evangels of almighty God that 
she did see the testator therein named sign and seal their will and that she <unclear>heard</unclear> him
publish pronounce and declare <unclear>thesame</unclear> tobehis last will and testament that of the 
time of the so doing he was tothe best of her apprehensions ofsound and <unclear>disposing</unclear> mind
memory and understanding and that she subscribed her respective name as awitness
tothesame will and saw Nancy Costin and Hugh Sherwood subscribe their respective
names as witness tothis will inthepresence and at the request ofthe testator and
inthe presence of each other
Queen Anns County ad</p>
<p><unclear></unclear><unclear></unclear> certificate<unclear>SMLayton</unclear> Regt. of wills
for Queen Anns County</p>

<p>
Seal of Orphans Ct.for <unclear>Q. A.</unclear>Caty.</p>

<p>In testimony that the aforegoing is <unclear>atrue</unclear> copy of the
last will and testament of John Costin late of said county (and 
the endorcements thereon) deceased I have hereonto set my
home and affixed the public seal of the Orphans Court for
the court aforesaid this 19th day of June AnnoDomini 1786</p>
<p><unclear>SMLayton</unclear> Reg of Wills
for Queen Anns County</p>
<p>Therefore it is ordered by the court here that the record of the proceedings
be transmitted tothe state of Maryland's highcourt of appeals and they are
hereby transmitted accordingly</p>
<p>James Earles</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
