<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0177.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>James Rhodes v. Moses Ball. Transcript</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Martin, Heidi K." xml:id="hkm">Heidi K. Martin</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0177.015</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0179</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Transcript</title>
<date when="1844-03-15">March 15, 1844</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 267</collection>
<idno>Box 242, Folder 2289</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Transcript</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1844-01">January 1844</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Bender, Jacob A</term>
<term>Brent, William</term>
<term>Briscoe, Richard G</term>
<term>Brooke, Edward</term>
<term>Campbell, Daniel</term>
<term>Clarke, James I</term>
<term>Clarke, Joseph S</term>
<term>Cranch, William</term>
<term>Dashiell, George W</term>
<term>Goddard, John H</term>
<term>Harr, Henry</term>
<term>Hoff, Lawrence</term>
<term>Hunter, Alexander</term>
<term>Keeting</term>
<term>King, Vincent</term>
<term>Little</term>
<term>Lusby, James</term>
<term>McGill, Howard</term>
<term>Middleton, Benjamin F</term>
<term>Morsell, James S</term>
<term>Nevitt, Robert K</term>
<term>Riley, Thomas B</term>
<term>Taney, Robert B</term> 
<term>Thruston, Buckner</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>United States of America</term>
<term>District of Columbia</term>
<term>County of Washington</term>
<term>County of Alexandria</term>
<term>City of Washington</term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bell, Moses</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Rhodes, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Bradley, Joseph H</persName>
<persName>Hoban, James</persName>
<persName>Wallach, Richard</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Brent, Robert J</persName>
<persName>Brent, William Leigh</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#kln">Reviewed.</change>    
<change when="2022-06" who="#hkm">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_3925.jpg"/>

<p>James Rhodes<lb/>
Plff in Error<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Moses Bell<lb/>
Deft. in Error</p>

<p>Transcript Record</p>

<p>Filed 26th December 1842.</p>

<p>Affirmed with Costs<lb/>
15th March 1844.</p>

<note>2289</note>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_3928.jpg"/>

<p>Supreme Court of the United States<lb/>
No. 76</p>

<p>James Rhodes, Plff. in Er.<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Moses Bell</p>

<p>In error to the Circuit Court U.S. for
Washington County D.C.</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_3930.jpg"/>

<fw type="pageNum">1</fw>

<p>James <sic>Rhoes</sic><lb/>
Plff in Error
vs<lb/> 
Moses Bell<lb/>
Deft. in Error</p>

<p>Index.</p>

<table>
<row>
<cell>Petition for Writ of Error</cell>
<cell>page</cell>
<cell>2.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Assignment of Errors</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>3.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Order granting Merit of Error</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>4.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Writ of Error</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>4.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Citation</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>4.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Copy of Appeal Bond</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>6.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Styles of Court</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>10.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Parties</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>10.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Petition for freedom</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>11.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Subpoena</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>11.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Marshal's return &amp; Defts appearance</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>12.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Rule plea</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>12.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Venire facias</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>13.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Jury</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>14.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Special Verdict</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>14.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Judgment for petitioner</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>15.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Memorandum</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>16.</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell>Clerks Certificate &amp; Seal</cell>
<cell> " </cell>
<cell>17.</cell>
</row>
</table>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_3932.jpg"/>

<fw type="pageNum">2</fw>

<p>Petition to Ch. Justice U.S. for Writ of Error.</p>

<p>To the Honorable Roger B. Taney Chief
Justice of the United States.</p>

<p>The petition of James Rhodes of Washington
County in the District of Columbia, respectfully
sheweth, that at March Term 1842 of the
Circuit Court of the District of Columbia in and
for Washington County, a certain Moses Bell (colored)
by judgment of said Court, recovered his
freedom against your petitioner who then held &amp;
still holds said Moses Bell as his lawful slave,
as will more fully appear by the record of the proceedings
in said cause herewith exhibited as part of
this petition. Your petitioner sheweth that he
is aggrieved by said judgment and he prays that
an order may be passed by your Honor directing
a writ of Error to be issued by the Clerk of said
Court for the County of Washington, according to the
Act of Congress entitled "An Act to limit the
right of appeal from the Circuit Court of <del>for</del> the United
States for the District of Columbia." Approved 
2nd April 1816. Otherwise your petitioner will 
<sic>loose</sic> the benefit of all appeal to the Supreme
Court of the United States, as the matter in
Controversy is less in value than one thousand
dollars, though exceeding in value the sum of 
one hundred dollars exclusive of Costs, and he
refers to the subjoined assignment of errors as
part of this petition, and your petitioner as
in duty will every pray.</p>

<p>James Rhodes<lb/>
By Brent &amp; Brent<lb/>
his 
attorneys</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_3933.jpg"/>

<fw type="pageNum">3</fw>

<p>Asst. of Errors</p>

<p>Assignment of Errors in the judgment,
referred to in the aforegoing petition</p>

<p>1st. There is Error because the removal of
Moses Bell from Alexandria County to Washington
County in the District of Columbia, as
stated in the Special Verdict, did not entitle
him to his freedom under any law in force in
said District.</p>

<p>2nd. Moses Bell being over 45 years of age
at the time of such removal was in-capable
by the laws in force in said <del>District</del> Washington
County of receiving his freedom by or 
through any act or acts of his master or
owner.</p>

<p>3d. That said removal of Moses Bell is
not an importation, according to the true
intent and meaning of the laws in force
in Washington County aforesaid.</p>

<p>See case of Bank of Alexa vs Dyer
decided by Sup. Ct. within last 4 years.</p>

<p>4th. That such removal even if it would have 
been illegal previous to the year 1812, was
legalised and allowed by Act of Congress
of the 24th June 1812.</p>

<p>See 8 Peters p. 49 which show how
unsettled the law is on these points
and how desirable a decision is for
Citizens of the District, whose daily 
transactions may be within the operation
of these principles.</p>

<pb xml:id="p006" facs="IMG_3937.jpg"/>

<fw type="pageNum">4</fw>

<p>Whereupon the Honorable Chief Justice
made the following order, to wit:</p>

<p>Ordered that the Writ of Error be
issued according to the prayer of the within
petition.</p>

<p>R. B. Taney<lb/>
Chief Justice of the
Supreme Court
of the U. States<lb/>
Dec. 13. 1842</p>

<p>To William Brent Clerk<lb/>
of the Circuit Court<lb/>
for Washington County in<lb/>
the District of Columbia</p>

<p>Thereupon the following Writ of Error 
issued as ordered, to wit:</p>

<p>Writ of Error</p>

<p>District of Columbia, to wit:</p>

<p>The United States of America,</p>

<p>To the Judges of the Circuit
Court of the District of Columbia, sitting for
the County of Washington, greeting:</p>

<p>Because in the record and proceedings 
as also in the <unclear>rendition</unclear> of the judgment of a
plea which is in the said Court before you
or some of you between Moses Bell plaintiff
and James Rhodes, defendant; a manifest
error hath happened to the great damage of

<pb xml:id="p007" facs="IMG_3940.jpg"/>

<fw type="pageNum">5</fw>

of the said defendant, as by his complaint
appears. We being willing that error if any
hath been, should be duly corrected, and full
and speedy justice done to the parties aforesaid
in this behalf do command you if judgment
be therein given, that under your hand distinctly 
and openly you send the record and
proceedings aforesaid, with all the things concerning
the same to the Supreme Court of the
United States together with this writ, so that 
you have the same at Washington on the second
Monday of January next, in the said Supreme 
Court to be then and there held, and that the
record and proceedings aforesaid being inspected
the said Supreme Court may cause further to
be done therein to correct that error, which
of right, and according to the laws, and 
customs of the United States should be done.</p>

<p>Witness the Honorable Roger B. Taney
Chief Justice of said Supreme Court</p>

<p>Issued this 16th day of Dec. 1842</p>

<p>W. Brent Clk</p>

<pb xml:id="p008" facs="IMG_3942.jpg"/>

<p>8</p>

<p>District of Maryland to wit</p>

<p>The United States of America
To Moses Bell Greeting:</p>

<p>You are hereby cited and admonished to be and
appear at a Supreme Court of the United States
on the Second Monday of January next, pursuant 
to Writ of Error filed in the Clerk's
office of the Circuit Court of the United
States for the District of Columbia in the
County of Washington, wherein James
Rhodes is Plaintiff in Error and you are Defendant 
in Error to show cause if any
there be, why judgement rendered against the
said James Rhodes, Plaintiff in Error, should
it be corrected, and why speedy justice
would not be done to the parties in this behalf.</p>
<p>Witness my hand and seal this 13th
day of December 1842</p>

<p>R.B. Taney
Chief Justice of the
Supreme Court of the U. States</p>

<p>Service acknowledged 
J Hoban
for Moses Bell
Dec 14. 1842</p>

<p>Seal</p>

<pb xml:id="p009" facs="IMG_3943.jpg"/>

<p>7</p>
<p>&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</p>

<pb xml:id="p010" facs="IMG_3945.jpg"/>
<p>8</p>
<p>Copy of Appeal Bond</p>
<p>Know all men by these presents, that 
the James Rhodes, Joseph S. Clarke, &amp;
Richard G. Briscoe of Washington County in
the District of Columbia, are held and
firmly bound unto Moses Bell in the full
and just sum of five hundred dollars
current money of the United States to be
paid to the said <del>United</del> Moses Bell his
Certain Attorney executes, administers, 
or assigns to which payment well and truly
to be made and done, we bind ourselves 
and each of us over and each from him
executes and administrators, jointly and 
severally firmly by these presents, sealed with
our seals and dated this 1st day of December
1842.</p>
<p>Whereas application is about to be
made to prosecute and sue forth a Writ 
of Error to reverse the judgment of the Circuit
Court of the District of Columbia, sitting for
the County of Washington in a suit pending
with the said Court between Moses 
Bell plaintiff and James Rhodes, defendant,
wherein judgement was rendered against
the said James Rhodes.</p>
<p>Now the conditions of the above
obligations is such, that if the said James
Rhodes, shall prosecute his writ with effect
and answer all damages and costs, if he fails
to make his plea good, then the above
obligations to be null and void, otherwise
to be and remain in full force and
<pb xml:id="p011" facs="IMG_3946.jpg"/>
virtue in law.</p>
<p>Signed, Sealed, and <gap extent="unknown" reason="illegible"/>
in presence of
James I. Clarke</p>
<p>James Rhodes</p>
<p>seal</p>
<p>Joseph S. Clarke</p>
<p>seal</p>
<p>Richard G. Briscoe</p>
<p>seal</p>
<p>Dec 13, 1842
Approved 
R.B. Taney</p>

<pb xml:id="p012" facs="IMG_3950.jpg"/>
<p>10</p>
<p>Style of Court</p>
<p>District of Columbia To wit:</p>
<p>At a Circuit Court of the District
of Columbia, began and held in and for the
County of Washington, at the City of Washington
on the Fourth Monday of March, being the
Twenty eight today of the same month, in
the year of our Lord one thousand eight
hundred and forty two, and of the Independence
of the United Stats the Sixty-sixth</p>
<p>Present
William Cranch Chief Judge</p>
<p>the Honorable Buckner Thruston &amp;</p>
<p>James S Morsell Afs. Judges</p>
<p>Alexander Hunter Esq. Marshal</p>
<p>William Brent Clerk</p>
<p>In the records of the proceedings of the
said Court among others are the following
to wit;</p>
<p>Parties Moses Bell
vs.
James Rhodes</p>
<p>Be it remembered, that
heretofore, to wit: on the
eighteenth day of March
in the year of our Lord
<pb xml:id="p013" facs="IMG_3952.jpg"/>
one thousand eight hundred and forty one, the
said Moses Bell by Richard Wallach, Esquire,
his attorney filed in Court here, the following
Petition, to wit:</p>
<p>To the Honorable the Judges of the Circuit Court of the
District of Columbia, for Washington County.</p>
<p>The Petition of Moses Bell respectfully represents
unto your Honor that your petitioner
is entitled to his freedom, that he is held in slavery
by one James Rhodes of the said County, 
and prays that a subpoena may issue to the said
James Rhodes and his rights be inquired into
by your Honors. </p>
<p>R. Wallach
for Petitioner</p>
<p>Thereupon the United States Writ of Subpoena
was issued directed to the Marshal of
the District of Columbia in the words and of
the <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> following to wit:
The United States of America,
To the Marshal of the District of Columbia,
Greeting:</p>
<p>We command you that you summon
James Rhodes late of Washington County if he
shall be found within the County of Washington
in your said District, so that he be and appear
before the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia
to be held for the County aforesaid, at the City
of Washington on the fourth Monday of March
<pb xml:id="p014" facs="IMG_3954.jpg"/>
next, to answer unto Moses Bell's petition
for freedom filed in the said Court against him.</p>
<p>Witness William Cranch Esquire, Chief Judge
of our said Court, as the City of Washington, the 27th
day of January Anno Domini one thousand
eight hundred and forty one.</p>
<p>Issued the 18th day of March 1841
Wallach
W. Brent Clk</p>
<p>At which mentioned fourth Monday of
March in the year of Our Lord one thousand
eight hundred and forty one and the day of
the return of the above subpoena, comes 
again into the Circuit Court here, the said petitioner
by his Attorney aforesaid; and the 
Marshal of the District aforesaid, to whom the
same was directed, makes believe thereof to the
Court here thus endorsed, to wit:</p>
<p>"Summoned"
"A Hunter"
"Marshal."</p>
<p>Marshal's Return &amp; Defendant App. &amp; An plea.</p>
<p>And the said defendant being called
appears in Court here by Brent &amp; Brent, Esqrs.
his attornies; whereupon a motion of the said
petitioner by his attorney aforesaid it is ruled
by the Court here, that the said defendant
answer to the said complaint of the petitioner
in the plea aforesaid, or judgement by the
Court here will be entered against him in
<pb xml:id="p015" facs="IMG_3957.jpg"/>
default thereof; and the said defendant by
his attornies aforesaid defend the face and
injury when and so forth and prays leave
of the Court here, to <unclear>imparte</unclear> until the fourth
Monday of November next, and then to
answer the complaint of the said petitioner
in the plea aforesaid and to him it is posted,
the same day is given to the said petitioner also.</p>
<p>At which mentioned fourth Monday
of November in the year of Our Lord one thousand
eight hundred and forty one, to which
said day the said defendant had leave to
<unclear>imparte</unclear> and then to answer to the Complaint
of the said petitioner in the plea
aforesaid, comes again into the Circuit Court
here, as well the said petitioner by his
attorney aforesaid, as the said defendant
by his attornies aforesaid; and the said
defendant by his attorney aforesaid as before
defends the face and injury when and so 
forth and says that the said petitioner
is not entitled to his freedom as is alleged
and of this he puts himself upon the country,
and the said petitioner in like manner 
and so forth; therefore by a Jury therein appear
before the Court here on the fourth Monday of
March next, by when &amp;c and who neither
&amp; to recognize &amp;c because as well &amp;c and 
the same day is given to the said parties
<pb xml:id="p016" facs="IMG_3959.jpg"/>
then and there &amp;</p>
<p>And now at this day, to wit: the
said fourth Monday of March in the year
of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and
forty two, comes again into the Circuit Court
here, as well the said petitioner by his attorney
aforesaid, as the said Defendant by his
Attorney aforesaid: Whereupon for trying the
issue aforesaid, it is ordered by the Court here,
that twelve persons from the <sic>pannel</sic> of petit
jurors returned to the Court here, by the Marshal
of the District of Columbia be called, 
who being called, come to wit:</p>
<p>1 John H Goddard</p>
<p>2 Daniel Campbell</p>
<p>3 Benjamin F. Middleton</p>
<p>4 Howard McGill</p>
<p>5 Jacob A. Bender</p>
<p>6 Henry Harr</p>
<p>7 Robert K. Nevitt</p>
<p>8 Vincent King</p>
<p>9 George W. Dashiell</p>
<p>10 Thomas B. Riley</p>
<p>11 James Lusby</p>
<p>12 Edward Brooke</p>
<p>who being duly empannelled and sworn to say
the truth in the premises, upon their oath, do say,
"We of the Jury find that previous to the year
1837, the petitioner was the salve of a certain
Lawrence Hoff, a resident of Alexandria County
in the District of Columbia, that in the year 1837
the said Hoff, then owning &amp; possessing the 
petitioner as his slave in the County of Alexandria
aforesaid whereof he continued to be a resident,
did sell and deliver the petitioner to one Little
then being a resident of Washington County in the
<pb xml:id="p017" facs="IMG_3961.jpg"/>
District aforesaid, and that the delivery of the petitioner
was made to the said Little in Alexandria
County aforesaid, and the petitioner was immediately
removed by said Little to Washington County
aforesaid to reside and also for sale whereof said
Little was resident, that the said Little shortly
afterwards to wit: about one year or a little more
sold the petitioner to me Keeting in Washington County
who sold and delivered him to the defendant, that
<unclear>twice</unclear> said sale, to said Little the petitioner has
always been kept and held in slavery in the
County of Washington aforesaid. That at the time 
of the sale and delivery of the petition was
more than forty five years of age, to wit: he
was 54 or 55 years old, and is now 59 or 60 
years old. And if upon the facts aforesaid
the law is for the petitioner, then we find
for the petitioner on the issue joined the defendant
then we find for the Defendant on the issue
joined. Whereupon here seen, heard, and fully 
understood and mature deliberation being
thereupon had, the Court is of opinion
from the statement of facts aforesaid, that
the law is for the petitioner. Therefore it 
is counselered by the Court here, that the said
Moses Bell the petitioner aforesaid, recover
his freedom of and against the said James
<pb xml:id="p018" facs="IMG_3962.jpg"/>
Rhodes and that he be free and discharged
of and from the service of the said James
Rhodes, and that he the said Moses Bell
go thereof freed and discharged without day
&amp;c. It is also considered by the Court here, that 
the said Moses Bell, recover against the
said James Rhodes the sum of twenty 
one dollars and seventy two cents by
the court here into him the said Moses Bell,
argued on his appeal for his costs and
charges by him about the prosecution of
his petition aforesaid laid out and 
and that he have thereof his execution &amp;c.</p>
<p>Memorandum. 1842 August 20th Judgment
rendered in this case on Special verdict
for Petitioner and $21.72/no costs.</p>
<p>Test. W Brent Clk</p>

<p>Writ of Error Produced</p>
<p>And whereas afterwards, to wit: on the
<del>twenty</del> nineteenth day of December in the year
of our Lord one thousand eight hundred
and forty two, the said James Rhodes the 
defendant aforesaid, by his attorney aforesaid,
produced and filed in Court here, the United
States Writ for the correcting of errors of and
upon the judgment aforesaid, directed to the
Judges of the Circuit Court of the District of
Columbia in the County of Washington, and in
pursuance thereof, and according to the form
<pb xml:id="p019" facs="IMG_3961.jpg"/>
and effect of the law in such case made and
provided a Transcript of the Record of
proceedings of the judgment aforesaid
and all things thereunto relating with the Writ
of Error aforesaid, and a Copy of the Appeal
bond hereunto annexed, are hereby transmitted
to the said Supreme Court accordingly.</p>
<p>The Testimony whereof I have hereunto 
subscribed my name and affixed
the seal of said Court at the City of 
Washington this 24th day of December
1842.</p>
<p>W Brent Clk</p>




</div1>


    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
