<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0018.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Rachel v. Thomas Roberts and Zachariah Roberts. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Zuniga, Santiago" xml:id="sz">Santiago Zuniga</name>
<name n="Kevin-Aligah, Grace Ogechi" xml:id="goka"> Grace Ogechi Kevin-Aligah</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0018.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0672</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1784-09-19">September 19, 1784</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1787-04">April 1787</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.006918">Bordley, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006920">Brown, John</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006919">Byron, James</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006923">Downes, Vachel</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006922">Earle, James</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006924">Emory, Arthur</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006925">Forman</term> 
<term xml:id="per.005383">Harrison, Robert Hanson</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006926">Ridgaway, Samuel</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006927">Sewell, Clement</term>
<term xml:id="per.006928">Thomas</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Queen Ann's County</term>
<term>Talbot County</term>
<term>Chester Mills</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgment for Petitioner</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006929">Rachel</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.006930">Roberts, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.006931">Roberts, Zachariah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.004871">Wright, Robert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.006932">Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-07" who="#SZ">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
<change when="2023-06-08" who="#goka">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8193.jpg"/>

<p>Memorandum the Defendants in this cause by Gustavus Scott their attorney sued out the State of Maryland's unit of certiorari, the tenor whereof ensues in the following words, towit:</p>
    
<p>The State of Maryland To the Justices of Queen Ann's County Greeting:</p>

<p>whereas black Rachel hath prepared a Petition before
you our said Justices humbly shewing that she the said Rachel is unjustly and unlawfully detained as a slave by Thomas and Zachariah
Roberts of Queen Ann's County, planters, and praying that a subpena might
issue forthwith to compel the attendance of the said Thomas and Zachariah
Roberts to answer unto lieu the Petitioner of and upon the Premises and
that she the said Petitioner might be discharged from servitude to
which said Petition is still depending  before you our said Justices in
our said court as it is said and we being desirous for certain reasons
that the Record of the said Petition with all proceedings thereon
had should by you be certified:</p>
    
<p>Do command you that you send under your seals the Record of the Petition afd and all the Proceedings
thereon with all things touching the same to the Judges of our General
Court to be held for the Eastern Shore of this State at Talbot County Court
House the second Tuesday of September next plainly and distinctly</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8194.jpg"/>
    
<p>and distinctly and in as full and ample manner as it now remains before you
together with this writ so that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what
shall appear to us of right ought to be done--</p>
    
<p>witness Robert Hanson Harrison
Esqr chief Judge of our said Court this 20. day of april anno Domini 1784.
Sued 19 June 1784.</p>
    
<p>James Earle Clk:</p>
    
<p>At which said day, towit, the second Tuesday of September anno Domini
one thousand seven hundred and eighty four, being the day of the return of the
aforegoing writ the Justices and Clerk of Queen Ann's County in compliance
with the writ aforesaid make return thereof to the Court here with the following
Record annexed, towit:</p>
    
<p>Maryland towit:</p>
    
<p>At a county court held for Queen
Ann's County at Chester Mills in the said County on the fourth Tuesday
in March, being the twenty third day of the same month and in the year
seventeen hundred and eighty four, By the Commissioners and
Officers authorized and impowered to hold the same Court of whom
were Present Mr. John Brown, Mr. Clement Sewell, Mr. Vachel
Downes, Mr. Thomas Mr. Forman.--</p>
    
<p>Saml. Ridgaway Esq Sheriff.--</p>
    
<p>Downes Clk</p>
    
<p>Black Rachel Preferred the following Petition, towit:</p>

<p>To the worshipful the Justices of Queen Ann's County Court
The Petition of black Rachel Humbly sheweth that she the said
Rachel is unjustly and unlawfully detained as a slave by Thomas &amp; Zachriah
Roberts of Queen Ann's County Planters and your Petitioner therefore
prays that a subpena, may issue forthwith to compel the attendance
of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts to answer unto your Petitioner
of and whom the Premises and that your Petitioner may be discharged
from servitude, and as in duty bound &amp;c</p>
    
<p>Rachel Petitioner</p>
    
<p>Rob Wright atty for Pettr.</p>

<p>On reading the above Petition, ordered by the Court here, that the same be
granted and that subpena issue forthwith to compel the attendance</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_8195.jpg"/>

<p>of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts according to the prayer of the same Petition:</p>
    
<p>which was accordingly issued, and the Sheriff of Queen Ann's County
makes return thereon in the following words, towit, Summoned by Saml. Ridgaway
Sheriff:</p>

<p>whereupon the same Thomas and Zachariah Roberts appeared in
open Court, and Recognized in Forty pounds current money each, conditioned
for the appearance of the said black Rachel on the third Monday
in May next to prosecute her said Petition for freedom, and also for
their appearance at the same time to Defend.--</p>
    
<p>The Court adjourns till the third Monday in May next
Monday 17. May 1784. The Court met according to adjournment
Present Mr. John Brown, Mr. James Bordley, Mr. Clement Sewell,
Mr. Vachel Downes:</p>
    
<p>Thomas and Zachariah Roberts appears
with black Rachel, in open Court, according to the tenor of their
Recognizance and was by the court here, ordered to be discharged
there from, and at the same time the same Thomas and Zachariah Roberts
Recognized in the sum of Forty pounds current money each conditioned
for the appearance of black Rachel at June Court next, to prosecute
her Petition of Freedom, and also for their appearance at the same time to
Defend.--</p>
    
<p>Maryland, towit, at a County Court held for Queen Ann's County
at Chester Mill in said County the fourth Tuesday in June being the
twenty second day of the same month and in the year seventeen hundred and eighty four.--</p>
    
<p>By commissioners and officers authorized
and impowered to hold the same Court, of whom were Present
Mr. John Brown, Mr. James Bordley, Mr. James Bryon, Mr. Clement
Sewell, Mr. Arthur <unclear>Emory jur</unclear>.</p>
    
<p>Saml. Ridgaway Esq Sheriff</p>
    
<p>Downes Clk</p>
    
<p>(Thomas)</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_8196.jpg"/>    
    
<p>Thomas and Zachariah Roberts appears with black Rachel, according to the Tenor
of their Recognizance. The Court here received a Certiorari to remove the Petition
of black Rachel for Freedom and the Record of the Proceedings thereon:</p>

<p>and ordered that the same be Transmitted under Seal to the next General Court to be
held for the Eastern Shore in the State of Maryland:</p>
    
<p>In Testimony that the aforegoing is a true copy taken from the Records of Queen Ann's
County afd I have hereto set my hand and affixed the public seal of the County
afd this 2d. day of Septr. anno Dom 1784. Downes Clk:</p>
    
<p>and now here at this day, towit, the said second Tuesday of September anno Domini
one thousand seven hundred and eighty four, comes into the General Court here as
well the said Negro Rachel by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Thomas and 
Zachariah Roberts by their attorney aforesaid:</p>
    
<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises aforesaid
between the Parties aforesaid by consent of the said Parties and their attorneys
aforesaid and by order of the Court here thereon was continued until the
second Tuesday of April next following.--</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of April anno Domini One thousand
seven hundred and eighty five came again the parties aforesaid by their
attorneys aforesaid:</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises aforesaid
between the Parties aforesaid by consent of the said Parties and their attorneys
aforesaid and by order of the Court here thereon was continued until the
second Tuesday of September next following.--</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of April anno Domini One thousand
seven hundred and eighty five came again the parties aforesaid by their
attorneys aforesaid:</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises aforesaid,
between the Parties aforesaid by consent of the said Parties and their attorneys
aforesaid and by order of the Court here thereon, was further continued until the
second Tuesday of September next following.--</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of April anno Domini One thousand seven hundered and eighty six, came again the
parties aforesaid by their attorneys afd:</p>
    
<p>Thereupon further process of</p>

<p>|cond|</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_8197.jpg"/>   

<p>and upon the Premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by consent of the said
Parties and their attorneys aforesaid and by order of the Court here thereon was
continued until the second Tuesday of September then next following.--</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of September anno Domini, one
thousand seven hundred and eighty six, came again the parties aforesaid
by their attorneys aforesaid :</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the Premsises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by consent of the
said Parties and their attorneys aforesaid and by order of the Court here
thereon was continued until the second Tuesday of April next following.--</p>

<p>And now here at this day, towit the said
second Tuesday of April anno Domini, One thousand seven hundred
and eighty seven, comes as well the aforesaid Negro Rachel by her
attorney aforesaid, as the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts by
their attorney aforesaid: whereupon all and singular the Premises
aforesaid and the allegations and Evidences as well on the part and
of the said Negro Rachel, as also on the part and behalf-
behalf of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts being by the
Court here seen, heard, fully understood and mature deliberation thereon
had; It is considered by the Judges here that the Petitioner is intitled
to her Freedom and that thereof she be free liberated and discharged
from the Custody and possession of the said Thomas and Zachariah
Roberts her Master.--</p>

<p>James Earle Clk:</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
