<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0026.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Maria Hughes, Daniel Hughes, Frank Hughes, and Lydia Hughes v. Henry Dickinson. Judgment Record.</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name> n="Chen, Ellis" xml:id="ec">Ellis Chen</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.mdcase.0026.001"></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0680"></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1789-05-06">May 6, 1789</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1789-04">April 1789</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.006922">Earle, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">  
<term>Caroline County (Md.)</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgment for Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006981">Hughes, Maria</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.007117">Hughes, Daniel</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.007118">Hughes, Frank</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.007119">Hughes, Lydia</persName> 
</person>

<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.007122">Dickinson, Henry</persName>
</person>

<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006984">Wright, Robert</persName>
</person>

<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.007120">Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-09" who="#ec">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8155.jpg"/>

<p>
Maria, Daniel, Frank 
and Lydia Hughes
against
Henry Dickinson

Be it remembered that at September Term Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and eighty 
seven, on the thirteenth day of the same Month,
the following Petition for freedom was by Robert
Wright attorney for the said Maria, Daniel, Frank
and Lydia Hughes preferred to the Court here to wit. "To the Honourable the Judges
of the General Court. The Petition of Bridget alias Maria Hughes Daniel Hughes 
Frank Hughes and Lydia Hughes most humbly showeth that they are unlawfully
detained as slaves by a certain Henry Dickinson of Caroline County
Your Petitioners therefore pray that a Subpena may issue against the said Henry
Dickinson to appear at this Court to show cause if any he hath why he detains 
your said Petitioners in Slavery, and do therein what to your honours may
seem just &amp; right and as &amp;ca - Daniel Hughes Frank Hughes
Robert Wright <unclear>Pro Petio</unclear> Lydia Hughes — "
Which Petition being read and granted it was ordered by the Court here that 
a Subpena be issued for the said Henry Dickinson to appear on the second Tuesday
of April then next whereupon command was given to the Sheriff of Caroline
County to summon Henry Dickinson, that all excuses and delays set aside he be
and appear before the Judges of our Genl. Court on the secondary Tuesday of April then
next, to answer the Petition of Maria, Daniel Frank and Lydia Hughes preferred agt.
him for freedom and that he should have then and there that <unclear></unclear> summons.
At which said second Tuesday of April in the year Seventeen hundred and eighty 
eight here came the said Petitioners by their Attorney aforesaid and the sheriff of
Caroline County aforesaid to whom the said summons was directed came and
made return that he could not summon the said Henry Dickinson as by the 
said Subpena he was commanded; and thereupon it was again ordered by the 
Court here, that <unclear></unclear> another Subpena should be issued for the said Henry to be and
appear before the Judges of our said Court on the second Tuesday of September, then next
to answer and soforth as above: whereupon command was given to the Sheriff
of Caroline County to summon Henry Dickinson, that all causes and delays be 
set aside, he be and appear before the Judges of our said General Court on the second
</p>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8156.jpg"/>

<fw>April Term 1789.</fw>
<fw>331</fw>

<p>
Tuesday of September then next; to answer to the Petition of Maria, Daniel, Frank
and Lydia Hughes, preferred against him for freedom, and that the said sheriff
should have then and there that subpena — At which said second Tuesday of
September in the year seventeen hundred and eighty eight, here come again the said
Petitioners by their Attorney aforesaid; and the Sheriff of Caroline County aforesaid
to whom the same Subpena was directed came and made return to the Court here
that he had summoned the said Henry as by the same subpena he was commanded
and thereupon came into court the said Henry Dickinson by Gustavus Scott and 
Luther Martin his Attorneys: whereupon day was given by the Court here to the said
parties, to hear the <sic>alegations</sic> and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said
Petitioners; as the said Henry until the second Tuesday of April then next following.
And now here at this day to wit, the said second Tuesday of April, in the year
One thousand seven hundred and eighty nine come again the Parties afd by their 
Attorneys afd, and upon hearing the Petition, the allegations of each Party, and
the Testimony by each <unclear>adduced</unclear> it is considered by the Court that the Petitioners
are not entitled to their Freedom and therefore they are remaned again to the service of their master Henry Dickinson. James Earle Clk:
Judgment was <unclear>rendered</unclear> in this action on the 6th day of May Anno Domini 1789.
</p>


</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
