<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="<!-- file name, check Case Spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.case.0011.015 -->">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Arthur Savoy and Jane Savoy v. William Bright. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<!-- add your name; e.g. - <name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name> -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0024.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0678</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="<!-- yyyy-mm-dd -->"><!-- June 25, 1810 --></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term> <!--Note: this is an assault case-->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1756-11">November 1756</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term></term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  


</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>, 
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Upper Marlboro (Md.)</term> 
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Verdict for Defendant</term>
<term>Judgment for Defendant</term>
<term>Judgment for Plaintiff for Costs</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Savoy, Arthur</persName> 
</person>

<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Savoy, Jane</persName>
</person>

<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Bright, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Darnall, Henry</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Dulany, Daniel</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. Prince George's County Court</orgName>
<placeName>Upper Marlboro (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="yyyy-mm-dd" who="#ini">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="<!-- image name-->.jpg"/>

<p>

Arthur Savoy &amp; Jane his Wife v William Bright
Verdict of Judgment for Defendant

Prince Georges County <unclear></unclear> William Bright of Prince Georges County <unclear>Planter</unclear> was attached to answer unto Arthur 
Savoy &amp; Jane his wife of <unclear></unclear>wherefore with force and <unclear>arms</unclear> of prince Georges County the said William Bright 
<unclear>or her</unclear> the said Jane an assault did make and her the said Jane did beat Wound and Evilly Treat so that of <unclear>his</unclear>
life it was greatly despaired and other great <unclear>harmes</unclear> to her did do to the great damage of her the said Jane and
against the Peace of the Right Honourable the Lord Proprietary and so forth. And whereupon the <unclear>same</unclear>
Arthur Savoy &amp;Jane his Wife by <unclear>Henry Darnall</unclear> their attorney complains that the afd. William Bright
the Sixteenth day of November in the year of our Lord one thousand Seven hundred &amp;fifty five <unclear>at</unclear>
Prince Georges County afd with force and <unclear>arms</unclear> to wit with Firsts, Clubs, Whips, <unclear>Staves</unclear>, teeth &amp;nails <unclear>upon</unclear>
her the said Jane at the County afd an assault did make and her did Beat wound &amp;evilly Treat <unclear></unclear>
that of her life it was greatly despaired and other great harmes to her did against the <unclear>Right/Bright</unclear>
Honourable the Lord Proprietary that now is &amp;ca and to the damage of the said Arthur Savoy &amp;Jane his wife 
Thirty pounds Current money of Maryland and therefore they bring suit &amp;ca ... Pledges &amp;ca <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear>
and the afd William Bright by Daniel <unclear>Dulany</unclear> his attorney Comes &amp;defends the force and Injury when <unclear></unclear>
and prays lycence of the Court here to Imparle until the Next County Court to be held at Upper Marlbro
Town in said County on the fourth Tuesday in March next and <unclear>he hath it</unclear>, and the same day is given to the <unclear>same</unclear>
Arthur Savoy &amp;Wife here <unclear>Zca.</unclear> at which day towit the fourt Tuesday in March afd. Comes here at the Town <unclear></unclear>
before the Justices of the Court here as well the said Arthur &amp;wife as the said William by their attorneys afd <unclear></unclear>
the said William by his attorney afd prays further Lycence thereof to Imparle here until the next County Court <unclear>to be</unclear>
held at Upper Marlbro Town in said County on the fourth Tuesday in June next <unclear>&amp;he hath it,</unclear> and the same <unclear></unclear>
is given the same Arthur &amp;wife here <unclear>zca</unclear> at which day towit the fourth Tuesday in June afd. Comes <unclear></unclear>
at the Town afd. before the Justices of the Court here as well the said Arthur &amp;wife as the said William by 
their attorneys afd. and the said William by his attorney afd prays further Lycence thereof to Imparle
here untill the Next County Court to be held at Upper Marlbro Town in said County on the fourth <gap></gap>
in August next &amp;he hath it and the same day is given the same Arthur Savoy here zca. at which day <gap></gap>
the fourth Tuesday in August afd. Comes here at the Town afd before the Justices of the Court here as <gap></gap>
said Arthur &amp; wife as the said William by their Attorneys afd and the said William by his attorney afd 

<pb facs="IMG_7986">
<fw>November Court 1756</fw>
<fw>373</fw>

prays further Lycence thereof to Imparle here until the next County Court to be held at Upper Marlbro Town in said
County on the fourth Tuesday in November Next and he hath it, and the same day is given the same Arthur and
Wife here zca: at which day to wit the fourth Tuesday in November afd. come here at the Town afd before the Justices of the
Court here as well the said Arthur &amp;wife as the said William by their attorneys afd and the said Arthur Wife
by their attorneys afd prays that the said William to <unclear>their Dictaration</unclear> above against him may Answer. And the 
afd. William by Daniel <unclear>Dulany</unclear> his attorney comes &amp;defends the forces of Injury <unclear>when</unclear> zca. and <unclear>saith</unclear> that he is not 
guilty of the <unclear></unclear> and assault above said to his Charge, in manner and form as the afd Arthur &amp; James above Complains
against him, and of this he <unclear></unclear> himself upon the <unclear>Country</unclear> &amp;the afd. Arthur &amp; Jane <unclear>like wises</unclear>, and the afd William
by leave of the Court here &amp; according to the form of the <unclear>statutes</unclear> in such <unclear>cases</unclear>made &amp; provided, further comes &amp;defends 
the force of injury when &amp;ca and as to the <unclear>residence</unclear> of the <unclear></unclear> and assault, by the said William in the <unclear></unclear>
<unclear>whom</unclear> afd above supposed to be done, the said William <unclear>saith</unclear> that the afd Arthur &amp; Jane ought not to have their  
action afd against him, because he saith, that the afd Jane the day and year in the declaration afd above <unclear></unclear>
<unclear></unclear> at the County afd with force and arms upon the said William made an assault, and him the said William then 
&amp;there would have beaten, wounded and evilly treated, <unclear></unclear> the same William then and there had sooner defended 
himself against the said Jane, and so the said William saith, that if any Damage or Evil then &amp; there <unclear>accrued</unclear> to
the said Jane, it was of the said Jane's own fault and this the said William is Ready to Verify, wherefore he prays Judgment, 
if the afd Arthur and Jane ought to have or maintain their action afd against him &amp;ca and the afd
Arthur &amp;Jane as to all the Residue of the Trespass and assault by the said William in the declaration afd above
<unclear>supposed</unclear> to be done, <unclear>say</unclear>, that.they. for anything by the said William above <unclear>on</unclear> that behalf by pleading before 
<unclear>alledged</unclear>, ought not to be precluded from having their action afd thereof against him, because they say. that 
the afd William of his own <unclear>proper</unclear> <unclear>Wrong</unclear>, and without such <unclear>Causes</unclear>, as by the said William above in that
<unclear>behalf</unclear> by pleading alledged, made an assault upon the said jane, and her did beat, wound and Evilly
treat, in manner and form as the afd Arthur &amp;Jane have Complained against the said William and this
they pray may be <unclear>Inquired</unclear>of the <unclear>Country</unclear>, and the afd William likewise. It is therefore Commanded the
<unclear>Sheriff</unclear> to wit <unclear>Colmore Beanes</unclear> Gentleman that he <unclear>Cause</unclear> to come here <unclear>Immidiately</unclear> this day to wit the fourth Tuesday 
in November afd Twelve &amp;ca by <unclear>whom</unclear> &amp;ca and who neither &amp;ca to Recognize &amp;ca because as well &amp;ca and
the same day is further given the Parties afd an now at this day to with the third Tuesday in November afd
Comes here again at the Town afd before the Justices of the Court here the Parties afd by their attorneys afd and 
the jurors thereon <unclear>Impannelled</unclear> being called Namely, Richard Duckett, James Gibbs, William Higgins,
Robert Whittaker, Paul Talbutt, James Wood, Thomas <unclear>Baden</unclear>, John <unclear>Berry</unclear>, James <unclear>Burgelo</unclear>, James Jones. Daniel <unclear>Frouirer</unclear> &amp; Benjamin Brooke. Likewise Come who to say the <unclear></unclear><unclear></unclear> the <unclear></unclear> being Elected <unclear>Tryed</unclear> and sworn
do say upon their oath, that the said William is not Guilty of the Trespass and Assault afd in manner and 
form as the said Arthur &amp; Jane above in their Declaration against him have Complained, therefore the
said William go without <unclear>day</unclear> <unclear>&amp;</unclear> the said Arthur &amp; Jane in <unclear>Macy</unclear> zca. Whereupon on the prayer of the
said William by his attorney afd that Judgment on the Verdict afd for him be Rendered, November <unclear>23d</unclear>
1756. It is <unclear>considered</unclear> by the Court here that the said William Recover against the said Arthur &amp; Jane
Six Hundred and Fifty Five pounds of Tobacco for his Costs &amp; Charges by him about his <unclear>defense/defence</unclear> in
this <unclear>part</unclear> sustained by the Court hereof the said Lord the Proprietary of the <unclear></unclear> of the said William
adjudged that thereof he have Execution <unclear>zca</unclear>: 

Arthur Savoy v William Bright
Judgment for Plantif for Costs
Prince Georges County <unclear></unclear> William Brightt of Prince Georges County Planter was attached to answer unto Arthur Savoy
<unclear></unclear> wherefore with force and arms at Prince Georges County <unclear></unclear> the said William Brightt on him the said Arthur an assault
did make and him the said Arthur did beat wound and evilly Treat so that of his life <unclear>is was</unclear> greatly <unclear>dispaired</unclear> and other
great harms to him did do to the great damage of him the said Arthur and against the Peace of the Right
Honourable the Lord Proprietary and <unclear>soforth</unclear>. And whereupon the same Arthur Savoy by Henry <unclear>Darnall</unclear>
his attorney complains that the afd William Brightt the sixteenth day of November in the year of our Lord one
Thousand Seven hundred &amp; fifty five at prince Georges County afd with force &amp; arms to wit Fists, Clubs
Whips, Staves Teeth &amp;Nails upon him the said Arthur Savoy at the County afd an assault did make
and him did beat wound &amp;evilly Treat so that of his life it was Greatly despaired and other great
<unclear>Enormities</unclear> to him did against the peace of the Right Honourable the Lord Proprietary <unclear>thas</unclear> now is
<unclear>&amp;ca</unclear> and to the damage of the said Arthur Savoy Thirty Pounds Current Money of Maryland
and <unclear>therefore</unclear> he brings <unclear></unclear> &amp;ca. 

Pledges &amp;ca <unclear>John Doe &amp;</unclear> <unclear>R2. Roe</unclear>
</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
