<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0006.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In the Matter of Denison et al. Court Report</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Chijioke, Chikamso" xml:id="CC">Chikamso Chijioke</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
    <idno type="project">oscys.reu.0006.001</idno>
    <idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0691</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <title level="m" type="main">Court Report</title>
<date when="1807-08-26">September 26, 1807</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Court Report</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1807-08">September 1807</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Angus Mackintosh</term><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Askin</term>  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Biddle</term>  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>C.J Woodward</term>  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Cooley</term>  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Henry Clay</term>  
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Matthew Elliot</term>  
</keywords>   
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Richard Pattison</term>  
</keywords>
 
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Sibley</term>  
</keywords>
 
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>William Tucker</term>  
</keywords>
 
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>France, Canada, Detroit</term><!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgment for Respondent</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>DENISON, ELIZABETH</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>DENISON, JAMES</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>DENISON, SCIPIO</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>DENISON, JR., PETER</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>CATHERINE TUCKER</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Brush, Elijah</persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Hickman, H. Harris</persName> <persName>Harrison, Jonas</persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Michigan Territory. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Detroit (Mi.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-18" who="#CC">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p>Case 60</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF ELIZABETH DENISON, JAMES DENISON, SCIPIO DENISON AND PETER DENISON,JR.</p>
<p>1807</p>
<p>Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Jorunal Entries</p>
<p>1. Writ of habeas corpus ordered</p>
<p>2. Arguments heard</p>
<p>3. Decision</p>
<p>4. Opinion</p>
    
<pb xml:id="p002"/>
    
<p>CALENDER OF CASES</p>
<p>Papers in File</p>
<p>1. Writ of habeas corpus</p>
<p>2. Return of writ of habeas corpus</p>
<p>Note:"In 1807 a very curious case arose concerning slavery. Mrs. Catherine tucker was required, upon habeas corpus, to answer for the detenion of Elizabeth and Scipio Denison, persons of color, and she justified on the ground that they were held as slaves at the time of the surrender of the post in 1796, and were assured to her under Jay's Treaty, in spite of the provision against slavery in the ordinance of 1787. Judge Woodward gave the matter a very elaborate examination, and wrote a full opinion sustaining her right. The case was decided on the 23rd of September. A few days later, application was made for the arrest and delivery of some Pawnee and mulatto slaves who had escaped from their masters, Mr. Pattinson and Matthew Elliott, who resided in Canada. In this case the decision was emphatic that there was no obligation to give up fugitives from a foreign jurisdiction. Thereupon Lisette and Scipio went over the river into Canada, where the same docterines were enforced, and they took refuge with Mr. Askin; and they were for a time employed in the family of Angus Mackintosh. They subsequently came back and were never molested,--remainig with Colonel Brush, Judge Sibley and Major Biddle, most of their lives. Lissette accumulated some property. The attempt to obtain Mr. Elliott's servants led to a disturbance. His agent was tarred and feathered, and himself treate with some indignity." (Campbell, Outlines of the Political Hisory of Michigan, 246-7) Judge Cooley, also, gave an account of these cases. (Michigan-- A History of Governments-- 136-7) Other accounts will be found in Michigan Pioneer and Historical Collections, XXIX, 646; ibid.,XXXVIII, 127; and in Bond, The Civilization of the Old Northwest, 221. The Elliot and Pattinson cases are cases 75 and 76 infra. Cases 9, 77, and 186 also involved slavery. An incomplete copy of the opinion apppears in Michigan Pioneer Collections, XII, 511-8. A letter dated August 18, 1807, gave references to the laws concerning slavery. (Ibid., pp.650-1) A synopsis of the opinion is give in Syllabi of Decisions and Opinions, infra. In March, 1812, Judge Woodward transmitted to Henry Clay, Speaker of the House of Representatives, "The decision in the case of the Denisons, claimed as slaves, against Catherine Tucker, on a writ of Habeas Corpus, and in the case of Richard Pattinson, a subject of his Britannic Majesty, residing in Upper Canada, on an application, for the restoration of his slaves, the latter a printed copy, both together determining the general question of slavery, as relating to the Territory of Michigan; and a legislative resolution proposed respecting and executive transaction in the relation to slaves, which, with other matters, gave rise to the dissatisfaction</p>

<pb xml:id="p003"/>
    
<p>of the executive magistrate, with the judge proposing it, taking date in October 1806, and October 1808." (House Files, portfolio 16) Woodward had proposed a bill providing for the restoration of slaves and deseerters. (Note, case 19, supra)</p>

<pb xml:id="p004"/>
<p>SYLLABI OF DECISIONS AND OPINIONS</p>
<p>NO. 60</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF ELIZABETH DEISON, ET AL.</p>
<p>September 26,1807</p>
<p>Habeas corpus</p>
<p>In obedience to a writ of habeas corpus Catherine Tucker brought before the court the bodies of the petitioners, and, as cause for their detention, stated that petitioners were born within the precincts and jurisdiction of the Post of Detroit while it was a part of Upper Canada and were children of slaves owned by William Tucker; that William Tucker and his heirs resided within the precincts and jurisdiction of the Post of Detroit at the time the post was surrendered by the British and were such settlers and traders as were contemplated by Jay's Treaty which provided "that all the settlers or traders, within the precincts or jursidiction of the said posts, shall continue to enjoy, unmolested all their property of every kind, and shall be protected therein, etc." The return was held sufficient.</p>
<p>Elijah Brush, attorney for petitioners</p>
<p>Harris H. Hickman and Jonas Harrison, attorneys for respondent</p>
<p>OPINION BY WOODWARD, C.J</p>
<p>1. When a statutory method of investigating the right to freedom is not provided, the common-law writ of habeas corpus is appropriate.</p>
<p>2. The question to be decided on a return of a writ of habeas corpus being the sufficiency of the return, facts stated in the return are not traversable at this stage of the proceedings.</p>
<p>3. Laws of France and Upper Canada noticed in a return of a writ of habeas corpus can be considered although they do not come as properly authenticated public documents:</p>
    <p>a. If they are the laws of a foreign state, they are matters of fact and as such are not traversable at this stage.</p>
    <p>b. If they are laws of this country, they must be judicially noticed.</p>
<p>4. The laws of France and Upper Canada ceased to have any effect in this Territory almost immediately after July 11, 1796, but under Jay's Treaty settlers continue to enjoy thier property of any kind.</p>

<pb xml:id="p005"/>

<p>SUPREME COURT OF MICHIGAN</p>
<p>5. The term property as used in Jay's Treaty includes slaves, as slaves were recognized as property by the countries concerned</p>
<p>6. Slaves living on May 31, 1793, and in the possesion of settlers in this Territory on July 11, 1796, continue such for life; children of such slaves born between these dates continue in servitude for twenty-five years; children of such children, and all born after July 11,1796, are free from birth</p>
<p>Note: See note, case 60, Calender of Cases, supra.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
