<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0016.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Nan v. Thomas and Zachariah Roberts, Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt"></principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Krohn, Esme M." xml:id="emk">Esme M. Krohn</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.mdcase.0016.001"></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0670"></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1787-04-20"> April 20, 1787</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1787-04">April 1787</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Bondley, James</term> 
<term>Brown, John</term>
 <term>Downes, Vachel</term>
<term>Forman, Thomas M.</term>
 <term>Harrison, Robert</term>
 <term>Ridgeaway, Samuel</term>
 <term>Sewell, Clement</term>  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland, Queen Ann's County</term>
<term> Talbot County Courthouse</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Jugment for Petitioner</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nan</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Roberts, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Roberts, Zachariah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wright, Robert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-06" who="#emk">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8185.JPG"/>


<p>Negro Nan 
against
Thomas Roberts and
Zachariah Roberts</p>
<p>Memorandum, the Defendants
in this cause by Gustavus Scott their
Attorney sued out the State of Maryland's
writ of Certiorari, the tenor whereof
ensues in the following words, to wit:
The State of Maryland, To the Justices of Queen Anns County Court Greeting
whereas Black Nan hath prefered a Petition to you our said Justices hum-
bly shewing that she the said Nan is unjustly and unlawfully detained
as a Slave by Thomas and Zachariah Roberts of Queen Ann's County 
Planters and praying that a Subpeona might issue to compel the attendance
of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts to answer unto her the Petitioner 
of and upon the premises and that the Petitioner might be discharged
from Servitude &amp; which said Petition is still depending before you in
our said Court as it is said, and we being desirous for certain Reasons
that the said Record should by you be certified to us: Do command you
that you send under your seals the Record of the Petition aforesaid and
all the Proceedings thereon with all things touching the same into our General
Court of the Eastern Shore of this State to be held at Talbot County Court House 
the Second Tuesday of September next plainly and distinctly and in as
full and ample as it now remains before you together with this writ, so
that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what shall appear
to us of right ought to be done. Witness Robert Harrison Esq. 
Chief Judge of our said Court this twentieth day of April Anno Domini 1784.
Issued the 15th day of May 1784. James Earle Clk. </p>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8186.JPG"/>
<p>At which said day, to wit, the said second Tuesday of September Anno Domini, One Thou-
sand seven hundred and eighty four being the day of the return of the aforegoing writ 
the Justices and Clerk of Queen Ann's County in compliance with the writ aforesaid made
return thereof to the Court here with the following Record annexed, to wit: Maryland, to
wit. At a County Court held for Queen Ann's County at Chester Mill in the said
County the fourth Tuesday in March being the twenty third day of the same month and
in the year seventeen hundred and eighty four, by the Comissioners and officers
Authorized and impowered to hold the same Court, of whom were present.–
</p>
<p>Mr. John Brown</p>
<p>Mr. Clement Sewell</p>
<p>Mr. Vachel Downes</p>
<p>Mr. Thomas </p>
<p>Mr.. Forman</p>
<p>Saml Ridgaway Esq., <unclear>Shriff</unclear></p>
<p>Downes Clk.</p>
<p>Black Nan prefered the following Petition, to wit:
To the worshipful the Justices of Queen Ann's County Court.–
The Petition of black Nan humbly sheweth, that she the said Nan is
unjustly and unlawfully detained as a slave by Thomas and Zachariah
Roberts of Queen Ann's County Planters your Petitioner therefore prays that a
Subpena may issue forth with to compel the attendance of the said Thomas and
Zachariah Roberts to answer unto your Petitioner of and upon the Premises
and that your Petitioner may be discharged from servitude, and as in duty bound &amp;.–</p>

<p> Rob. Wright Atty for Petitioner–Nan, Petitioner</p>

<p>On reading the above Petition–ordered by the Court that the same be granted
and that Subpena issues forth with to compel the attendance of the said Thomas
and Zachariah Roberts, according to the prayer of the same Petitioner, which
was accordingly issued and the Sheriff of Queen Ann's County make return there-
on in the following words, to wit, Summoned Sam. Ridgeway Sheriff–whereupon
the same Thomas and Zachariah Roberts appeared in open Court and–
Recognized in Forty pounds current money each conditioned for the appearance
of the said black Nann on the said third monday in May next to prosecute 
her said Petition for Freedom, and also for their appearance at the same 
</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_8187.JPG"/>

<p> time to Defend.–The Court adjourns till the third Monday in May next.–
Monday 17 May 1784. The Court met according to adjournment. </p>

<p>Present
Mr. John Brown
Mr. James Bondley
Mr. Clement Sewell
Mr. Vachel Downes
</p>

<p> Thomas and Zachariah Roberts appears with Black Nan in open Court, 
according to the Tenor of their Recognizance, and was by the Court here Ordered
to be discharged therefrom, and at the same time the same Thomas and 
Zachariah Roberts Recognized in the sum of Forty pounds current money
each, conditioned for the appearance of black Nan, at the next General Court
to be held for the Eastern Shore in the State of Maryland at Talbot County 
Court House, on the second Tuesday in September next to prosecute her Petition
for Freedom; and also for their appearance at the same time and place to
defend.–The Court received a Certiorari to remove the Petition of black Nan
for Freedom and the Record of the Proceedings thereon, and ordered that the 
same be transmitted under seal, to the next General Court to be held for the 
Eastern Shore in the State of Maryland.–In Testimony that the foregoing
is a true copy taken from the Records of Queen Ann's County afd,
I have here to set my hand and affixed the public seal of the County 
afd, this 2d day of September Anno Domini 1784. 
Downes Clk.</p>

<p> And now here at this day, to wit, the said second Tuesday of September Anno Domini
one thousand seven hundred and eighty four, comes into the General Court
here as well the said Negro Nan by her attorney afd, as the aforesaid
Thomas and Zachariah Roberts by their attorney aforesaid: Thereupon further process
of and upon the Promises aforesaid between the Parties aforesaid, by consent of 
the said Parties and by order of the Court here thereon was continued until</p>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_8188.JPG"/>

<p> the second Tuesday of April then next following.– At which said second Tuesday of April
Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred and eighty four came the parties aforesaid by 
their attorneys aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises aforesaid,
between the parties afd, by consent of the said Parties and their attorneys aforesaid, and 
by order of the Court here thereon was further continued until the second Tuesday
of September then next following.–At which said second Tuesday of Septem
ber Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred and eighty five, came again the 
Parties aforesaid, by their Attornies aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon 
the premises aforesaid, between the Parties aforesaid by consent of the said Parties and
their Attorneys aforesaid and by order of the Court here thereon was continued
until the second Tuesday of April next following.–</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of April Anno Domini, one thou-
sand seven hundred and eighty six, came again the Parties aforesaid by their
Attorneys aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises aforesaid
between the Parties aforesaid, by consent of the said Parties and their attorneys afd
and by order of the Court here thereon was further continued until the second Tues
day of September next following.
</p>

<p>
At which said second Tuesday of September Anno Domini, 
One thousand seven hundred and eighty six, came again the Parties afd
by their Attorneys aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the Premises
aforesaid, between the Parties aforesaid by consent of the said Parties and their 
Attorneys aforesaid, and by order of the Court here thereon was further Con
tinued under notice of Trial until the second Tuesday of April next 
following.– And now here at this day, to wit, the said second
Tuesday of April Anno Domini One thousand seven hundred and eighty
seven, cameth <add> as well</add>the said Negro nan by her Attorney aforesaid as the said
Thomas and Zachariah Roberts by their Attorney aforesaid: Whereupon all
and singular the Premises afd and the allegations and Evidences as well on the
part and behalf of the said Negro Nan; as also on the part and behalf 
of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts being by the Court here seen
heard and fully understood and mature deliberation
thereupon had:
</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_8189.JPG"/>
<p>It is considered by the Court here that the Petitioner is entitled to her Free
dom and that thereof she be free liberated and discharged from the the Custody
and Possession of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts her Masters.–
James Earle Clk.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
