<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0023.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title><!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Croxton Monday v. Henry T. Garnett. Judgment Record) --></title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<!-- add your name; e.g. - <name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name> -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project"><!-- file name - same as xml:id above --></idno>
<idno type="case"><!-- caseid number, check Case Spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.caseid.0323 --></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="<!-- yyyy-mm-dd -->"><!-- June 25, 1810 --></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="yyyy-mm"><!-- Month Year --></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term/><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term/><!-- Organize by largest place entity first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term/><!-- What was the outcome of the case? e.g. Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName><!-- Name of the Court listed on Case Spreadsheet - e.g. Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore --></orgName>
<placeName><!-- Location of the Court listed on Case Spreadsheet - e.g. Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="yyyy-mm-dd" who="#ini">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8149.jpg"/>

<p>Negro Hannah against James Selby</p>

<p>Be it remembered that on the eleventh day of september
in the year of lord one thousand seven hundred and 
ninety seven, the Chief Justice and Associate Justices of
Worcester County Court in pursuance of the Act of
Assembly in such case made and proved be, transmitted to the General Court a Record 
of the <del>pl</del>Proceedings of a plea which was lately defending before there in the said 
County Court between Negro Hannah, Plaintiff and James Selby, Defendent, and 
wherein the said County Court gave Judgement for the said James Selby against the
said Negro Hannah, and from which said Judgment the said Negro Hannah prayed 
an Appeal unto our Genreal Court; The tenor of which said Record and Proceedings
is in form following toueit. - In the Records and Proceedings of Worcester County
Court, among other matters and things it is contained as follows, toueit. - Worcester County
touet; As a court of the State of Maryland held at Snow Hill Town in and for the
County second Monday of August, touet the 24th day of the same month
in the year of our Lord one thousands seven hundred and ninety seven -</p>
<p>Were Present</p>
<p>The Honble John Done Esqr. Chief Justice William Morris &amp; William Purnell Esqrs. Associate Justices</p>
<p>Levin Pollitt Esqr. Shff. John C. Handy Clk</p>
<p>Negro Hannah vs James Selby</p>
<p>The following petition being prefered to the Court of June
Term 1795 by Negro Hannah, the same was read in 
Open Court in these words following, touet. - To the
Honble Court of Worcester County now Judicially setting 
The Petitioner of Negro Hannah, humbly shews that your petitioner is held in the
bond of Slavery by a certain James Selby of Worcester County contary to law -
She Therefore humbly supplicates your Honours to take her case with consideration,
and grant her such relief as the Law directs, and she will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Whereupon by order of Court Commanded was given to the Sheriff of Worcester County
that he should summon the said James Selby if he should be found in his
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8150.jpg"/>
Bailiwick that all Execceses sat apart he be and appear before the Justices of
the County Court of Worcester, at a Court by there to be held at Snow Hill
Town in and for the County afd the fourth Monday in November Anno Domini
one thousand seven hundered and ninety five, to answer the Petition of Negro Hannah
presented against him for freedom; and the same day is given to the afd Hannah
here and soforth..- At which said fourth Monday of November came the afd
 Negro Hannah by William Whittington Gentn her Atty: and the Sheriff, toueit,
Levin Pollitt Gentn who now here returned that he had summoned the afd James
Selby to be and appear before the Justices afd, at the time and place aforsaid,
as by the foregoing Wit of Summons he was commanded - Thereupon the said
James Selby puts in his place William Polk Gentn his Atty against the afd
Negro Hannah of the plea aforesaid, Whom which, at the request of the Parties afd
by their Atty afd day is to them now here given untill the next Court, to be held
at Snow Hill Town in and for the County afd, the second Monday in June then
next following in the same State as at present saving to the parties afd here &amp;
soforth - At which said fourth Monday of November last mentioned came
again the parties afd by their Attornies afd, upon which at the request of the parties
afd by their Atty's afd further day is to them now here given untill the
next Court by them to be held at Snow Hill Town in and for the County afd
the Second Monday of February then next following in the same State as at
present saving to the parties afd here and soforth.- At which said second
Monday of February came agin the parties afd by their Attornies aforesaid
upon which at the request of the parties afd by their Attornies afd further day
in to them now here given untill the next Court to be held at Snow Hill
Town in and for the County afd the seconds Monday of August then next following
in the same State as at present saving to the parties afd here and soforth-
At which said seconf Monday of August came again the parties afd by their
Attornies aforsaid, and the said James Selby by his Attorney afd, came and says
that the said Negro Hannah is ot held in the bonds of Slavery contrary to
 Law, in manner and form as is alledged by the said Petition and of this he
puts himself upon Country, and the said Negro Hannah in like manner
and soforth - Whereupon command was given to the Sheriff of Worcester
afd now judicially setting twelve good free and lawful men of the County
<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_8151.jpg"/>
afd by whom the trutg of the premises may be better known, and who are no way related
to the parties afd to recongnize upon their Oaths of and upon the premises afd because 
aswell the said Negro Hannah as the said James Selby have put themselves upon
that Jury and the Jurors of that same Jury whereof within is made uncertain by theann
Peter Corben, Hezakiah Jonson, John Whittington, George Spencer, Rowland Beanans
Edward Stoneuson, and Hillary Petts exactly came, who to the truth of the within contained
being elected, heed and sworn on their Oarh say that Negro Hannah is not held
in the bond of Slavery Contrary to Law in manner and form as the said Negro Hannah
in her Petition hath soforth, as the said James Selby by pleading hath
alledged.- Therefore by the Court now here it is considered that the afd Negro
Hannah is not entitled to her Freedom, and therefore accordingly dismiss the Petition
and adjudge that the said Petition be returned to her Master - At which said
Second Monday of August, at the Trial of the Issue afd, between the Parties afd
the said Negro Hannah by her Atty afd produced here in Court the following
Bill of Exception and prayed that the same might be filed of Record, which
said Bill of Exception is to this record annexed  and is as followeth toueit.-</p>
<p>Negro Hannah vs James Selby</p>
<p>Petition for freedom &amp;c in Worcester County at August Term 1797</p>
<p>The Petitioner by her Council moves the Court to direct the Jury
that if they find that Negro Hannah the petitioner lived in the
State of Virginia</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
