<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0021.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Juan Domingo Lopez v. Francis Phillips. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Mbaukwu, Somi L." xml:id="slm">Somi L. Mbaukwu</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name> 
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0021.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0675</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1770-04-10">April 10, 1770</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>Provincial Court (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S551-84</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1770-04">April 1770</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.006970">Antonio, Manuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006494">Bordley, J. B. (John Beale), 1727-1804</term>
<term xml:id="per.006977">Brown, Hendrick</term>  
<term xml:id="per.006958">Brown, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.006972">Francisco</term>
<term xml:id="per.006311">Ghiselin, Reverdy</term>
<term xml:id="per.006976">Graham, Alexander</term>  
<term xml:id="per.006492">Hepburne, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006974">Joseph</term>  
<term xml:id="per.007125">Lawson, A.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006969">Long, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.006971">Ogay, Jacob</term>
<term xml:id="per.006963">Price, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006962">Russell, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006961">Russell, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.006964">Scanoon, Andrew</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006959">Simms, Richard</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006975">Troy, Antonio</term>
<term xml:id="per.006960">Whitwick, Mary</term>   
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Curaçao</term>
<term>Hispaniola</term>
<term>Jamaica</term>
<term>West Indies</term>
<term>Baltimore County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term> 
<term>Kingston (Jamaica)</term>   
<term>Saint Jago de la Vega (Jamaica)</term>  
<term>Santo Domingo (Santo Domingo)</term> 
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Dismissed</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006956">
<persName>Lopez, Juan Domingo</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006957"> 
<persName>Phillips, Francis</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001514">
<persName>Chase, Samuel</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.004813">
<persName>Rumsey, Benjamin</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. Provincial Court</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>    
<change when="2023-07-18" who="#kln">Reviewed, edited.</change>         
<change when="2023-06-07" who="#sm">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_7975.jpg"/>

<p>Juan Domingo Lopez<lb/> 
against<lb/> 
Francis Phillips</p>

<p>Baltimore County, Sst, Juan Domingo Lopez
exhibits to the Court here the following Petition, viz.</p>

<p>To the <sic>Worshipfull</sic> the Justices of 
Baltimore County Court.</p>

<p>The Humble Petition of Juan Domingo Lopez (late of the City of Saint 
Domingo in the Island of Hispaniola commonly called Saint Domingo) Shoemaker but now of Baltimore County</p>

<p>Sheweth.</p>

<p>That your Petitioner is a native born of the Island of Hispaniola in the 
West Indies and a Subject of the King of Spain, that your petitioner there enjoyed his
natural right of being a freeman which he <sic>humble</sic> apprehends cannot be <sic>forfieted</sic> or 
taken from him without his own consent.</p>

<p>That your Petitioner embarked as an Adventurer with several others
some time in the Year one thousand seven hundred and sixty one during the late 
War on board a Privateer Sloop called the Polena from the Island of Curacoa and 
during the <sic>cruize</sic> was taken by an English Privateer whereof a certain Henry Brown 
was Master and carried as a prisoner of War into the Island of Jamaica belonging 
to his <sic>Britannick</sic> Majesty and there confined as such in prison.</p>

<p>That your petitioner hath been informed that the said Sloop Polena 
was condemned by a Decree of the Court of Vice Admiralty of Jamaica as a prize
on a Libel exhibited against her on or about the fourteenth day of May one thousand 
seven hundred and sixty four.</p>

<p>That your Petitioner has been informed that he with the other Negroes 
taken as Prisoners as aforesaid was by the said Court of Vice Admiralty condemned 
and to be sold for the benefit of the Captors.</p>

<p>That your petitioner ignorant of such Condemnation only by information
since his Arrival into this province, no party to the said Libel, deprived of the  
opportunity of Defence and condemned unheard humbly apprehends himself not 
bound or deprived of his Liberty thereby.</p>

<p>Your Petitioner further sheweth to your Worships that a certain 
Richard Simms Master of a Vessel brought your petitioner into this Province and 
Sold him as a Slave without his consent to a Company called by the name of the 
Principio Company in Baltimore County and who as your petitioner is informed

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_7976.jpg"/>
        
consists of a certain Mary Whitwick, William Russell, Thomas Russell and John 
Price. Your Petitioner further sheweth that he is detained by a certain Francis 
Phillips Manager for said Company as the Slave and property of the said Company 
who can have no other Title or claim than herein before set forth by your Petitioner.</p>

<p>That your said Petitioner hath been informed that the said Persons who
compose the said Company are not Inhabitants of this province he therefore humbly 
prays Your Worships to take his case into your most serious Consideration, grant him 
that Liberty which is his Natural Right and save him from the Slavery which is odious 
to the British Constitution, and from whose Laws your Petitioner hopes and expects
Relief. Your Petitioner further prays that the usual process may Issue against the 
said Francis Phillips to compel his appearance to answer to the facts about alledged 
by your petitioner</p>

<p>And your Petitioner as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c</p>

<p>Juan Domingo Lopez.</p>

<p>Witness for the Petitioner Andrew Scanoon.</p>

<p>Whereupon it is commanded the Sheriff of Baltimore County that he 
Summon the said Francis Phillips to appear immediately before the Justices of Baltimore 
County at the Court house in the same County to answer of and concerning the said 
complaint of the said Juan Domingo Lopez, who return that he has summoned the 
said Francis agreeable to the exigence of the same Summons. And thereupon 
here comes the said Francis by Benjamin Rumsey his Attorney, and the said 
Complainant produces to the Court here the Right Honourable the Lord Proprietary 
that now is his Writ of Certiorari in these words, to wit.</p>

<p>Fredrick Absolute Lord and Proprietary of the Provinces of Maryland and 
Avalon Lord Baron of Baltimore and so forth To the Justices and Clerk of Baltimore 
County greeting. We being willing for certain causes to be certified of the Record and 
proceedings of a certain Petition before you depending between Juan Domingo 
Lopez complainant and Francis Phillips Defendant. We command you that the 
Record and proceedings of the petition aforesaid with all things thereunto relating as 
far as before you it remains whatsoever names the parties in the same are distinguished 
to our Justices of your provincial court to be held at Annapolis the third Tuesday 
of May next under your hands and seals you send together with this writ that our 
said Justice may further do therein that which of Right they see ought to be done 
Witness John Hepburne Esquire one of the Justice of our provincial court the 29th 
day of October in the 18th year of our Dominion &amp;ca <sic>Annoq</sic> Dom 1768</p>

<p>Issued 2d day of November 1768. Reverdy Ghiselin, Clk.</p>

<p>Allowed  J. B. Bordley.</p>

<p>Which being read and heard by the court here It is Ordered that the Petition with 
all things relating thereto be sent before the Honourable the Justices of the provincial
court to be held at Annapolis on the third Tuesday of May next.</p>

<p>Test J. B. Bordley, Clk.</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_7977.jpg"/>

<p>In Testimony whereof the Seal of the County aforesaid is affixed hereto this 
twentieth day of April Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred and 
sixty nine by</p>

<p>A. Lawson, Clk, Balt. Coty Court </p>

<p>(Seal of Baltimore Coty Court)</p>

<p>And now here at this day to wit the third tuesday of May being the sixteenth day of 
the same month Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty nine comes into his 
Lordships Provincial Court here as well the said Juan Domingo Lopez by Samuel 
Chase his Attorney as the said Francis Phillips by Benjamin Rumsey his Attorney 
aforesaid Thereupon the said cause is continued untill next Court</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit the seventeenth day of October Anno Domini 
seventeen hundred and sixty nine comes again as well the said Juan Domingo Lopez 
by his attorney aforesaid as the said Francis Phillips by his attorney aforesaid. 
Thereupon the said cause is further continued untill next Court</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit the tenth day of April Anno Domini seventeen
hundred and seventy comes again as well the said Juan Domingo Lopez by his 
attorney aforesaid as the said Francis Phillips by his attorney aforesaid. Whereupon 
all and singular the premisses aforesaid and Allegations and Evidence as well on
the part and behalf of the said Juan Domingo Lopez as the said Francis Phillips 
being by the Court here seen heard fully understood and mature deliberation thereupon 
had</p>

<p>It is considered by the Justices here that the said Petition be dismissed 
And thereupon the said Juan Domingo Lopez by Samuel Chase his attorney 
aforesaid prays an Appeal from the Judgment of the Court so as aforesaid rendered 
against him to his Lordships High Court of Appeals and the same is granted</p>

<p>It is therefore ordered that the Record and proceeding in the premises 
aforesaid be transmitted to the High Court of Appeals accordingly</p>

<p>Test Reverdy Ghiselin, Clk Provl Court </p>

<p>Memorandum. Upon hearing the Complaint between the parties aforesaid the 
following Record was produced to the Court and read in Evidence to wit</p>

<p>(A).</p>

<p>Advoc Genl exretn 
Brown &amp; al.<lb/> 
against<lb/>
Armed Sloop Polena</p>

<p>At a high Court of Vice Admiralty held
at the Town of Saint Jago Dela Vega in the Island 
aforesaid on Thursday the fourteenth day of May in
the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred 
and sixty one before the Honourable Edward Long 
Esquire Sole Judge of the said court. This cause this day coming on to the heard 
our Advocate <sic>Generall</sic> opened the <sic>Libell</sic> and the several Preparatory Examinations
taken in this cause were severally read upon hearing whereof and what was alledged 
by Mr Advocate General his Honour the Judge was pleased to order adjudge and 
Decree as it is hereby ordered adjudged and decreed that the said Armed Sloop 
or <sic>Vessell</sic> called the Polena her Guns Tackle Furniture Ammunition and <sic>Apparell</sic>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_7978.jpg"/>

and the <sic>Negroe</sic> Slaves named Manuel Antonio Jacob Ogay Francisco, Juan 
Domingo Antonio Toy and Joseph, and the Goods Wares Merchandizes and Effects on 
board her taken and <sic>seised</sic> be confiscated and condemned to our Sovereign Lord the 
King for the use of the Captors and that the same may be sold and the price and prices 
thereof and of every part and parcel thereof be distributed and divided among the said 
Henry Brown his Owners Officers and Mariners agreeable to their Articles and pursuant 
to the Statute and his Majesty's Declaration and Proclamation for that purpose made
and Issued</p>

<p>Alex. Graham Dep. Regr Cur. Vic. Admirl</p> 

<p>Jamaica. Sst.</p>

<p>I Alexander Graham Esquire Deputy Register and Scribe of the
Acts Causes and Businesses of the High Court of Vice Admiralty in and for the Island 
aforesaid duly admitted and Sworn dwelling in the Town of Kingston in the said 
Island do hereby certify unto all Persons to whom these presents shall come or may 
concern that the Sheet of Paper writing hereunto annexed marked (A) contains a true 
and exact copy of the Sentence made and pronounced by the Honourable Edward 
Long Esquire Sole Judge of the said Court on Thursday the fourteenth day of May last 
against a certain Armed Sloop or <sic>Vessell</sic> called the Polena (whereof one Hendrick 
Brown a Mulatto Man late was Master her Guns Tackle Furniture Ammunition and 
<sic>Apparell</sic> and the Negro Slaves named Manuel Antonio, Ogay, Francisco, Juan 
Domingo, Antonio Troy and Joseph and also the Goods Wares Merchandizes and 
effects on board her taken and seized by Henry Brown Commander of a certain 
Brigantine or Private <sic>Vessell</sic> of War called the Hawk his Officers and Marines and 
that the same hath been by me carefully examined and compared with the Original 
Sentence now of Record in the said Court</p>

<p>In Testimony of the Truth whereof I the said Alexander Graham have 
hereunto set my hand (and by order of the Honourable Edward 
Long Esqr. Sole Judge as aforesaid) Affixed the Seal of the 
said Court at Kingston aforesaid this sixteenth day of July 
in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and 
sixty one</p>

<p>(Seal of the Court of Vice Admiralty in the Island of Jamaica)</p>

<p>Alexr. Graham. Dep. Regr. Cur. Vic Admirl.<lb/>
Test Reverdy Ghiselin, Clk.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
