<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0005.007"><!-- Insert file name inside quotes. Check spreadsheet; e.g. - oscys.reu.0011.015 -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title><!-- Case Name. Document (e.g. - Edward Queen v. John Ashton. Deposition of Thomas Warfield) --></title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Mendiola, Madison" xml:id="MKM">Madison K. Mendiola</name><!-- Add your name where indicated. -->
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.reu.0005.007</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0690</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of Lewis F. Linn, John Scott, and Eloy LeCompt</title>
<date when="yyyy-mm-dd">MONTH DAY, YEAR</date><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="yyyy-mm">MONTH YEAR</date></term><!-- Fill in date in both places. -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Charlotte</term> <!-- Paul Jones's sister -->
<term>Linn, Lewis F.</term>
<term>LeCompt, Eloy</term>
<term>LeCompt, John H.</term>
<term>LeCompt, S.</term>
<term>Scott, john</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Illinois, Prairie Du Rocher</term>
<term>Illinois, Cahokia</term>
<term>Illinois, Kaskaskia</term>
<!-- Places mentioned in the document, organized by largest place first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term><!-- Was the outcome of the case stated in this document? What was it? e.g. - Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jones, Paul</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Jones, George W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName><!-- Last Name, First Name --></persName><!-- If needed -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Wisconsin Territory. District Court (Grant County)</orgName>
<placeName>Lancaster (Wi.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-17" who="MKM">Transcribed, encoded.</change><!-- Fill in the date and your initials as defined above. -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/><!-- Add a new page break for every new page and change the page number. -->

<p>Should purchase him, and that said Paul 
went willingly with the service of said defendent
Jones</p>
<p>And for answer to the Eight interrogatory he 
answers &amp; says that he cannot now remember
anything further in relation to said matter except
as above stated and further he saith not..
Lewis F Linn</p>
<p>When John Scott who first faint duly sworn answers 
to said interrogatories as follows- to the first he 
answers &amp; says that he knows both plaintiff &amp;
Defendant that he has known the defendant from 
the time he was a small Boy and that he has
known Paul about thirty years that he knew him 
first as a slave in the family of John Le Compte
the father of John H Le Compte &amp; Eloy Le Compte
and the Husband of S. Le Compte the vendor
in the bill of sale to George W. Jones. that they 
then resided in Prairie du Rocher Illinois.</p>
<p>And for answer to the second interrogatory he 
says that he is not acquainted with the handwriting
of S Le Compte &amp; John H Le Compte. but that the 
Hand write of Eloy Le Compet he is well acquainted 
with having frequently seen him write and 
that the signature to the bill of sale is in his 
own proper handwriting. </p>
<p>And for answer to the third interogatory he answer
and says that he was not present when the bill
of sale was executed nor did he sign the same 
as a subsidiary witness</p>

<pb xml:id="p002"/>
<p>and for answer to the fourth interrogatory he says 
that the signature of Lewis F Linn to the 
bill of sale is in the proper hand write of said 
Lewis F Linn that he has often seen him write</p>

<p>And for answer to the fifth interrogatory he 
says that he is acquainted with the coloured man
named Paul transfered in the said Bill of 
Sale to George W Jones and have known <add>him</add> about 
thirty years. that he knows the woman who was 
called his mother who lived with John H. Le Compte
<add>the elder</add> Prairie du Rocher in Illinois as his slave.
from AD 1805-6. till he left the country some 
several years ago.</p>

<p>And for answer to the sixth interrogatory he 
answers &amp; says that his of own knowledge he does
not known when Paul the Plft was born
but believes he was from Prairie du Rocher
Illinois for there he first saw him a small
Boy at the house of John <add>H</add> Le Compte the father 
of two of the vendor to Jones. the reputed mother
of Paul being in the family at that time as 
a slave.</p>

<p>And for answer to the seventh interrogatory 
he answers and says that he knows the said Plaintiff
Paul went into the service of Jones willingly
and that Jones purchased him with his 
approbation and consent.</p>

<p>And for answer to the eighth interrogatory 
he answers and says that he has no recollection
of anything that would tend further to illucidate
the subject &amp; further he saith not</p>

<p>John Scott</p>

<pb xml:id="p003"/>
<p>And the follow interrogatories were propounded
to Eloy Le Compte</p>

<p>Interrogatory 1<hi>st</hi> <lb/>
Do you know the parties plaintiff and defendant in the title of these interrogatories named
as either of them and which of them and how long 
have you known them respectively.</p>

<p>2<hi>nd</hi> interrogatory. Are you or either of you acquainted
with a coloured man called Paul who was sold 
as a slave by Eloy le Compte John H lecompte
and S Le Compte to the defendent George W Jones
if so state all you know about the said sale
and at what time it took place</p>

<p>3 <unclear></unclear> Do you or either of you know who 
was the mother of the said coloured man Paul
when did she <unclear>reside</unclear> by what name called
whether she was not held as a slave in the 
state of Illinois if so by what <unclear>tenure</unclear> or right.</p>

<p>4<hi>th</hi> witns Do you or either of you know where and 
when the before named Paul was born if so 
please state </p>

<p>5<hi>th</hi> interrogatory Do you or either of you know whether 
the said Paul was held to service for life as 
a slave in Illinois under the Laws &amp; wages 
in free in the late North Western Territory now 
State of Illinois in favour of the ancient french
and Canadians inhabitants of the vilages 
of Kaskaskia and Prairie du Rocher Cahokia
and other vilages in the former north western territory 
now state of Illinois aforesaid if so please
state all you know in relation to it as 
fully as if particularly interrogated there to </p>

<pb xml:id="p004"/>
<p>6<hi>th</hi> Do you or either of you know whether
the mother of the said coloured man Paul 
was or was not on or before the 13<hi>th</hi> July AD 1787
held and owned as a slave found to service
to one of the Candadian or French inhabitants 
mentioned in th fifth interrogary if so please
state what you know in relation to it.</p>

<p>7<hi>th</hi> Do you or either of you know whether the 
said Paul was a slave in the state of Illinois 
according to any Law or wage then in free
if so state by <unclear>when</unclear> held and by what 
right &amp; tenure</p>

<p>8<hi>th</hi> are you <s>acquainted</s> or either of you 
interested directly or indirectly in the event
and termination of this suit. </p>

<p>9<hi>th</hi> Do you know of any thing further that 
may told to the benefit and advantage of the 
defendant in the cause or the illucidation of 
subject if so please state fully &amp; particularly.</p>

<p>When Eloy Lecompte being first duly 
sworn answer the said interrogatories as follows
to the first he answers &amp; says that he 
is acquainted with both Pett and defendant in 
the above named suit that he has known defendant
about fifteen years. that he has known the plaintiff
Paul since he can remember anything that is to say 
about twenty five or thirty years.</p>

<p>To the 2<hi>nd</hi> interrogatory he answers and says that 
the 18<hi>th</hi> march 1829. his mother S. LeCompt
John H Lecompte &amp; himself sold 
said Boy Paul to George W Jones and executed 
to him a bill of sale for him without general 
warranty. that Paul was sold together with his 
sister. Charlotte for the sum of five hundred 
dollars</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
