<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.reu.0002.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Edward Gantt vs. Thomas Baldwin. Deposition of James Gilmore</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Minton, Ryan A." xml:id="ram">Ryan A. Minton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.reu.0002.005"></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0687"></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of James Gilmore</title>
<date when="1836-11-18">November 18, 1836</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1836-11"></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term>Adams, James</term>
<term>Allen, Beverly</term>
<term>Baird, John</term>
<term>Blackhart, James</term>
<term>Brotherson, James</term>
<term>Burns</term>
<term>D., Brotherson</term>
<term>Davis, H.N.</term>
<term>Gamble, H.R.</term>
<term>Gilmore, James</term>
<term>Hough, Daniel</term>
<term>Hough, David</term>
<term>Jess</term>
<term>Lewis, Anderson</term>
<term>Ruland, John</term>
<term>Spalding, Dunham</term>
<term>Waters</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Missouri</term>
<term>Saint Louis County</term>
<term>Saint Louis</term>
<term>Louisville</term>
<term>Pittsburgh</term>
<term>Quincy</term>
<term>Jeffersonville</term>
<term>Bard's Landing</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Edward Gantt</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Thomas Baldwin</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beverly Allen</persName>
<persName>H.R. Gamble</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>J. Spalding</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Missouri. Circuit Court (Saint Louis)</orgName>
<placeName>Saint Louis (Mo.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2024-06-11" who="#ini">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001"/>

<p>Edward Gant
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thomas Baldwin</p>
<p>St. Louis Circuit Cout.</p>
<p>Take notice that on the 18th day of November in the year of our Lord one thousand eight undred and thirty-six, between the hours of eight in the forenoon and five in the afternoon, of that day at the office of David Hough in the City of Saint Louis</p>
<p>depositions will be taken by the undersigned, to be read on the trial of the above entitled case, on behalf of the defendant; and that the taking of said depositions, if not completed on that day, will be continued from day to day at the same place and between the same hours, until completed.
<lb/>To the above named plaintiff</p>
<p>15 November 1836
<lb/>Thomas Baldwin</p>

<pb xml:id="p002"/>

<p>Gantt
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>Baldwin
<lb/>notice</p>
<p>The plantiff will serve this today on the attorney of record of plantiff
<lb/>J. Spalding
<lb/>15 November</p>
<p>Served this notice by delivering a true copy thereof to H.R. Gamble &amp; Beverly Allen attornies of record of the within named plantiff on the 15th day of November 1836 in the county of St. Louis Edward Gantt the within named plantiff not found in my county. 
<lb/>James Brotherson Sheriff
<lb/>By <unclear></unclear> Brotherson D. Sheriff
<lb/>Service $1.00</p>

<pb xml:id="p003"/>

<p>State of Missouri
<lb/>County of Saint Louis</p>
<p>Deposition of a witness produced sworn and examined on this eighteenth day of November eighteen hundred and thirty six between the hours of eight in the forenoon and five in the afternoon of that day before me although a justice of the peace within and for the county aforsaid at my office in the city of Saint Louis in a certain cause now pending in the Saint Louis Circuit Court between Edward Gantt plaintiff and Thomas Baldwin defendant, on behalf of the defendant.</p>
<p>James Gilmore being produced sworn and examined deposith and said that he shows the defendant Thomas Baldwin that he master of the Steam Boat Tempist last fall the said boat then running from Pittsubrgh to Louisville and sometimes to St. Louis, the said boat was in St. Louis two or three times last fall then said boat left St. Louis on or about the 19th December 1835 for Louisville, being the last trip she made that season witness was mate on said Boat from the 8th of September 1835 to the 13th July 1836 and was on her during every trip, and was on board of her during all the time and every time she was at St. Louis. Witness knows of no black or mulatto

<pb xml:id="p004"/>

women taken from St. Louis at any time on said <add>boat</add> except on the last trip two slaves claimed by a person on board who paid their passage to the mouth of the Ohio, where they left the boat with him at Bard's Landing one a mulatto the other black. Witness does not recollect the name of the man who had the above women in charge, he was a white man and witness had no reason to believe that the said slaves belonged to the man who paid their passage as they were brought on board by him at St. Louis or at least they all <del>they all</del> came on the Boat about the same <add>time</add> and were all at that time claimed by him they came on board but a short time previous to the departion of the Boat, the steam being up witness saw them taken from the Boat at the mouth of the Ohio by the same man who brought them on board, which was the last deponent saw of them and has no knowledge that he ever saw them before they were brought on board at St. Louis no other black or yellow women were taken from St. Louis on said trip either 

<pb xml:id="p005"/>

as passenger or in any other capacity except the Chamber maid who had been on the Boat for some time having been engaged at Pittsburgh. Witness thinks there could have been no other black or mulatto women on board without his knowledge, these being but little freight on board, and witness having charge of the hold was daily in it from one end to the other and carried the key of the hatches which were generally locked and the forecastle was always locked and witness was the only one that had keys to the hatches or forecastle witness says that as mate of the boat it was his duty to see to it generally and was daily in all the store rooms and pantrys to see that everything went right, and all through the cabins, and likewise several times in the course of a day were in the deck hand room, firemans room, and steward room and also in the cookhouse that he was sometimes in the Ladys Cabin and frequently walked around it

<pb xml:id="p006"/>

witness beleives that there were some lady passengers on the Boat during the last trip from St. Louis but does not recollect how many it was quite cold, freezing weather at that time the river had been closed above St. Louis as the Boat attmpeted to ascend to Quincy but could not get up and had to return, and then left for Louisville and could not ascend the Ohio any further on account of the ice during the last trip from St. Louis to Louisville the weather was severely cold all the time the weather was so cold that persons would suffer extremely without fire two of the deck hands left the boat during that trip and assigend as a reason that it was too cold for work on the Boat. the trip above spoken of that is the last trip, is the one when it were alleged the slave was taken from St. Louis for soon after the Boat arrived at Louisville witness heard the charge was made heard is probably not more than two days after

<pb xml:id="p007"/>

he arried at Louisville witness heard that Mr. Baird had written from St. Louis enquiring if a slave had been taken on that trip when the clerk mentioned to witness that the Boat was charged with taking a slave from St. Louis it lead to some talk among the crew of the Boat, but <add>witness</add> is confident there was none on board when the boat left port it was the custom for the desk of witness to go through the rooms of the deck passengers to collect the passage money and the clerk himself went through the cabins witness says the same was done when the boat left St. Louis on the last trip last fall witness quit the boat on the 13th of July last the defendant Baldwin now resides in Louisville, and witness thinks his family resided there last fall. Baldwin is a slave owner he had a slave (a man) on board the Boat during the trip above mentioned.</p>
<p>Cross examined</p>
<p>Witness does not recollect the day of the 

<pb xml:id="p008"/>

week the Boat left St. Louis on her last trip last fall <add>though</add> Baldwin was captain of the boat which was the Tempest and had been captain of said Boat for some time previous to the trip above mentioned say for more than two months, and continued as captain <add>until</add> this last Spring probably till May Witness was mate on said Boat all the time that Baldwin was captain and they were on board together during that time. John Baird was clerk of said Boat during the last trip above mentioned, and had been clerk from the 21st, September 1835 and continued to until May or thereabout 1836 The boat made no trip to this place from the time of the last trip above mentioned until Baldwin left her does not recollect the names of any gentlemen or lady passengers on the trip called the last trip it did not belong to witness to find out thier names the last time witness saw Baird the clerk was on the 4th and 5th of November instant

<pb xml:id="p009"/>

at Jeffersonville <unclear>IN</unclear> at which time he was captain of steam Boat Pavillion but witness does not know where he is now the last time witness saw Captain Baldwin was on the Mississippi river below St. Louis some time this present month, but does not recollect the day does not know where he is now. Witness says he has has some but not much conversation with Captain Baldwin on the subject matter of this suit that Baldwin told him he had been sued.</p>
<p>The above conversation was some time this month in Louisville. Witness came this evening to testify at the request of Mr. Spalding thereby he arrived in this city last sunday morning and sometime after he arrived made himself known to Mr. Spalding. During the trip called the last trip the crew conisted of James Adams &amp; James Blackhart both white men and Jess a slave from Kentucky as firemen and being all 

<pb xml:id="p010"/>

the firemen at that time one having left at St. Louis on account of the cold. The deck hands were Burns &amp; Waters, both white men, does not recollect their christian names, being the only <unclear>men</unclear> that went as far as Louisville too having previously <add>to her arrival at St. Louis</add> left on account of the cold. Witness had known Jess for some time Anderson Lewis a yellow man was assistant steward on said last trip and had one assistant names not recollected there was one chamberaid does not know where the assistant steward now is he was a white man from Louisville. These might <add>have</add> some Boats left on the same day the Tempest did on her last trip so called after before or after deponenet thinks these were from about that time does not recollect the names of any boats bound for Louisville lying at St. Louis when the Tempest left on which she lay here just before she left does not recollect how many days the Tempest was soing to Louisille passed the Lady Jackson on the 

<pb xml:id="p011"/>

trip said to be bound to Louisville from St. Louis saw another Boat on the trip but whether she passed the Tempest or the Tempest passed her does not recollect nor does he recollect her name but were said to <add>be</add> from St. Louis and bound to Louisville. The Tempest during the last trip so called had a slow passage on account of the old and ice does not recollect the day of the month or week the Boat arrived in Louisville. Witness came out to Kaskaskia for the purpose of <unclear>intering</unclear> land and came from Kaskaskia to St. Louis in Steam Boat Ontario. Witness did not come to St. Louis at the request of Capt. Baldwin, but came to purhcase some land of Dunham Spalding. This was an assistant clerk on the Tempest sometime previous but thinks not on the last trip so called thinks his name was William Morgan does not know a man by the name of William Massie but has heard of his 

<pb xml:id="p012"/>

name.</p>
<p>Re-examined by deft. Anderson Lewis the steward came on board the Tempest at Pittsburgh came to St. Louis &amp; went to Louisville and has never been here on the Tempest so far as witness knows, since the last trip so called but has been twice here on other Boats. Witness does not recollect the names of the cooks thinks the first cook was a black man came from Louisville the second cook was a yellow man also came from Louisville an those were all the cooks there were so far as witness recollects. James Gilmore</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this eighteenth day of November eighteen hundred and thirty five.
<lb/>D. Hough J.J.</p>
<p>State of Missouri
<lb/>County of Saint Louis</p>
<p>Daniel Hough a justice of the peace within and for 

<pb xml:id="p013"/>

County aforsaid do certify that the foregoing deponenet James Gilmore was by me sworn to testify the whole truth of his knowledge touching the matter in controversy aforsaid, that he was examined and his examination reduced to writing subscribed sworn to said deponent in my presence on the day, between the hours, and at the place in that bahalf first aforesaid.
<lb/>Daniel Hough J.J.</p>
<p>Justice fee $2.00
<lb/>paid by H.N. Davis
<lb/>for defendant</p>

<pb xml:id="p014"/>

<p>Gantt
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>Baldwin</p>
<p>Deposition</p>
<p>opened &amp; filed 6th December 1837
<lb/>John Ruland Clerk</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
