<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0250.012">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Davis v. Hezekiah Wood. Transcript from Circuit Court</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Green, Autumn" xml:id="ag">Autumn Green</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0250.012</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0251</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0249</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Transcript from Circuit Court</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 267</collection>
<idno>Box 33, Folder 691</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Transcript</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1816-02">February 1816</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001868">Boothe, Jeremiah</term> 
<term xml:id="per.000006">Boyd, Washington</term>
<term xml:id="per.001555">Brent, Daniel Carroll, 1759-1815</term>
<term xml:id="per.000003">Brent, William, 1774-1848</term>
<term xml:id="per.000194">Caldwell, Elias Boudinot, 1776-1825</term>
<term xml:id="per.001869">Coombe, Griffith</term>
<term xml:id="per.000004">Cranch, William, 1769-1855</term>
<term xml:id="per.001608">Davis, Airy</term>
<term xml:id="per.000160">Davis, Susan</term>
<term xml:id="per.001543">Duckett, Allen B., 1775-1809</term>
<term xml:id="per.000063">Fitzhugh, Nicholas</term>
<term xml:id="per.000011">Hiort, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.000093">Hollingshead, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001870">Joncherez, Alexander L.</term>
<term xml:id="per.000435">Jones, Walter, 1776-1861</term>
<term xml:id="per.000001">Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843</term>
<term xml:id="per.001871">King, Charles</term>
<term xml:id="per.001872">Lindsay, Adam</term>
<term xml:id="per.001592">Moore, George</term>
<term xml:id="per.001580">Newton, Ignatius</term>
<term xml:id="per.001873">Queen, Nicholas L.</term>
<term xml:id="per.000168">Swann, Caleb</term>
<term xml:id="per.001874">Thompson, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001875">Veitch, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.001876">Wharm, David</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Washington County (D.C.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001601">
<persName>Davis, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001602">
<persName>Davis, Mary Ann</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001603">
<persName>Davis, Teresa</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.001604">
<persName>Wood, Hezekiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2022-07" who="#kln">Reviewed.</change>
<change when="2022-06" who="#ag">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.001.jpg"/>
    
<p>District of Columbia towit:</p>
 
<p>At a Circuit Court of the District of Columbia, begun 
and held in and for the County of Washington, at the City of 
Washington on the fourth monday of december, being the twenty
sixth day of the same month, in the year of our Lord one 
thousand, Eight hundred and Eight, and of American 
Independence the thirty third.</p>

<p>The Honorable<lb/>
William Cranch Esquire, chief judge<lb/>
Nicholas Fitzhugh &amp;
Allen B. Duckett Esquires assistant Judges</p>

<p>Washington Boyd Esquire Marshal<lb/>
William Brent Clerk.</p>

<p>In the Record of Proceedings of the same Court, 
amongst others in the following, towit;</p> 

<p>Susan Davis &amp; her 
Daughter, Ary<lb/>
against<lb/>
Caleb Swan</p> 

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit 
on the fourth day of September in the 
year of our lord one thousand Eight 
hundred and seven, the said Susan and 
Ary by Henry Hiort their attorney 
filed in Court here, the following Petition 
towit, "To the Honble the Judges of the Circuit Court of the 
County of Washington in the District of Columbia, The humble 
Petn of Susan Davis &amp; her daughter Ary, humbly sheweth,
That your Petitioners are detained in slavery by Caleb Swann 
&amp; as they were born free, they pray that process may be awarded 
     
<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.002.jpg"/>
     
to compell the appearance of the said Caleb Swann to 
answer their complaint.</p>

<p>H. Hiort for Complt.<lb/>
4th Septr. 1807.</p>

<p>Whereupon a writ of the United States, of Subpoena, issued to 
the marshal of the District of Columbia, in the words and of 
the tenor following, this is to say,</p> 

<p>"District of Columbia, towit:</p> 

<p>The United States of America to the Marshal of the District 
of Columbia, Greeting:</p> 

<p>You are hereby commanded to Summon Caleb Swann that 
all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before 
the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia, to be held 
in and for the County of Washington at the City of 
Washington on the fourth monday of december next then 
and there to answer the petition of negro Susan Davis and 
her daughter Ary, in the said Court exhibited against him 
for their freedom. Hereof fail not at your peril and have 
you then and there this writ. Witness William Cranch
Esqr. Chief Judge of the said Court the 31st day of 
August 1807. Issued the 4th day of September 1807.</p> 

<p>Wm Brent Clk.</p> 

<p>Hiort</p> 

<p>At which said fourth monday of december, being the 
twenty eighth day of the same month in the year of our 
lord one thousand eight hundred and seven, and the 
return day of the aforegoing writ of subpoena, come into 
the Circuit Court here, the said Susan and Ary by their 
        
 <pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.003.jpg"/>
     
said attorney; and the marshal of the District of Columbia 
aforesaid, to whom the said Subpoena, was in form aforesaid 
directed, makes return thereof to the Court here, thus endorsed,
towit;</p>

<p>"Sumd 4th Septr 1807."<lb/>
Danl C Brent, Marshal.</p>

<p>And the said Caleb Swann being called appears in court here 
by Francis S Key and Elias B. Caldwell his attornies: Whereupon 
the Court here, on motion of the said Petitioners by their said attorney, 
order the said Caleb Swan to enter into recognizance in the sum 
of eight hundred dollars current money, conditioned that the said 
Caleb Swan, do not remove the said Petitioners out of the District 
of Columbia nor obstruct them from attending this court from 
time to time, in support of their said petition; Thereupon 
the said Caleb Swann present here in court, acknowledges 
himself to owe and stand justly indebted unto the United 
States of America in the sum of Eight hundred dollars 
current money, to be levied of his body, goods and chattels; 
lands and tenements, to and for the use of the United States,
on condition that he the said Caleb Swan do not remove 
Susan Davis and her daughter Ary out of the District 
of Columbia, nor obstruct them from attending this court from 
time to time, in support of their petition for freedom, exhibited 
in the said Court against him the said Caleb Swan and 
in the mean time to feed cloath and use them well.</p> 

<p>And thereupon, on motion of the said Petitioners by their
attorney aforesaid, it is ruled by the Court here that the
 
<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.004.jpg"/>
     
said Caleb Swan answer to the petition aforesaid, of the 
said petitioners, on the plea aforesaid, or judgment by the 
Court here will be rendered against him by default, and 
the said Caleb Swan by his said attornies, defends the 
force and injury, when &amp;c. and prays leave of the Court 
here to imparle untill the first monday of June next,
to answer to the petition of the said Petitioners in the 
plea aforesaid, and he hath it; the same day is given
to the said petitioners then &amp;c. At which mentioned 
first monday of June being the sixth day of the 
same month in the year of our Lord one thousand 
eight hundred and Eighth, untill which day the said 
Caleb Swan had leave to imparle, and then to answer 
to the Petition of the said Petitioners in the plea 
aforesaid, come as well the said Petitioners by their said 
attorney; as the said Caleb Swan by his said attornies.</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid 
between the parties aforesaid by counsel of said parties, and their 
attornies aforesaid, and by order of the Court herethereon, is further 
continued untill the fourth monday of december next.</p> 
 
<p>And now here at the day towit the fourth monday of 
December, being the twenty sixth day of the same month 
in the year of our Lord one thousand, Eight hundred and eight 
come again into the Circuit Court here as well the said 
Petitioners by Henry Hiort and Walter Jones Junior, <del>by</del> their 
attornies; as the said Caleb Swann by his attornies aforesaid.</p> 

<p>And the said Caleb Swan by his said attornies come and defends the force and injury when he and says that <catchwords>the</catchwords>
     
<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.005.jpg"/>
 
the said Susan and her daughter Airy are the proper slaves 
of him the said Caleb without that that the said Susan 
&amp; Airy are free women &amp; of free condition &amp; this he is ready 
to verify, wherefore he prays judgment if the said Susan 
&amp; Airy &amp; their action aforesaid to have or maintain ought 
by any thing before by the said Caleb in pleading alleged, 
they ought not to be precluded from having said maintaining their 
action aforesaid against the said Caleb, because protesting, that 
they are not slaves, but are free born, and this they pray may 
be enquired of by the Country &amp;c and the said Caleb in 
like manner &amp;c.</p> 

<p>Therefore let a jury therefore appear before the Court here immediately 
by whom &amp;c and who neither &amp;c. to recognize &amp;c Because 
as well &amp;c. Who being called, come that is to say, James Veitch,
Charles King, Alexander L. Joncherez, Jeremiah Boothe, David Wharm, 
Griffith Coombe, John Hollingshead, Adam Lindsay, Nicholas 
L. Queen, George Moore, Ignatius Newton and John Thompson 
who being empannelled and sworn to say the truth in the 
premises, upon their oath do say, that they find for the 
Petitioners; Therefore it is considered by the court here, that the 
said Susan Davis and her daughter Ary, the petitioners 
aforesaid, recover their freedom of and against the said Caleb 
Swan, and that they be free and discharged of and from the 
service of the said Caleb Swan, and that they the said 
Susan Davis and her daughter Ary go thereof freed and 
 
<pb xml:id="p006" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.006.jpg"/>
     
discharged without day &amp;c. it is also considered by the 
court here, that the said Susan Davis and her daughter 
Ary recover against the said Caleb Swan the sum of 
thirty seven dollars Sixty two and one half cents and the 
quantity of one hundred and Eighty six pounds of tobacco 
by the Court here unto the said Susan Davis &amp; her daughter 
Ary, adjudged on their assent, for their costs and charges
by them about the <del>suit</del> prosecution of their petition aforesaid 
<gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> out and expended, and that they have thereof their 
execution, &amp;c.</p> 

<p>Memorandum. Judgment rendered in this 
cause for the petitioners, for their freedom and costs of prosecution 
on the eighteenth day of January Ano Domini one 
thousand Eight hundred and Nine.</p>

<p>Test Wm Brent Clk.</p>

<p>District of Columbia towit,</p>

<p>I William Brent Clerk of the Circuit Court of 
the District of Columbia for the County of Washington 
do hereby certify that the aforegoing is truly taken from 
the record and proceedings of this said Court</p> 

<p>In testimony whereof I hereunto subscribe 
my name and affix the seal of the said 
Court this twenty seventh day of March 
Anno Domini 1809.</p>

<p>Wm. Brent Clk</p>

<p>District of Columbia towit. I William Cranch Chief judge of the 
Circuit Court of the District of Columbia do hereby certify that the aforegoing 
attestation by William Brent clerk of the said court for the County of Washington is in due form.</p>

<p>Given under my hand this 29th day of September 1812.
at the city of Washington<lb/>
W. Cranch.</p>
         
<pb xml:id="p007" facs="oscys.case.0250.012.007.jpg"/>
     
<p>Susan Davis &amp; her daughter Ary<lb/>
against<lb/>
Caleb Swan</p>

<p>Petition for freedom and Judgment thereon for the petitioners.</p> 

<p>Transcript</p> 

<p>District of Columbia 
record</p>
     
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>