<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygeoscys.case.0001.034n RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0001.034">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ben v. Sabrett Scott. Transcript from Circuit Court</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Green, Autumn" xml:id="ag">Autumn Green</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0001.034</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Transcript from Circuit Court</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 267</collection>
<idno>Box 21, Folder 328</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Transcript</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1810-02">February 1810</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.001546">Barnes, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001555">Brent, Daniel Carroll, 1759-1815</term>
<term xml:id="per.000004">Cranch, William, 1769-1855</term>
<term xml:id="per.001543">Duckett, Allen B., 1775-1809</term>  
<term xml:id="per.000063">Fitzhugh, Nicholas</term>
<term xml:id="per.001552">Jameson, Richard</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>Virginia</term>
<term>West Indies</term>
<term>Washington County (D.C.)</term>
<term>Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.000002">
<persName>Ben</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000005">
<persName>Scott, Sabret</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.000001">
<persName>Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.000044">
<persName>Morsell, James Sewall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.000435">
<persName>Jones, Walter, 1776-1861</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Supreme Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>    
<change when="2022-07" who="#kln">Reviewed.</change>         
<change when="2022-06-14" who="#ag">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
  
<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_4544.jpg"/>
 
<p>Negro Ben<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Sabrett Scott</p>
    
<p>In this cause the Court, on the motion of 
the Petitioner, were of opinion and so instructed
the Jury, if they are satisfied by the Evidence 
the Petitioner was imported by the Defendant 
into the State of Maryland before the month of November 
1796, to prove which fact, evidence was offered on the 
part of the Petitioner, that the Defendants in order to 
bring himself within the proviso contained in the first section 
of an act passed by the General Assembly of Maryland 
in the year 1783, entitled "An act to prohibit the bringing 
of slaves into this State" must shew to the Jury that it 
has been fully proved to the satisfaction of the Naval Officer 
or Collector of Tax, by the oath of the owner or some
one or more credible witness or witnesses that the Petitioner 
was a resident of some one of the United States 
for three years antecedent to his coming into the State 
of Maryland and that it is not sufficient for the 
Defendant to prove on this trial to the satisfaction of 
the Jury that the Defendant being a citizen of some and 
of the United States and coming into the States of Maryland 
with a bona fide intention of settling therein, and who 
actually resided within said State for one year at 
least computed from and next succeeding his coming 
into the State, imported the Petitioner, who then belonged 
to the Defendant, and that the Petitioner had been 
an Inhabitant of some one of the United States for 
the space of three whole years next preceding such 
Importation. To which opinion and Instruction 
of the Court the Defendant by his Counsel
<catchwords>excepts</catchwords>

<fw type="pageNum">1</fw>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_4548.jpg"/>
      
excepts &amp; prays that this his Bill of exceptions 
may be sealed and enrolled which in done accordingly</p>
    
<p>W Cranch (seal)<lb/>
Allen B Duckett (seal)</p>

<p>True Copy Test. Wm Brent Clk</p> 

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="IMG_4547.jpg"/>
    
<p>Ben<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Scott</p>

<p>Excepts</p>
   
<p>Sup. Ct. U.S.</p>
 
<pb xml:id="p004" facs="IMG_4549.jpg"/>
 
<p>District of Columbia towit</p>
 
<p>At a Circuit Court of the District of Columbia begun
and held for the County of Washington at the City of Washington 
on the first monday of June Being the first day of the same month 
in the year of our lord one thousand eight hundred and seven, and 
of American Independence the thirty first.</p>
 
<p>Present</p>

<p>The Honorable 
William Cranch Esquire Chief Judge<lb/> 
Nicholas Fitzhugh &amp;
Allen B. Duckett Esquires assistant Judges</p>
 
<p>Daniel Carroll Brent Esquire Marshal<lb/> 
William Brent Clerk</p>

<p>In the record of Proceedings of the same court amongst 
others is the Following towit</p>

<p>Negro Ben<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Sabritt Scott</p>

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit:
the seventeenth day of September in the year 
of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and 
six the said Negro Ben by Francis S. Key his 
solicitor prosecuted and sued forth out of the Circuit Court aforesaid the
United States writ of subpoena directed to the Marshal of the 
District of Columbia aforesaid in the words &amp; of the Court following; 
that is to say, "District of Columbia towit. The United States of America 
to the Marshal of the District of Columbia, Greeting: You are 
hereby commanded to Summon Sabritt Scott that all excuses and 
delays set aside be and appear before the Circuit Court of the 
District of Columbia to be held for the County of Washington at 
the City of Washington on the fourth monday of December next 
to answer the petition of Negro Ben in the said Court exhibited by 
the said Ben against the said Sabritt Scott for his freedom. Hereof 
fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ.</p>

<p>Witness the honorable William Cranch Esquire Chief Judge of the said 
Court the 25th day of June 1806. Issued this 17th day of September</p>

<p>Wm Brent Clk.</p>

<p>F. S. Key</p>
 
<pb xml:id="p005" facs="IMG_4556.jpg"/> 

<p>And the said Negro Ben by his solicitor aforesaid at the time of 
suing forth the aforesaid writ of subpoena filed in Court here this Petition
against the said Sabritt Scott, which is in the words and of the 
tenor following towit.</p> 

<p>To the Honble the Judges of the Circuit Court of the District 
of Columbia The Petition of Ben (a man of Colour) humbly 
sheweth that he is unjustly held in bondage by a certain Sabritt Scott 
of the District of Columbia who claims your petitioner as a slave.
Your petitioner states that he was carried out the State of Virginia 
contrary to the laws of that state &amp; there sold to the said Scott 
&amp; therefore your petitioner considers himself entitled to his freedom. 
He also states that he was brought from Virginia by said Scott 
into the State of Maryland contrary to the laws of the state of 
Maryland &amp; therefore your petitioner also considers himself entitled 
to his freedom. He therefore prays your Honors that he may be 
permitted to prove the truth of the above allegations &amp; relieved 
in the premises as to your honors May be seem meet</p>

<p>F.S. Key for the Petn</p> 

<p>Whereas at an adjourned session of the said Court held on 
the first monday of October being the sixth day of the same month 
in the year of our lord one thousand eight hundred and six 
the said Negro Ben by his solicitor aforesaid filed in Court here 
another petition against the said Sabritt Scott which is in the words &amp; 
of the tenor following; towit, "To the Honble the Judges of the Circuit 
Court for the County of Washington in the District of Columbia</p> 

<p>The petition of Ben (a man of colour) humbly sheweth that 
he has filed a petition in this Court for his freedom against a 
certain Sabritt Scott &amp; that a subpoena has been issued thereon &amp; 
he believes served on the said Scott returnable to the next December 
term of this court. Your petitioner further states that he seriously
apprehends, that before the return of said subpoena &amp; before said Scott
can be compelled under it to enter into the usual &amp; proper recognizance
he may be removed by secret &amp; unjustifiable means without the 
Jurisdiction of this honorable Court. Your Petitioner being still 
held in the possession of said Scott &amp; the said Scott owning and trading
with Vessels to the West Indies &amp; other places &amp; your petitioner being
one of his mariners, he fears that the means of removing him being so

<pb xml:id="p006" facs="IMG_4559.jpg"/>
 
obvious &amp; easy, the said Scott will avail himself of them.</p> 

<p>Your petitioner therefore begs that this honorable Court will 
interpose; that said Scott may be compelled by a Subpoena to 
appear &amp; recognize with Security in the usual manner, or that 
Subpoenas may issue to compell the attendance of witnesses to prove 
that his grounds of Apprehension are reasonable. And your 
Petitioner will pray</p>

<p>F.S. Key for Petitr.</p>
 
<p>Whereupon the Court ordered, the United States' writ of Subpoena 
to be issued against the said Sabritt Scott returnable immediately,
which was done accordingly and directed to the Marshal of the 
District of Columbia aforesaid in the words and of the tenor 
following, Viz.</p>

<p>District of Columbia towit</p>
 
<p>The United States of America to the 
Marshal of the District of Columbia Greeting.</p>

<p>You are hereby commanded to summon Sabritt Scott 
that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before 
the Circuit Court (of the District of Columbia, holding for the County
of Washington at the City of Washington) here immediately to 
answer the petition of Negro Ben for his freedom this day filed 
against him. Hereof fail not at your peril and have you then
and this writ. Witness the honl. William Cranch Esqr. Chief Judge 
of the said Court the 8th October 1806. Issued 8th October 1806</p>

<p>Wm Brent Clk.</p>

<p>And the Marshal of the District of Columbia aforesaid to whom
the last aforegoing writ of subpoena was in form aforesaid Directed makes
return thereof to the court here thereon endorsed</p>

<p>"Summoned"<lb/>
Danl C. Brent, marshal</p>
 
<p>And the said Sabritt Scott in his own proper reason appears in Court 
here; thereupon it is ruled by the Court here that the said Sabritt Scott 
enter into recognizance as prayed in the said Petition.</p>

<p>Whereupon the said Sabritt Scott entered into the following recognizance
towit</p>

<p>United States<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Sabritt Scott</p>

<p>You Sabritt Scott do acknowledge yourself to owe and stand 
Justly indebted to the United States of America in the sum

<fw type="pageNum">4</fw>
 
<pb xml:id="p007" facs="IMG_4562.jpg"/>

of <gap extent="dollar amount" reason="torn document"/> dollars current money to be levied of your body, goods and 
chattels, lands and tenements to and for the use of the said United States
on the condition that you do not remove negro Ben out of the District of Columbia nor obstruct him from attending this court from time to time 
in support of his petition for freedom, exhibited in the said Court against
you and in the mean time to feed, cloath, and use him well, and 
pay whatever satisfaction the Court shall adjudge for the services of 
the said Ben from this term to the time of the Judgment, with costs.</p> 

<p>At which said fourth monday December being the twenty 
second day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand 
eight hundred and six and the day of the return of the first aforegoing
writ of subpoena comes into the Circuit Court here the said Negro Ben 
by his solicitor aforesaid; And the Marshal of the District of 
Columbia aforesaid to whom the said writ of subpoena was in form
aforesaid Directed, makes return thereof to the court here thus endorsed.</p>

<p>"Summoned on the 17th of September 1806"<lb/>
Danl C. Brent Marshal</p> 

<p>And the said Sabritt Scott by James S. Morell and Walter 
Jones Junior his attornies appears in court, here; thereupon on motion 
of the said Negro Ben by his Solicitor aforesaid it is ordered by the Court
here that the said Sabritt Scott answers to the petition aforesaid 
of the said Negro Ben; Whereupon the said Sabritt Scott by his 
attornies aforesaid prayed leave of the court here to imparle untill the 
first monday of June next and then to answer to the petition aforesaid 
of the said Negro Ben; And to him it is granted; the same day is 
given to the said Negro Ben also, then and there &amp;c.</p>

<p>And now here at this day towit the said first monday of 
June being the first day of the same month in the year of our lord 
one thousand eight hundred and seven to which said day the said 
Sabritt Scott had leave to imparle and then to answer the petition 
aforesaid of the said Negro Ben; comes into the Circuit Court here 
as well the said Negro Ben by his Solicitor aforesaid, as the said 
Sabritt Scott by his attornies aforesaid</p>

<p>And the said Sabritt Scott by his attornies aforesaid saith that 
the said Negro Ben is a slave and not free as the said Ben by 
his said Petition first above has alledged and of this he puts himself 
upon the Country &amp;c and the petitioner likewise and <del>and</del> so forth</p>

<p>Therefore let a Jury thereon appear before the Court here immediately</p>

<pb xml:id="p008" facs="IMG_4537.jpg"/>

<p>Negro Ben<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Sabrett Scott</p>
    
<p>On the trial of this cause the Petitioners 
offered evidence to prove that he had been 
imported as a slave by the Defendant 
from the State of Virginia into George Town in the state of 
Maryland some time between the year 1794 &amp; 1796 and the
Defendant on his part offered evidence to prove that at the time of
said importing the said Petitioner he the Defendant was a citizen
of Virginia and came into the State of Maryland with a bona
fide intention of settling therein and actually resided within the
State of Maryland for one year and upwards computed from
and next succeeding his coming in to the State and that the <sic>Petioner</sic>
at the time of being so imported, and for a long time before, 
belonged to the Defendant, and had been an Inhabitant 
of the State of Virginia for the space of three whole years next
preceding such Importation. And the Court upon the 
Motion of the Petitioner, having decided that it was not
sufficient for the Defendant to prove these circumstances 
as on this trial but that it was necessary for the Defendant 
to shew that the residence of the Petitioner in some one of the
United States for three years as aforesaid antecedent 
to his coming into the State of Maryland and been fully
proved to the satisfaction of the Naval Officer or Collector 
of the Tax, by the Oath of the owner or some one or
more credible witness or witnesses. Whereupon the
Defendant offered the Certificate of John Barnes
the Collector of Customs and Naval Officer of 
the United States for the District and Port of George 
Town aforesaid in the words and figures following 
vizt. District of Columbia. County of Washington 
towit. On this 16th day of June in the year eighteen 
hundred and seven, Sabrett Scott a citizen of
<catchwords>the</catchwords>

<fw type="pageNum">5</fw>
    
<pb xml:id="p009" facs="IMG_4538.jpg"/>
    
the United States owner of a mullatto slave named Ben
by his oath before me the subscriber the Collector and Naval 
Officer of the Port of George Town in the County of Washington 
and District of Columbia proved to my satisfaction that the 
said negro Ben was a resident of the State of Virginia and 
of the United States three whole years next preceding
time when the said Mulatto Ben was brought into the State
of Maryland. John Barnes. Collector. The John 
Barnes being at the time of taking the proof and granting 
certificate aforesaid admitted to have been since the year
1801, duly appointed by the President of the United States 
Collector and Naval Officer as aforesaid, and the said Sabrett 
Scott being then and ever since, such his removal and 
Importation into the State of Maryland as aforesaid a 
Resident of George Town aforesaid within the present limits 
of the County of Washington in the District of Columbia aforesaid. 
and upon the Motion of the Petitioner the Court 
decided that the said Certificate was not a sufficient 
Evidence. Whereupon the Defendant offered 
in Evidence the Certificate of Richard Jameson 
who was admitted to have been since the year 1801 
and at the time of taking the proof and granting the Certificate last mentioned
duly appointed by the Levy Court of the County of 
Washington Collector of the Tax for the County of 
Washington aforesaid, which Certificate is in the 
Words and figures following, towit. District of 
Columbia County of Washington towit On this 12th 
Day of June in the Year eighteen hundred and seven
Sabret Scott the owner of a mullatto man called Ben 
fully proved to the satisfaction of me Subscriber the Collector
<catchwords>of</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p010" facs="IMG_4542.jpg"/>

of the Tax for the county of Washington and District of Columbia 
aforesaid that the said negro Ben was a resident of the State 
of Virginia one of the United States three whole years next
preceding the time when the said mulatto Ben was brought 
into the State of Maryland. Richard Jameson</p>

<p>And the Court upon the like motion of the Petitioner 
also decided that the last mentioned Certificate was 
not admissible evidence in this case. To which decision
of the Court the Defendant by his Counsel excepts 
and prays that this his Bill of exceptions may be sealed
and enrolled according to law and the same is done
accordingly.</p>
    
<p>W. Cranch (seal)<lb/> 
N. Fitzhugh (seal)</p>

<p>True Copy Test.<lb/>
Wm Brent Clk</p>

<fw type="pageNum">6</fw>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
