<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0016.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Nan v. Thomas and Zachariah Roberts, Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt"></principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Krohn, Esme M." xml:id="emk">Esme M. Krohn</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="oscys.mdcase.0016.001"></idno>
<idno type="oscys.caseid.0670"></idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1787-04-20"> April 20, 1787</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1787-04">April 1787</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term/><!-- Alphabetized. Only people mentioned in the document. Parties and attorneys go in particDesc. -->  
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term/><!-- Organize by largest place entity first: States, then Counties, then Cities. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term/><!-- What was the outcome of the case? e.g. Judgment for Petitioner -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nan</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName>Roberts, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Roberts, Zachariah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/><!-- If needed -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.) --></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2023-06-06" who="#emk">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="IMG_8185.JPG"/>


<p>Negro Nan 
against
Thomas Roberts and
Zachariah Roberts</p>
<p>Memorandum, the Defendants
in this cause by Gustavus Scott their
Attorney sued out the State of Maryland's
writ of Certiorari, the <unclear>Person</unclear>whereof
ensues in the following words, to wit:
The State of Maryland, To the Justices of Queen <unclear>Anne </unclear> County Court <unclear> Greeting </unclear>
whereas Black Nan hath <unclear>proffered</unclear> a Petition to you our said Justices hum-
bly shewing that she the said Nan is unjustly and unlawfully detained
as a Slave by Thomas and Zachariah Roberts of Queen Ann's County 
Planters and praying that a Subpeona might <unclear>serve</unclear>to compel the attendance
of the said Thomas and Zachariah Roberts to answer unto her the Petitioner 
of and upon the promises and that the Petitioner might be discharged
from Servitude eta. which said Petition is still depending before you in
our said Court as it is said, and we being desirous for certain Reasons
that the said Record should by you be certified to us: Do command you
that you send under your seals the Record of the Petition aforesaid and
all the Proceedings thereon with all things touching the same into our General
Court of the Eastern Shore of this State to be held at Talbot County Court House 
the Second Tuesday of September next plainly and distinctly and in as
full and ample as it now remains before you together with this writ, so
that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what shall appear
to us of might ought to be done. Witness Robert Harrison Esq. 
Chief Judge of our said Court this twentieth day of April Anno Domini 1784.
<unclear>Signed</unclear>the 15th day of May 1784. James Earle Clk. </p>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="IMG_8186.JPG"/>
<p>At which said day, to wit, the said second Tuesday of September Anno Domini, One Thou-
sand seven hundred and eighty four being the day of the return of the aforegoing writ 
the Justices and Clerk of Queen Ann's County in compliance with the writ aforesaid made
<unclear>return</unclear> thereof to the Court here with the following Records annexed, to wit: Maryland, to
wit. At a County Court held for Queen Ann's County at Chester <unclear>Mill</unclear>in the said
County the fourth Tuesday in March being the twenty third day of the same month and
in the year seventeen hundred and eighty four, by the <unclear></unclear> and officers
Authorized and impowered to hold the same Court, of whom were present.–
</p>
<p>Mr. John Brown</p>
<p>Mr. Clement Sewell</p>
<p>Mr. <unclear>Nachet</unclear> Downes</p>
<p>Mr. Thomas M. Forman</p>
<p>Saml Ridgaway Esq., <unclear>Shriff</unclear></p>
<p>Downes Clk.</p>
<p>Black Nan proffered the following Petition, to wit:
To the worshipful the Justices of Queen Ann's County Court.–
The Petition of black Nan humbly sheweth, that she the said Nan is
unjustly and unlawfully detained as a slave by Thomas and Zachariah
Roberts of Queen Ann's County Planters your Petitioner therefore prays that a

</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
