<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0008.033">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Mahoney v. John Ashton. Deposition of John Clagett</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0008.033</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0481</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of John Clagett</title>
<date when="1797-10-30">October 30, 1797</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgments)</collection>
<idno>MSA S498-220</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1799-05">May 1799</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004596">Clagett, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.004683">Clagett, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004597">Crane, Jack</term>
<term xml:id="per.004599">Crane, Moll</term>
<term xml:id="per.004516">Darnall, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.004643">Hickman, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004337">Joice, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.004595">Knight, Peter</term>
<term xml:id="per.001483">Randall, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004576">Wood, Jack</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Queen Ann (Md.)</term>
<term>Upper Marlboro (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.004476">
<persName>Mahoney, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000215">
<persName>Ashton, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2017-08-01" who="#kln">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.033.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The deposition of John Clagett of Edward taken by consent to be read in evidence in the sundry petitions now depending in the General Court brought by persons claiming to be descended from Joice formerly <del>the property</del> in the possessn of Col. Henry Darnall for freedom</p>

<p>To deponent being 64 years of age the 28th of August last past old style and being duly sworn deposeth and saith that Edward Clagett his father who lived in Prince Georges died about the year 1788 as well as he remembers</p>

<p>That he this depont saith that he knew John Wood and Jack Crane who lived at the Woodyard as he understood and was present in Court when they received sentence of death for killing their overseer as it was said. That this Depont was married <del>and moved to Ann Arundel</del> when this event took place and that he was in his twenty fourth year when he was married, but when they were hanged he cannot now precisely ascertain.</p>

<p>That after this event took place he has frequently at times heard his father Edward Clagett speak of John Wood and Jack Crane but never to the best of his knowledge heard him say <del>that they</del> or intimate that they the said Wood &amp; Crane or either of them were born free or descended of a white woman or in any manner entitled to freedom.</p>

<p>That he this Deponent never to the best of his knowledge heard his said father say one word about the Indenture or the burning of the Indenture mentioned in the Deposition of Peter Knight in the cases taken.</p>

<p>That he never heard his said father to the best of his knowledge speak of a person by the name of Moll Crane. That he this Deponent never heard of a woman by that name that he recollects until the other day he heard of such a person from one of the Petitioners, John Hickman. That this Deponents father lived <gap extent="several words" reason="strikethrough"/> and died between Upper Marlbrough and the Woodyard and some where about two or three miles from Marlbrough</p>

<p>That this Depont lived with his father until he this Depont was married except some few years that he was at school that he then moved away and lived near Queen Ann until <gap extent="several words" reason="strikethrough"/> the year 1783 when he moved into Ann Arundel. That this Depont never knew any other Edward Clagett but his father, except a nephew of his said father who died many years ago quite a young man. That this deponent was frequently at his fathers house after he this Depont was married. That this Depont never knew Peter Knight nor does he know that he ever saw him</p>

<p>Sworn to before me 24 Oct 1797<lb/>
John Randall</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>4 1/2 sides</p>

<p>John Clagett of Edward<lb/>
(Contradicts P. Knight)</p>

<p><del>No 24</del></p>

<p>filed 30 Oct 97</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
