<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0008.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Mahoney v. John Ashton. Deposition of Eben Paramore</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0008.015</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0481</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of Eben Paramore</title>
<date when="1796-06-01">June 1, 1796</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgments)</collection>
<idno>MSA S498-220</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1799-05">May 1799</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004336">Baltimore, Charles Calvert, Lord, 1637-1715</term>
<term xml:id="per.004601">Bullen, J.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004337">Joice, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.004616">Lane, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004617">Molly</term>
<term xml:id="per.004618">Nelly</term>
<term xml:id="per.004614">Paramore, Eben</term>
<term xml:id="per.004615">Ratcliff, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.004619">Sally</term>
<term xml:id="per.004620">Shekell, Samuel</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>London (England)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Blue Shirt Neck (Md.)</term>
<term>Pig Point (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.004476">
<persName>Mahoney, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000215">
<persName>Ashton, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2017-07-26" who="#kln">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.015.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Charles Mahoney<lb/>
vs<lb/>
John Ashton</p>

<p>Pet for freedom in the General Court.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Eben Paramore of Prince Georges County aged thirty eight years or thereabouts being duly sworn on the holy evangely of Almighty god deposeth and saith, that he has known the petitioner about three years, but does not know Mr Ashton; that he knows nothing of Charles' claim for freedom more than what he heard from Rachel Ratcliffe now deceased, that about six years ago when the Deponent was a single man, he had his washing done at Mrs Ratcliffe's and being there one evening he saw a mulatto man, there, and after he was gone, he the Deponent asked Mrs Ratcliff, who he belonged to, she answered he belonged to John Lane; The Deponent observed that he was neither white nor black, but more white than black; upon which Rachel Ratcliff told the deponent that she knew Ann Joice very well, and that she understood that she came into this Country with Lord Baltimore, That she lived at the Wood Yard, when she the said Rachel Ratcliffe lived close by it, and that she always understood that she was free and that she now was held in bondage until she had a child named Molly who was a very pretty girl, and that Molly had two children named Nelly and Sally: That some time afterwards about eighteen months before Mrs Ratcliffe died, the Deponent having understood that some of the family of Anne Joice had petitioned for their freedom, he mentioned it to Mrs Ratcliffe, and told her he imagined that she would be summoned, upon which she related again what is abovementioned, and said if she were sworn, that she would swear that she always understood that Anne Joice was not held as a slave until after she had Molly and that Molly had two daughters named Nelly &amp; Sally; and that Mrs Ratfliffe informed the Deponent that she was born and lived near the Wood Yard, and when this Deponent knew her she lived in blue shirt neck near Pig Point. The Deponent further saith that he well knew Samuel Shekell late of Anne Arundel County deceased, and about two year ago he mentioned to the said Shekell what Mrs Ratcliffe had told him, &amp; Shekell said it was <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> true and that he had always understood that Anne Joice came into this Country with Lord Baltimore, &amp; that she was free &amp; not held as a Slave until she had Molly, and the Deponent says that he understood from Mr Shekell that one of the Darnalls at that time owned her but did not mention his christian name That Samuel Shekell lived near Mount Pleasant. Being

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.015.002.jpg"/>

asked if he understood from what country Anne Joice came; answers he did understand both from Rachel Ratcliffe and Samuel Shekell, that she came with Lord Baltimore from London.</p>

<p>Sworn to this 12th day of May 1796, before Bullen</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Eben Paramore's Deposition</p>

<p>8</p> 

<p>5 sides</p>

<p>Eben Paramore</p>

<p>Filed the 1st day of June 1796.</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
