<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0360.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Bowling &amp; Clarissa Gardner v. David Atkins. Bill of Exceptions</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Muñoz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Muñoz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Steph N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2014</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0360.007</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0384</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Bill of Exceptions</title>
<date when="1841-12-17">December 17, 1841</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 21, Entry 6</collection>
<idno>Box 641, Folder 105/106</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Bill of Exceptions</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1841-11">November 1841</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001239">Atkins, Alfred</term>
<term xml:id="per.001240">Atkins, Margaret Norah</term>
<term>Atkins, George</term>
<term>Atkins, Matilda</term>
<term>Bryan, Mrs.</term>
<term xml:id="per.001238">Gardner, Richard B.</term>
<term>Lucas, James F. M.</term>
<term xml:id="per.000044">Morsell, James Sewall</term>
<term>Schill</term>
<term>Simms, Edward</term> <!--alternate spelling Semmes-->
<term xml:id="per.000064">Thruston, Buckner, 1763-1845</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Washington County (D.C)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001241">
<persName>Bowling, Francis</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001242">
<persName>Gardner, Clarissa B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.001236">
<persName>Atkins, David</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>

</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2016-02-15" who="#snc">transcribed; encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Gardiners administrators<lb/>
vs<lb/>
David Atkins</p>

<p>Replevin</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">
   
<p>1st Bill of Exceptions</p>
<p>At the trial of this cause the Plaintiff to sustain the issues on their part joined gave evidence lending to prove that the negro woman named Matilda, mentioned in the deceleration in this case, was sold &#38; conveyed to Richard B. Gardiner their interstate , by one Schill on the 15 August 1822, <unclear extent="one word"/> the bill of sale of that date, &#38; that said negroe woman was in the possession of Edward Semmes in Washington City District of Columbia, for many years before the year <del>1827</del> 1827 &#38; that the other negroes named in the deceleration were the children of said negroe woman named Matilda, &#38; were born since 1822, the Defendant then gave evidence upon the cross examination of the Plaintiffs witnesses to show that the said Matilda from the Spring of <unclear>1827</unclear> cohabited with the Defendant as his wife &#38; acted &#38; passed as a free woman from sometimes in the year 1826

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.002.jpg"/>

<fw>2)</fw>

or 1827 to the present time unmolested by said Semmes or the plaintiffs intestate or the plaintiffs until the year 1833 - that during that time she bore &#38; she &#38; <del>her husband mentioned</del> the Defendant cohabiting as aforesaid mentioned the children in the deceleration mentioned &#38; in that year the said woman &#38; her said children still living with said Defendant, the said Sims was called on after the death of the Plaintiffs intestate &#38; on the part of the Plaintiffs to know what had become of <del>said of the</del> said woman &#38; her children with a view of putting them on their inventory of their interstates estate (they having administrated in Maryland where they &#38; their intestate resided) &#38; that thereupon said Semis produced the letter from Plaintiffs intestate dated 20th February 1827 (front the same) authorizing the said intestates named &#38; <del>then de</del> the said Semis then declared that he had set free the said woman &#38; her children &#38; that this statement of said Semis was communicated to Pltffs intestate shortly afterward, who acquiesced the same until within the last two years when they discovered <del>were informed</del> that the said Sims

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.003.jpg"/>

had not executed any deed of manumission of said woman &#38; her children but had sold the said woman &#38; her children but had sold the said woman &#38; home of her children in the year 1836 to the Defendant <del>&#38; had obtained in his possession the two oldest children of said Matilda claiming them as his slaves</del> &#38; that the said woman &#38; her said <del>slaves</del>children were not included in the inventory of said intestates estate in consequence of the statement made as aforesaid by said Sims - but the Defendants counsel on offering the above proof stated to the Court &#38; Jury that the Defendant confined his defense solely to the proof above given of the said negroes being free in consequence of the letter of said intestate &#38; the said negroes passing as free as aforesaid &#38; so continuing unclaimed &#38; unmolested from 1826 or 1827 to 1846 as aforesaid &#38; that they did not claim their freedom under <unclear>deeds</unclear> of Residence Evidence by Pltts as aforesaid or either of them expend <del extent="one word"/> title of said excuses<del>in any other way or any <unclear exclude="two words"/> any other title or right whatsoever</del> of the plaintiff then gave evidence tending to ignore that their intestate Gardiner resided in Charles County Maryland where he died in 1832 &#38; that the plaintiffs also resided in said county when they administered on said Gardiners estate

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.004.jpg"/>

<fw>4)</fw>

(front the letters of administration), and the plaintiffs gave evidence tending to prove that the Defendant acknowledges he has bought the woman Matilda &#38; her son George from the said Sims (a)</p> 

<pb xml:id="p010" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.010.jpg"/>

<p>and at the same time stated that he <unclear extent="one word"/> <del extent="one word"/> <del>had</del> Simms had no title to them and suspected Mr Gardiner had and he wished the witness to <unclear extent="one word"/> Mr Gardiner  one of said Plaintiffs and see upon what terms he could get the interest of the of the Plaintiffs intestate if they had any interest in the said negores</p>

<p><gap extent="one third of page" reason="another sheet of paper glued ontop"/> The Plaintiffs gave into evidence that the said Defendant was the slave of one Bryan until July 1833 when it is admitted he was manumitted by a complete deed &#38; that previous to 1833 the said Atkins <add place="above">with the permission of his said Mistress</add> <del>the defendant was allowed to keep house &#38; work for himself &#38; his said wife lived together &#38; were generally seen at market together &#38; that the defendant previous to 1833</del> acted &#38; passed in the same way that his said wife did who lived with him. </p>

<p>And the Deft's further offered evidence tending to prove that in the year 1827 <del>witness</del> the said Sims <del extent="one word"/> after the marriage of the said Matilda &#38; after she was going at large as aforesaid, shewed the said letter of said Gardiner to the Witness &#38; stated that said woman was then going at large as aforesaid &#38; the Witness thereupon told the said Sims that he ought to emancipate her.</p>

<pb xml:id="p011" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.011.jpg"/>

<p>And it was further agreed that the said Deft. and the said Matilda &#38; children have never been registered as free negroes under the Court of Corporation of Washington</p>

<pb facs="oscys.case.0360.007.004.jpg"/>

<p><del>further read in evidence to the Jury from the records of Washington County in the District of Columbia the record of a bill of sale from the said Semis to the Defendant dated 19th May 1836 (Front the same) x also read in evidence to the Jury the record of a deed of</del></p>

<p>And the Plaintiffs for the purpose of rebutting the testimony offered &#38; given on the part of the Defendant in regard to the passing of the said negroes as free as aforesaid <del>read in evidence</del> previous to the year 1836 <add place="margin">&#38; for the purpose of shewing that the Defendant claimed the said Matilda &#38; her son George by purchase from said Sims in 1836</add> read in evidence to the Jury <del>from the records of Washington County in the District of Columbia, the record of</del> a bill of sale from said Sims to the Defendant dated 19th May 1836 (front the same) <del>for the purpose afore said of rebutting the evidence on the part of the Defendant in regard to said</del> <add place="margin">And for the purpose of rebutting the evidence on the part of the Defendant as to said negroes passing as free during the time aforesaid</add> also read in evidence <del>from the records</del>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.005.jpg"/>

<fw>5</fw>

<del>aforesaid</del> the record of a deed of manumission by the Defendant dated 23rd May 1836 (front the same) &#38; further gave evidence tending to prove that the said Sims <del>about <gap extent="one word"/>years ago</del> <add place="above">shortly after the date of said bill <del extent="one word"/> date</add>
look into his possession the <del>two</del> eldest child<del>ren</del> of said Matilda named Norah &#38; <add place="above"> in the year 1840 took Alfred the</add> next oldest child &#38; has ever since kept them in servitude, the said Norah being now about 14 years old &#38; the said Alfred being about Eleven years old <add place="above">which children are not exhibited in this suit</add> but the plaintiffs further <del>affirmed to</del> read in evidence for the purpose of explaining the character of <del>explaining</del> said Sims possession, the following letters of said Sims to their intestate written at their respective dates <del>but to the reading of said</del> vis a letter dated 27th Aug. 1822, a letter dated 15th Dec. 1824 &#38; one dated 8th Jany 1825 (front the letters) <del>but the Defendant by his counsel objected to the reading in evidence of said letters or any of them &#38; the Court refused to permit the said letters or any of them to be read to which refusal of the Court the Plaintiffs except &#38; this their bill of exceptions</del>

<pb xml:id="p006"  facs="oscys.case.0360.007.006.jpg"/>

<fw>6</fw>
and the Deft. further offered in evidence <del extent="one word"/> to shew that the said Matilda was married to the Deft and when the said marriage took place the following marriage certificate (here insert it) which was admitted to have the same effect as if Revd Lucas was duly sworn as a Witness &#38; <del>testified to</del> offered to testify to the same facts &#8212; To the admission of which evidence the Dfts counsel objected, but the Court overruled the said objection, &#38; allowed the said Evidence to which the Pltfs except.</p>

<p>And the Deft then further proved that from the time of said marriage the said Matilda lived &#38; kept house with the Deft as her husband &#38; passed about openly &#38; publicly in Washington attending the public market as a free woman, until 1840 &#38; bore the children named in the declaration, who were nurtured &#38; brought up at the sole expense of herself and her said husband, &#38; that neither the said Matilda nor the said Children were during the said period molested by the said Semis or Gardner or the Plfts until the said Sims took <gap extent="one paragraph" reason="page folded in on itself"/></p>

<pb xml:id="p007" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.007.jpg"/>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>2nd Bill of Exceptions</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p><del>In addition to the evidence contained in the aforegoing bill of exceptions the Plaintiffs swore the counsel of the Defendant in this cause &#38; asked him whether he had not in his possession in court a paper purporting to be an original bill of sale from Edward Sims aforesaid to the Defendant conveying the woman Matilda &#38; her son George named in this deceleration to which the said witness replied that all the papers which he had relating to this cause were given to him as his counsel by the Defendant the Plaintiffs then asked said witness to say whether the said paper purporting to be the original bill of sale was not produced by him as a witness in another cause tried in this court on yesterday &#38; was not then returned to him, to which

<pb xml:id="p008" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.008.jpg"/>

the witness replied in the affirmative &#38; the plaintiffs then inquired of said witness to whether the paper so produced by him as aforesaid came into his possession as counsel of the Defendant, which question refused to answer &#38; the Court refused decided that the witness was not bound to answer such question to which opinion decision of the court the plaintiffs except &#8212;</del></p>

<p><del>the Jury</del>And the Deft further proved that said Gardiner married in 1826, &#38; that after his marriage he was in the habit for some years of coming to Washington every year &#8212; but the Witness has no <del extent="one word"/> knowledge of his so coming to Washington after the year 1824 &#8212; that when he came to Washington he was in habit of staying sometimes at the Witness's house &#38; sometimes at said Sim's, whose wife was his niece&#8212;</p>

<p>And the Pltfs then asked the following instructions which the Deft's counsel admitted (here insert A &#38; B.) and then asked the following instructions (here insert the others, marked refused) which the court refused to give to which <catchwords>refusal</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p009" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.009.jpg"/>

<fw>8</fw>

refusal, the Pltfs by their Counsel excepted &#38; prayed the Court to sign &#38; seal this bill of exceptions, which is accordingly done this 17th Decr 1841.</p>

<p>Witness our hands &#38; seals<lb/>
B. Thurston   seal<lb/>
James S Morsell   seal</p>

<p>and the Deft by his Counsel thereupon prayed the Court as follows (insert C.) which the Court &#8212; to which also the Pltfs by their Counsel except &#38; pray the Court to sign &#38; seal this bill of Exceptions, which is done accordingly this 17th Decr 41</p>

<p>Witness our hands &#38; seals-</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p012" facs="oscys.case.0360.007.012.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>agreement 106.</p>
<p>Gardiner<lb/>
vs<lb/>
David Atkins</p>

<p>Replevin negroes</p>

</div2>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>