<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0429.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moses Rustin v. John E. Stromatt. Affidavit of Francis L. Smith</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Askren, Elizabeth" xml:id="ea">Elizabeth Askren</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0429.002</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0458</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Affidavit of Francis L. Smith</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 2</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Affidavit</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1846-05">May 1846</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">   
<term xml:id="per.003552">Stromatt</term><!-- father of John E. Stromatt -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Alexandria County (Va.)</term>
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Alexandria (Va.)</term>
<term>Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.003549">
<persName>Rustin, Moses</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.003550">
<persName>Stromatt, John E.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.003551">
<persName>Smith, Francis L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2017-08-30" who="#kln">added missing xml:id to Stromatt</change>
<change when="2016-10-26" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change> 
<change when="2016-07-21" who="#kln">reviewed, edited</change>           
<change when="2016-06-29" who="#ea">Encoded and transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0429.002.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Moses Rustin<lb/>
vs<lb/>
John E. Stromatt</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia. Sitting at Alexandria.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">
     
<p>Having been assigned counsel for the plaintiff <del>in this case</del>, to report the facts in this case and my opinion thereon. I beg leave to state. <del>That</del> I have reason to believe, that it will be in evidence on the trial of this case, that the plaintiff, was born in slavery as the property of Stromatt, the father of John E. Stromatt, the deft. many years since, in <del>the</del> Charles County in the State of Maryland, that the said plaintiff was held in bondage as a slave for some years in the said County, by said deft, (and his father prior to his death) that he was carried to Washington D.C. as a slave about the year 1828, and remained there &amp; in Georgetown for some years, and from there was taken to the South, when he was held in slavery for a few months <del>for</del> after which he was carried back to Charles County, and <del>at</del> from thence was removed about the spring of 1837, to the Town of Alexandria, D.C. where he has been held in slavery ever since up to the issuing the warrant in this case, on the 20th of December 1845. That since the plaintiff was brought to Alexandria, he has <del>been</del> remained there <del>in the Town of Alexandria</del> <gap extent="two words" reason="strikethrough"/> continuously up to said period, with an absence thereupon once or twice for several days. that during the said period the said plaintiff has remained in the said County of Alexandria for a longer period than one year, without intermission. and that the said defendant has claimed to be the owner or possessor of said Plaintiff as a slave, and during the whole or greater

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0429.002.002.jpg"/>

part of the time last referred to (that <del>is given</del> is during the period that the plaintiff has been held in Alexandria) up to the said 20th of Decr. 1845. the said Stromatt has been in receipt of the hiring of the plaintiff, and controlling him as a slave. If the foregoing facts shall be proven on the trial, as I believe they will be, I have no doubt that the plaintiff is entitled to his freedom, under the provisions of <del>the</del> An Act to reduce into one the several acts concerning slaves, free negroes and mulattoes, passed the 17th of December 1792. This law is in force here, by the provisions of the Act of Congress of the 17th of Feby. 1801, adopting the existing laws of Virginia. The 2nd section provides that "slaves which shall hereafter be brought into the Commonwealth, and kept therein one whole year together, or so long at different times, as shall amount to one year, shall be free." There are some exceptions to this general provision contained in the 4th Sec: of the Statute. I have no reason to believe, that it will be in the power of the defendant, to bring his case within either of the exceptions, in the proviso, referred to. I am therefore of opinion that as the <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> plaintiff was brought as a slave from Maryland to the County of Alexandria, and has been Kept here longer than one year, he is entitled to his freedom.</p>

<p>Very respectfully submitted<lb/>
Francis L. Smith</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0429.002.003.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Moses Rustin<lb/>
vs<lb/>
John E. Stromatt</p>

<p>Opinion of F. L. Smith</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
