<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0008.024">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Mahoney v. John Ashton. Deposition of Sarah Ratcliff</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0008.024</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0481</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of Sarah Ratcliff</title>
<date when="1796-06-10">June 10, 1796</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgments)</collection>
<idno>MSA S498-220</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1799-05">May 1799</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004668">Anderson</term>
<term xml:id="per.004669">Maria</term>
<term xml:id="per.004614">Paramore, Eben</term>
<term xml:id="per.004615">Ratcliff, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.004665">Ratcliff, Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.004667">Richardson, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.004666">Tillard, Thomas</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.004476">
<persName>Mahoney, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000215">
<persName>Ashton, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2017-07-31" who="#kln">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.024.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Question Did yr Mother Rachel Ratlief the person alluded to in the Deposn of Eben Paramore respectg the Freedm of some Negs belongg to the Revd Mr Jno Ashton &amp; others ever <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> Wash the Linen or do any Kind of Work for the Sd Paramore</p>

<p>Answer My Mother Rachel Ratlief never did Wash for the sd Parramore nor did she ever do any Kind of work to <del>her</del> my Certain Knowledge for the sd Eben Paramore</p>

<p>Questn Were yr Mother Ra Ratlief acquainted or did she ever see the sd Eben Paramore</p>

<p>Answer Eben Paramore never <del>was at</del> see my Mother Ra Ratlief who Lived with me all <del>her</del> my Life time after <del>my</del> being a woman grown</p>

<p>Questn Did <gap extent="one or two words" reason="strikethrough"/> any Person ever apply to yr Mother to Enquire whether she Knew any thing respectg the Freedm of some Negs.</p>

<p>Answer Yes Ths Tillard &amp; Rd Richardson did once apply to my Mother. but she told them tht she knew nothg of the Freedom of any Negroes whatever or any Neg was Entitd to their Freedom. Mrs Andersons Negroe Woman Maria

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.024.002.jpg"/>

did <unclear reason="illegible">also</unclear> apply to my Mother Rachel Ratlief to Enquire abt her Freedom. but my Mother told her she Knew nothg of her Freedom. if she was Entd to it it was wht she did not Know</p>

<p>Qu What length of time do you Immagine yr Mother Lived with you &amp; did she Continue to Live with you untill her Death</p>

<p>Ansr Abt Sixteen or Seventeen Years <del>ago</del> &amp; she Lived with me untill her Death</p>


<p>Qu Did yr Mother Ra Ratlief wash for her Self to the time of her Death</p>

<p>Ansr My Mother never washed for Herself for Fifteen or Sixteen Years before her Death I did her washing &amp; every thing Else for her</p>

<p>Qu Why did you wash for yr Mother such a Considera Length of time</p>

<p>Ansr Because she was not Able to Wash or do any Kind of Work <del>bei</del> Whatever unless it was a little Knittg but she never Washd as above</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.024.003.jpg"/>

<p>Quesn Then yr Mother Rachel Ratlief had no Connexion with Eben Paramore nor was she in the Least Acquainted with him</p>

<p>Ansr My Mother was not in the least to my Knowledge Acquainted with Eben Paramore nor had she any Connexion with him any Respect</p>

<p>Qs do you Recollect whether the sd Eben Paramore ever <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> or was he ever <del>at</del> on any occasion at yr House with whom yr Mother Lived to the time of her Death.</p>

<p>Ansr Eben Paramore was never at my House nor did I ever see him but once as he Passed the Main Road &amp; was then told by some one tht it was the sd Eben Paramore</p>

<p>Qn Did yr Mother Rachel Ratlief ever Live near the Wood Yard in Prince Georges County as Asserted in the Deposn of the sd Eben Paramore</p>

<p>Ans My Mother never did live near the Wood Yard to my Knowledge</p>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.024.004.jpg"/>

<p>A A County June 10th 1796 Sarah Ratlief aged abt Forty Years or thereabout Came before me the Subscriber &amp; made oath that the answers she has made to the Defts interogas are to the best of her Knowledge Just &amp; True</p>

<p>Thos Tongue</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="back">

<p>5 1/2 sides<lb/>
Sarah Ratcliffe<lb/>
(contradicts Eben Paramore)</p>

<p>No 14</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
