<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0388.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>William v. George W. Lewis. Affidavit of Augustus Wynkoop</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0388.002</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0413</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Affidavit of Augustus Wynkoop</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 1</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Affidavit</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1819-03">March 1819</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.003080">Butler, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.003084">Nitchie, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.003081">Wynkoop, Augustus</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>New Jersey</term>
<term>Virginia</term>
<term>New York (N.Y.)</term>
<term>Richmond County (N.Y.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.003082">
<persName>William</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.003083">
<persName>Lewis, George W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>   
<change when="2016-07-25" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change>
<change when="2016-06-23" who="#snc">reviewed</change>           
<change when="2016-05-11" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0388.002.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>State of New York ss:</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Augustus Wynkoop of the city of New York merchant being duly sworn deposeth &amp; saith that in or about the fall of the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and eleven he purchased from Thomas Butler of Richmond County in the State of New York the time of a negro boy named William then about the age of seven years, which said William being born since the fourth day of July one thousand and seven hundred and ninety nine was by the Laws of the State of New York free, but subject to remain the Servant of the owner of his mother in the same manner as if bound to service until the age of twenty eight years. That Deponent only received from said Butler a title to the services of the said William until he should arrive at the said age of twenty eight years. That Deponent on the thirty first Day of May last transferred his right to the said Boy to one George W Lewis of the State of New Jersey, a Physician by profession as deponent understood, that it was well understood by said Lewis at the time of such transfer that the said William was not a slave but only liable to serve until of the age aforesaid. That this fact was expressly stated by Deponent to said Lewis, and a memorandum thereof made on the deed of transfer from Deponent to said Lewis. That Deponent has since understood that the said Lewis has

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0388.002.002.jpg"/>

since sold the said William as a Slave in the State of Virginia. That from an official certificate <unclear reason="illegible">handed</unclear> to Deponent by said Thomas Butler at the time of the purchase by this Deponent it appeared that said William was born on or about the twenty fifth day of December one thousand eight hundred and four. And that the said certificate was handed over to said Lewis by Deponent along with the Deed of Transfer made by said Deponent to said Lewis</p>

<p>Augustus Wynkoop</p>

<p>Sworn this 13th June 1816 Before Me<lb/>
J: Nitchie<lb/>
Pub. Notary State of N York Residing in the City of N York</p>

<p>State of New York ss: I John Nitchie a Public Notary of the State of New York residing in the City of New York do hereby certify that by the Seventh section of the Act of the Legislature of the State of New York entitled "An Act concerning slaves &amp; servants" - passed April 9th 1813, it is enacted "that every Child born of a slave within this State after the fourth day of July one thousand seven hundred and ninety nine, shall be free, but shall remain the servant of the owner of his mother and the Executors or Administrators of such owner, in the same manner as if such child had been bound to service by the

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0388.002.003.jpg"/>

overseers of the poor, and shall continue in such service, if a male, until the age of twenty eight years, and if a female, until the age of twenty five years." And does further certify that the said Law of 1813 is one of the revised laws of said States and that the same provision was contained in the antecedent law of the state, under the existence of which the said negroe Boy was born. In Testimony whereof I have hereunto subscribed my hand and affixed my seal of office this thirteenth day of June 1816.</p>

<p>J: Nitchie<lb/>
Pub Noty &amp;c</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
