<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0415.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ann Brooks v. William D. Nutt. Special Verdict</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0415.004</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0442</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Special Verdict</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 2</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Verdict</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1834-10">October 1834</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.003303">Brooks, Clara</term>
<term xml:id="per.003304">Finley, Oliver P.</term>
<term xml:id="per.003310">Gregory, W.</term>
<term xml:id="per.003311">Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.003305">Stewart, James Montgomery</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Alexandria County (Va.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="orginal" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson> 
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.003306">
<persName>Brooks, Ann</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.003307">
<persName>Nutt, William D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.003308">
<persName>Huitt, Thomas W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>    
<change when="2016-09-21" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change>   
<change when="2016-07-01" who="#snc">reviewed</change>          
<change when="2016-06-08" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0415.004.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Ann Brook vs W. D. Nutt admr of Oliver P. Finley.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>We of the Jury find that on the 24th day of July 1805, one James. M. Stewart being the owner and in possession of two female slaves named Clara and her her daughter Sarah, sold the said Clara for the Term of seven years and the said Sarah as a slave for life to Oliver P. Finley, the Defdts intestate, the Terms and conditions of which sale are truly stated in a written agreement between the parties by them duly executed on the said 24th day of July 1805 which agreement is in the words and figures following. "Know all men" &amp;c (here insert paper marked A) we find that the said paper marked A was on the 10th day of May 1833 recorded in the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia for the County of Alexandria on the acknowledgment of the said James M Stewart in open Court. The said James having been on the the 5th day of July 1805, and having ever since continued to be an Inhabitant of the County of Alexandria. We find that the <del>plf</del> said Oliver. P. Finley on the 3rd day of April 1817 duly executed a Deed of emancipation so she said Clara, which was recorded in the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia on the 29th day of Novr

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0415.004.002.jpg"/>

1817 on the acknowledgment in open Court of the sd Finley the said Oliver at the time he executed the said Deed of emancipation and of the recording thereof as aforesaid and until his death having been an Inhabitant of the said County of Alexandria which Deed is in these words. insert paper B</p>

<p>We find that the said Clara was delivered to the said Oliver. P. Finley under the sale aforesaid and remained in his possession under the same from the day of the date thereof until the expiration of the said Term of seven years for which she was sold.</p>

<p>We find that during the said Term of seven years and whilst the said Clara was so held by the said Oliver P. Finley, the Petitioner the daughter of the said <del>Sarah</del> Clara was born, that is to say in the year 1811</p>

<p>We find that the said Oliver P. Finley during his life and the Defdt after his death, held the said Petitioner as a slave claiming her as the property of the said Oliver during his life and as the property of the Defdt as his administrator since his death, from the time of the birth of the plf til the institution of this suit. and that the Defdt still claims to hold the Petitioner as his slave in his <unclear reason="illegible">character</unclear> of administrator as aforesaid.</p>

<p>We find that the said James

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0415.004.003.jpg"/>

M. Stewart on the 3rd day of June 1833 executed and delivered to the plf a Deed of Emancipation in the words "Know all men &amp;c" (here insert paper C) + we find that the said James at the time of the execution and recording of the said Deed was an Inhabitant of the said County of Alexandria</p>

<p>(+ and that the said Deed was on the same day duly recorded in the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia at Alexandria)</p>

<p>if on the evidence aforesaid the law be for the plf then we find for the plf and assess her damages to the sum of one cent. and if the law be for the Defdt then we find for the Defdt<lb/>
<unclear reason="illegible">W</unclear> Gregory, Foreman</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.case.0415.004.004.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Special Verdict</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.case.0415.004.005.jpg"/>

<p>Negro Ann Brooks<lb/>
v.<lb/>
Nutt (admr.)</p>

<p>For Freedom</p>

<p>1833. May T. 3d day: T. W. Hewitt assd. counsel, on whose report leave given to sue in forma paup. &amp; caps. awd. &amp; docketd</p>

<p>5th day. Jury sworn, &amp; retired to consider of their verdict.</p>

<p>6th day. Jury retd. special verdict. [see papers]</p>

<p>1834. Oct. T. 4 day.<lb/>
Judgt. for Deft on the special verdict</p>

<p>Oct. 1834 - 1</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
