<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0007.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ann Queen v. Sylvester Boarman and David Queen v. Sylvester Boarman. Court Record of Edward Queen v. John Ashton</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Bryant, Samantha M." xml:id="smb">Samantha M. Bryant</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2014</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0007.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0386</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0387</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Court Record of Edward Queen v. John Ashton</title>
<date when="1801-05-26">March 26, 1801</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Historical Society of Harford County, Maryland</repository>
<collection>County Court Records Collection, Bel Air, Maryland</collection>
<idno>Folder 32:14 - Court Records</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Exhibit</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1801-03">March 1801</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001487">Atwell, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001486">Atwell</term>
<term xml:id="per.000215">Ashton, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001498">Beall Jr., Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.001489">Belt, J. S.</term>
<term xml:id="per.001499">Billingsley, Walter</term>
<term xml:id="per.001469">Carrick, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.001470">Carrick, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001471">Carroll, Anthony</term>
<term>Carroll, John, 1735-1815</term><!-- I think maybe Warfield means John Ashton, not Carroll. We didn't encode him in oscys.mdcase.0001.005 or oscys.mdcase.0001.015 -->
<term xml:id="per.000065">Carroll, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.001490">Chapman, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.002102">Chase, Jeremiah Townley, 1748-1828</term>
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.000061">Clarke, Caleb</term>
<term xml:id="per.001472">Clarke, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.001496">Cooke, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.000066">Cooper, Nanny</term>
<term xml:id="per.001500">Cooper, Spencer</term>
<term xml:id="per.001501">Cresap, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.000072">Davis, George</term>
<term xml:id="per.000073">Disney, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.001488">Duckett, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.001393">Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</term>
<term xml:id="per.000062">Duvall, Mareen</term>
<term xml:id="per.001474">Fowler, Susannah</term>
<term xml:id="per.001502">Gassaway, John</term>
<term>Goldsborough, Robert, 1740-1798</term>
<term>Goldsmith, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.001503">Gover, Robert</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001504">Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.001505">Hilleary, Tilghman</term>
<term xml:id="per.000075">Ijams, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001491">Ijams, Plummer</term>
<term xml:id="per.001495">Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</term>
<term xml:id="per.001475">Larkin, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.001478">Lee, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.000077">Lee, Lewis</term>
<term xml:id="per.000221">Lusby, Deborah</term>
<term xml:id="per.001507">Mackubin, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.001506">Matthews, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.001508">McCubbin, John Cray</term>
<term xml:id="per.001509">Merrikin, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.000078">Queen, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.001479">Queen, Gervais</term>
<term xml:id="per.000068">Queen, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.001485">Queen, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.001476">Queen, Phillis</term>
<term xml:id="per.001480">Queen, Proteus</term>
<term xml:id="per.001481">Queen, Sukey</term>
<term xml:id="per.001482">Queen, Winifred</term>
<term xml:id="per.001477">Quynn, Allen</term>
<term xml:id="per.001483">Randall, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.001510">Robinson, Archibald</term>
<term xml:id="per.001511">Truman, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.000074">Warfield, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.001484">Welch, Robert</term>
<term xml:id="per.001513">West, Benjamin</term>
<term xml:id="per.001494">Williams, J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson xml:id="oscys.caseid.0386">            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Queen, Ann</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Boarman, Sylvester</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listPerson xml:id="oscys.caseid.0387">            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Queen, David</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Boarman, Sylvester</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. County Court (Harford County)</orgName>
<placeName>Bel Air (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2016-02-29" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change>
<change when="2016-02-23" who="#kln">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2016-02-01" who="#smb">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The State of Maryland Sct.</p>

<p>At a General Court of the said State, one of the United States of America begun and held for the Western Shore at the City of Annapolis on the Second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth day of the same month in the Eighteenth year of the Independence of the said United States of America and in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four.</p>

<p>Present<lb/>
The Honorable Samuel Chase, Esquire chief Judge<lb/>
Robert Goldsborough and Jeremiah Townley Chase Esquire Judges</p> 

<p>William Goldsmith Esquire Sheriff. John Gwinn Clk</p>

<p>In the record of the proceedings of the same court among others is the following towit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
against<lb/>
Reverend John Ashton</p>  

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it Remembered that on the fifteenth day of October in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one Edward Queen by Gabriel Duvall his attorney exhibits to the Judges of the General court here in court sitting his Petition for freedom against the Reverend John Ashton in the words and figures following towit.</p>  

<p>To the Honorable The Judges of the General Court.</p>   

<p>The Petition of Edward Queen humbly sheweth that he is held in slavery by the Revd. John Ashton altho he is informed he is entitled to his freedom being descended from a free woman, vizt. being the son of Phillis who was the Daughter of Mary Queen commonly called Queen Mary, a free woman; he therefore prays your Honours to direct summons to issue against the said John Ashton returnable immediately to answer the premises; &amp; that your honours, the facts being proved will adjudge your petitioner to be free; and he will pray &amp; soforth.</p>  

<p>G Duvall<lb/>
P B Key for Petr.</p>

<fw type="catch">Whereupon</fw>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.002.jpg"/>

<p>Whereupon it is ordered by the court here that the said Reverand John Ashton do not remove the aforesaid Edward Queen out of this State, nor obstruct him from attending this court from time to time in support of his Petition for freedom preferred against him the said John Ashton and in the mean time to feed, cloath and use the said Petitioner well; And at the prayer of the aforesaid Edward Queen by Gabriel Duvall and Philip Barton Key his attornies aforesaid Summons is ordered by the court here to issue to the Sheriff of Anne Arundel County against the aforesaid John Ashton to answer the Petition aforesaid which accordingly issued in the words and figures following towit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland, Sct. To the Sheriff of Anne Arundel County, Greeting. We command you that you summon the Reverend John Ashton that all delays and excuses set aside he be and appear before the Judges of our General Court at Annapolis immediately to answer unto the Petition of Edward Queen preferred against him for freedom; hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness The Honorable Samuel Chase Esquire chief Judge of our said Court the 11th day of October Anno Domini 1791.</p>

<p>Issued the 17th day of October 1791. GD Jno. Gwinn Clk</p>

<p>And the Sheriff of Anne Arundel County to whom the aforegoing precept was made and directed comes and makes return thereof to the court here thus endorsed to wit.</p>

<p>Sd. J. Williams Shff.</p>

<p>And the aforesaid Reverend John Ashton by William Cooke his attorney comes and defends the complaint aforesaid when <unclear reason="torn page">and</unclear> where the said court shall take the same into consideration <unclear reason="torn page">and</unclear> prays leave of the court to imparle hereunto untill next court; and he hath it: the same day is given to the Petitioner also. At which said next court towit the second Tuesday of May being the eighth day of the same month in the year of our <unclear reason="torn page">Lord</unclear> one thousand seven hundred and ninety two comes again <gap extent="one or two words" reason="torn page"/> into our General Court as well the aforesaid Edward <unclear reason="torn page">Queen</unclear> by his attornies aforesaid as the aforesaid John Ashton <unclear reason="torn page">by his</unclear> attorney aforesaid: and the aforesaid John Ashton <fw type="catch">by</fw>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.003.jpg"/>

by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the complaint aforesaid when and where the court shall take the same into consideration and prays further leave of the court to imparle hereunto untill next court; and he hath it: the same day is given to the Petitioner also.</p>

<p>At which said next court towit, the second Tuesday of October being the ninth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, comes again here into our General Court as well the aforesaid Edward Queen by his Attornies aforesaid as the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid: and the aforesaid Edward Queen by his Attornies aforesaid filed in court here the following Depositions towit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
a<lb/>
John Ashton</p>

<p>Petition for Freedom in the General Court.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Richard Disney of Anne Arundel County aged seventy five years being duly sworn on the Holy Evangelist of Almighty God, to say the truth of his knowledge in this cause saith, that he knows Phillis and Nanny Cooper who belong to the Defendant, and has known them ever since he was a child. And Phillis is a Mulatto, and Nanny Cooper as black as most negroes; but he does not remember the Mother of Phillis and Nanny; and this deponent knew James Carroll who formerly lived at Fingal, very well, and this Deponent's Mother who is now dead, was a midwife, and has often told him that the aforesaid Nanny was the first child she ever took, and was very well acquainted in the said James Carroll's family and she attended the family many years as a midwife, and he has often heard her say, that is was a shame that the mother of Phillis and Nanny was kept in slavery, and if Mr Carroll would be false in one thing, he would be false in another; And this Deponent remembers to have heard a great deal of talk about her and has heard divers persons say that Captain Larkin brought her into this country and that she had a great many fine Cloaths and that old William Chapman took her a shore once and it was noised about that there was a fine Lady from

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.004.jpg"/>

London, and nobody would buy her for some time, untill at last James Carroll bought her and this Deponent has heard Captain Iiams, who is now deceased, brother of Plummer Iiams say that Phillis ought to be free, and this Deponent further saith that he cut and spayed young stock at Fingal three or four years when Lewis Lee who is now dead, was overseer there and he has heard Lewis Lee say that Phillis ought to be free and Phillis then lived in a house by herself; Being asked if Lewis Lee was an older man than the Deponent? Answers yes, many years, and that he was a man when the Deponent was a Boy: and the Deponent says that he never took much notice of what was said about her, never expecting to be a Witness: Being asked whether the Mother of Phillis and Nanny was respected to be a mulatto woman or a negro? Answers he dose not know. The foregoing Deposition taken before me, one of the Justices of the peace for the county aforesaid on the fourteenth day May seventeen hundred &amp; ninety two.</p>

<p>J.S. Belt.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
v<lb/>
The Revd. John Ashton</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in the General Court.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The Deposition of Thomas Warfield aged forty two years or thereabouts, being sworn on the Holy Evangely of Almighty God saith that about the year seventeen hundred and eighty two or seventeen hundred &amp; eighty three this Deponent was overseer at Bright Seat in Anne Arundel County for the late Reverend John Carroll and had carried down six Hogsheads of Tobacco for the said John Carroll to Taylor's Landing warehouse where Capt. John Jiams, now deceased, was Inspector, and the said Inspector was going to mark the Tobacco with the name of the Deponent when the Deponent told him not, but to mark it with the name of John Carroll, priest, upon which the said Capt. John Jiams asked him what he to do with priest Carroll to which the Deponent answered he was overseer for him; the said John Jiams then asked the Deponent if he knew old Phillis who lived at the quarter, to which he answered that he did know <fw type="catch">(her)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.005.jpg"/>

her very well; The Deponent then asked the said John Jiams if he knew her, and he answered he knew her very well and said she was as free as he was if she had her right; the Deponent then asked him how she came to be free, and he answered that her mother was free and was brought into the Country by Captain Larkin and was sold for seven years and the Deponent thinks the said Jiams told him that she was sold to one of the Chapmans; and he further says that the said Captain Jiams told him that her name was Mary Queen to the best of his recollection; and that she afterwards belonged to James Carroll who lived at Fingal in Anne Arundel County, and who as this deponent has understood left the place beforementioned together with the White Marsh Plantation and his personal Estate to the church; being asked how far Captain John Jiams lived from the quarter where Phillis then lived? Answers about a mile, and he always lived there ever since the memory of this Deponent, and he has always understood that Phillis beforementioned is the mother of Ned the petitioner. Being asked what is the Complexion of Phillis? Answers she is yellow and appears to be a bright mulatto: and further saith not.</p>

<p>Sworn to before the subscriber this 11th Oct. 1792.</p>

<p>James Mackubin.</p>

<p>And the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the complaint aforesaid when and where the court shall take the same into consideration and prays further leave of the court to imparle hereunto untill next court; and he hath it: the same day is given to the Petitioner also.</p>

<p>At which said next court towit the second Tuesday of May being the fourteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three comes again here into our General Court as well the aforesaid Edward Queen by his attornies aforesaid as the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid: and the aforesaid Edward Queen <fw type="catch">(by)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p006" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.006.jpg"/>

by his Attornies aforesaid files in court here the following Deposition towit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
against<lb/>
John Ashton</p>

<p>Petition for Freedom in the General Court.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>George Davis of Anne Arundel County aged fifty four years and upwards being sworn on the Holy Evangely of Almighty God to testify the truth of his knowledge in this cause deposeth and saith that he has known Ned the Petitioner for many years, and he has known Phillis who now lives with Mr Ashton for about twenty years; and he further saith that between Twenty one and Twenty two years ago, the Deponent happened at John Atwell's who then lived on the Land now owned by Thomas Duckett near Mr Ashton's, and Ned the Petitioner passed by, and Lewis Lee who lived in Anne Arundel County was present and when Ned the Petitioner was passing the Deponent observed how many Mulattoes there were at the priests to which the said Lewis Lee answered yes, and said that, that Lad pointing at Ned, ought to be free, for his grandmother was a free woman: Being asked if he knew the grandmother of Ned? Answers he did not know any thing about her he further saith that Mrs. Atwell wife of the aforesaid John Atwell asked the said Lewis Lee several questions about her (meaning the grandmother of Ned) and Lewis Lee made answer, the substance of which he does not recollect except that he said that Capt Larkin brought her in: Being asked if he remembers that the said Lee mentioned where she was brought from? Answers he does not.</p>

<p>being asked if Lewis Lee mentioned the name of Neds Grandmother? Says he did not nor where she lived nor how he got his Information</p>

<p>Sworn before me this 27th May 1793. Allen Quynn</p>

<p>And the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the complaint aforesaid when and where the court shall take the same into consideration, and prays further leave of the court to imparle hereunto untill next court; and he hath it: the same day is given to the Petitioner also. At which said next court towit, the second Tuesday <fw type="catch">(of)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p007" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.007.jpg"/>

of October being the eighth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three comes again here into our General court as well the aforesaid Edward Queen by his attornies aforesaid as the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid and the aforesaid Edward Queen by his attornies aforesaid files in court here the following Deposition towit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
against<lb/>
John Ashton</p>

<p>Petition for Freedom in the General Court.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Caleb Clarke of Prince George's County aged forty seven years being sworn on the Holy Evangely of Almighty God, deposeth and saith that he knows Ned the Petitioner, and the Defendant, and has known them both for many years: that he knows Phillis a mulatto woman who lives with the said John Ashton but does not know that she is the mother of Ned; Being asked if he knew the grandmother of Ned? Answers he never did. That he has often heard his mother, Mary Clarke, who has been dead about eight years, and was about sixty nine years old when she died, say that a yellow woman called Mary Queen was brought into this country by Captain Larkin as she had been frequently told by her Father Marsh Mareen Duvall: that the said Larkin frequented her said Father's House, and was known by his said mother; that James Carroll also frequented it: and the said Carroll and his the Deponents grandfather lived within sight of each other; and he has heard his mother say often in conversation that the said Mary Queen was owned by the said James Carroll, and that her father had often heard the said James Carroll and Mary Queen quarrelling and wrangling about her freedom as he had told her that the said James Carroll would say to her, poh! have patience you will be free by and by, or you will get your freedom, by and by or words to that effect, and would promise what he would do for her; that he has often heard The same from his Aunt Fowler who was his mother's sister, and from his Aunt Carrick another sister, and also from John Carrick husband of his Aunt Carrick that his said Aunts were <fw type="catch">(many)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p008" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.008.jpg"/>

many years older than his mother; Being asked how much older they were than his mother? Answers he does not know exactly; but that he knew his Aunt Fowler well and she must have been at least twenty years older than his mother: and his Aunt Carrick about ten or twelve years older than his mother; and that his said Aunts and the said John Carrick are all dead: and further he saith that he has understood from some of the persons aforesaid that the said Mary Queen was left or given by the said James Carroll to Anthony Carroll and sent <del>up</del> across the Bay to him. And further he saith not.</p>

<p>Allen Quynn</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the premisses aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by consent of the same parties and their Attornies aforesaid and by order of the court here thereon is continued untill the second Tuesday of May next following.</p>

<p>And now here at this day towit the said second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four comes again here into our General Court as well the aforesaid Edward Queen by his attornies aforesaid as the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid: and the aforesaid John Ashton by his attorney aforesaid files in court here the following Deposition and Extract of James Carroll's will towit.</p>

<p>The Deposition of Deborah Lusby of Anne Arundel County about fifty years of age being first duly sworn deposeth and saith that she is the Daughter of Edward Lee and well knew his Brother Lewis Lee and Robt. Welch who were very old men when they respectively died who all lived in the neighbourhood of James Carroll's Plantation called Fingall where old Phillis the <del>respected</del> reputed slave of James Carroll also <del>died</del> lived, that this deponent well knows old Phillis and knew her about thirty years past but never heard the said Phillis or any of her Descendants were intitled to be free; or that they claimed Freedom until very lately. This Deponent further <fw type="catch">(saith)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p009" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.009.jpg"/>

saith the said Edward and Lewis Lee were well acquainted in Mr. Carroll's Family and verily believes if they or any one of them had ever thought the said Phillis or her Children were entitled to freedom or had ever thought so she should have heard them mention it she also deposeth and saith that she often heard her father Edward Lee say that he never no much repented any thing in his life as that he did no buy the said Phillis at a time when he might have got her for five pounds, but at that time it was generally known that the said Phillis was very ill with the veneral complaint and married to one of his negroes. The Deponent further saith that she has often heard her Father &amp; Uncle Lewis Lee talking about Phillis, but does not recollect what they said: that she does not recollect ever to have heard either of them say who Phillis's mother was; that she has known Ned the Petitioner a great many years, &amp; always understood he was the son of Phillis, but she never heard any person say who was the mother Phillis, That at the time when Phillis was sick as before related the Deponent cannot say how old she was, but thinks she had Children afterwards, but is not sure; that Phillis has one sister named Nanny Cooper, which the Deponent knew many years ago; that said Phillis has many children known to this Deponent, towit, Sukey, Mary, Gervais, Proturs and Winifred; but she does not recollect any more.</p>

<p>Deborah Lusby<lb/>
her + mark</p>

<p>Sworn before me the 21st day of March 1794 the Deponent Deborah Lusby having first signed the same.<lb/>
John Randall</p>

<p>I bequeath to my cousin Anthony Carroll now with me two negroes vizt. Henry and Mary to be delivered if alive to him the tenth of October after my decease the better to enable him to seat his five hundred acres of Land which is to be laid out in a convenient form where he shall think fit to seat if he settles first.</p>

<p>In Testimony that the above is a true extract from the will of James Carroll bearing date <fw type="catch">(the)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p010" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.010.jpg"/>

the twelfth day of February one thousand seven hundred and twenty eight and proved June the 27th 1727 recorded in Liber CC No.2 one of the late prerogative Records I have hereto set my hand and affixed my seal of Office this 19th day of May in the year of our Lord 1794.<lb/>
Jno. Gassaway Reg Wills AA Coty</p>

<p>And the said John by his attorney aforesaid (admitting that the said Edward is descended from Mary Queen mentioned in the said Petition) comes and says that the said Mary Queen the Grand Mother of the Petitioner from whom by Descent the Petitioner claims his freedom always was a Slave: and this the said John is ready to verify: without that, that the said Mary was free as alledged by the said Petition. And the said Edward by his attorney aforesaid saith that the said Mary Queen was not a Slave at the time of the Birth of the Issue of Mary Queen from whom the said Edward is descended as the said John above in pleading hath alledged: and this the said Edward prays may be enquired of by the country and soforth: and the said John doth the like. Therefore let a Jury thereupon appear before the court here immediately by whom andsoforth, and who neither andsoforth to recognize and soforth, because as well and so forth, who being called come that is to say; John Truman, John Cray McCubbin, Walter Billingsley, Archibald Robinson, Robert Gover, James Cresap, James Matthews, Benjamin West, Richard Beall Junior, Spencer Cooper, Tilghman Hilleary and Richard Merrikin, who being elected, tried and sworn to say the truth in the premises upon their Oath do say, that the said Mary Queen the Grandmother of the Petitioner was not a Slave; and that he the said Edward Queen the Petitioner is descended from the said Mary Queen in manner and form as he the said Edward Queen in his said Petition to the court here preferred against the aforesaid John Ashton hath alledged.</p>

<p>Therefore it is adjudged by the court here that the said Edward Queen the Petitioner aforesaid be hence freed and discharged of and from the service of the aforesaid Reverend <fw type="catch">(John)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p011" facs="oscys.mdcase.0007.001.011.jpg"/>

John Ashton, and that he the said Edward Queen the Petitioner aforesaid go thereof without day andsoforth.</p>

<p>It is also considered by the court here that the said Edward Queen the Petitioner recover against the aforesaid Reverend John Ashton the quantity of one thousand nine hundred and ninety seven pounds of Tobacco by the court here unto him the said Edward Queen the Petitioner aforesaid on his assent adjudged for his costs and charges by him about his Prosecution of the Petition aforesaid in this behalf laid out and expended: and that he have thereof his execution against the aforesaid John Ashton soforth.</p>

<p>Memorandum, Judgment was rendered in this cause on the twenty third day of May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clk</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sct.</p>

<p>I hereby certify that the aforegoing is truly taken from the Record of Proceedings of the General Court of the Western Shore of the State aforesaid.</p>

<p>In Testimony whereof I have to this Exemplification (the same being first duly Stamped) set my hand and affixed the seal of the said General Court this fifteenth day of March in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety eight, and in the twenty third year of the Independence of the United States of America.</p>

<p>John Gwinn Clk<lb/>
Genl. Court. W Shore S of Maryland</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Edward Queen<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Revd. John Ashton</p>

<p>Record</p>

<p>No. 1</p>

<p>Cost £2.12.O Cmy</p>

<p>8$ 7 May</p>

<p>Fild. 26 May 1801</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
