<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.supp.0002.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Select Committee on Illegal Traffic in Slaves in D.C. Deposition of Francis S. Key</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2014</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.supp.0002.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of Francis S. Key</title>
<date when="1816-04-22">April 22, 1816</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 233, Records of the Select Committees of the House of Representatives</collection>
<idno>HR 14A-C.17.4, Papers of the Select Committee to Inquire into the Existence of an Inhuman and Illegal Traffic in Slaves in the District of Columbia</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.000279">Brown, Mary Eliza</term>
<term xml:id="per.000280">Brown, Rosanna</term>
<term xml:id="per.000001">Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843</term>
<term xml:id="per.000278">Miller, George</term>
<term xml:id="per.000282">Parker, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004850">Randolph, John, 1773-1833</term>
<term xml:id="per.000276">Wilson, Cordelia</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Delaware</term>
<term>Georgia</term>
<term>Maryland</term>
<term>North Carolina</term>
<term>Alexandria County (Va.)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Washington County (D.C.)</term>
<term>Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc> 
<change when="2017-12-12" who="#kln">added xml:ids</change>            
<change when="2017-12-11" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="document">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.supp.0002.003.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The Deposition of Francis S. Key of Geo Town Cola who being required to state his knowledge of the nature &amp; extent of the slave-trade carried on in this District &amp; of any abuses attending the same, deposed as follows&#8212;</p>

<p>My own observation will not enable <del>to</del> me to <del>do much more than conjecture</del> speak <unclear reason="illegible">positively</unclear> or particularly as to the extent &amp; nature of this trade. I believe it is principally carried on in Slaves brought here from Maryland Deleware &amp; perhaps other places to be sold to <del>the</del> Traders, <del>who are almost</del> from Georgia Carolina &amp; other States some of whom are almost always to be found here, &amp; slaves who are purchased in Maryland &amp; other places by such Traders &amp; brought here in order to be kept together till they have obtained <del>a sufficient</del> the number they mean to purchase. The number <del>sold to such Traders from persons residing in</del> <del>purchased by</del> of negroes residing in the District sold to such Traders is (I think) not considerable.</p>

<p>This business, I have observed, has been greatly increasing for several years past. What number are annually purchased <del>&amp; transported in the ways I</del> in the various ways I have mentioned &amp; transported from <del>the</del> Washington County in this District I cannot tell, but I should think some hundreds. I have no knowledge of the extent or nature of this business in Alexandria County.</p>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.supp.0002.003.002.jpg"/>

<p>The abuses which I have observed attending this trade (omitting those acts of inhumanity committed in confining &amp; transporting them which are perhaps necessary to the trade &amp; therefore not to be considered as abuses of it) are the separations of Husband &amp; Wife, Parents &amp; Children, &amp; the frequent seizure <del>&amp; transportation</del> of free persons who are hurried off in the night brought to the City, &amp; transported as slaves. Several instances of the most extreme distress have been produced by each of these abuses; <del>with</del> of some of them I have <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> had pesronal knowledge, though of amost of them I have only information from others.</p>

<p>A woman was sold to a Trader a week or 10 days ago, who has a husband in Geo  Town. She had lived for nearly a year near my house. Her master <del>whose name</del> who lives in Maryland told me that shew as most faithful servant &amp; had always behaved well, that he wanted to sell her but would not sell her away from her husband. She was taken by the Trader into the City in a hack &amp; and I am credibly informed &amp; believe that she attempted to kill herself by cutting her throat in the hack. The wound was sewed up in the City at George Miller's tavern. I was told this by two persons who saw her afterwards. I was also called upon professionally &amp; my opinion required by some person interested in the

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.supp.0002.003.003.jpg"/>

contract, upon the following facts which he stated to me.</p>

<p>A negro woman (I think in P. Geos County) was sold to one of these Traders. She was shewn to the Purchaser &amp; told that she was sold, when taking up a cleaver, or some such instrument she chopped off one of her hands; upon which the Trader refused to take her.</p>

<p>I have been <del>called upon to issue process</del> employed in several cases where free persons were about to be transported as slaves. <del>&amp; also</del> Three were discovered during the last term of Washington County Court to be among a drove of negroes then in the City &amp; their transportation stopped by the Court. They were stolen <del>f</del> in the State of Delaware &amp; I have received papers from that State shewing that they are free. About a year ago I was present when a Magistrate <unclear reason="illegible">Dott</unclear> took from a Trader who was <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> carrying off a number of negroes a woman who was unquestionably free, or who had only a limitted time to serve. On that occasion we were refused permission to see the negroes &amp; while a man, concerned with the trader, kept us in conversation in the front of the house, the other attempted to carry off the woman (with other negroes) through the back yard into another street. We overtook him leading his horse with the woman by his side, &amp; a Pistol in his hand. He left the woman leaped on his horse &amp; rode off at full speed.</p>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.supp.0002.003.004.jpg"/>

<p>I do not remember any other instances of abuses of this nature of which I have personal knowledge. I have been informed of others &amp; have no doubt from the secrecy with which they are generally kept, &amp; the difficulties in arresting them in time, that many are carried away as slaves who are entitled to their freedom.</p>

<p>FSKey.</p>

<p>Geo Town<lb/>
22 April 1816.</p>

<p>Sown to before me this 22d day of April 1816<lb/>
John Randolph of Roanoke<lb/>
Chairman</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
