<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0179.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moses Graham v. Richard B. Alexander. Jury Instructions</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Steph N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0179.011</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0181</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Jury Instructions</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 2</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Jury Instructions</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1840-03">March 1840</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001347">Alexander, Frances</term>
<term xml:id="per.001348">Brown, Elizabeth</term>
<term xml:id="per.003632">Brown, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.001352">Dunbar, Milly</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Alexandria County (Va.)</term>
<term>Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson> 
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.001342">
<persName>Graham, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.001343">
<persName>Alexander, Richard B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>             
<change when="2017-01-18" who="#snc">reviewed, edited</change>
<change when="2016-10-26" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change>  
<change when="2016-07-07" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Neg Moses v Alexander</p>

<p>(1)</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>If the Jury believe from the evidence that the Deft. as admr. of Mrs Alexander admitted that the Petr was entitled to his freedom at the age of 31, then they may infer from such admission <del>is proper &amp; competent evidence to shew</del> that Mrs Alexander had no greater claim to the Petr than to serve to that age. Unless the contrary is proved to their satisfaction</p>

<p>given 24 Apl 1839.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.002.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Petitioner</p>

<p>inference from Admission of Adm</p>

<p>1838<lb/>
<hi rend="underline">&#160;&#160;26</hi><lb/>
1812</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.003.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Neg. Moses v Alexander (3)</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>If the Jury believe that Miss Brown the owner of Milly brought her from Geo Town to Alexa. Couty where she lived with her sister Mrs Alexander intending to sell her for a term of years &amp; her issue to the same period <gap extent="several words" reason="strikethrough"/>. And that Miss Brown &amp; Mrs Alexander both considered that the Will of Parson Brown was valid &amp; that <gap extent="two or three words" reason="strikethrough"/> the said Milly and her issue were to be free at 31, and that they were so considered by both of them in the bargain or sale made <del>by</del> between them, then such Evidence is competent <del>bargain or</del> for the consideration of the jury in deciding whether the Sale is to be considered <del>as understood by the said parties to give</del> as giving Mrs Alexander a right to the issue as slaves for life or till the age of 31 &amp; no longer.</p>

<p>Given 24 Apl 1839</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.004.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Instructions Given &amp; refused</p>

<p>Given for Petitioner.</p>

<p>inference from impression of parties to sale of validity of Parson Brown's will.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.005.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>If the Jury believe from the evidence that the Petr's Mother was brought into Alexa. Coty. from Washington after the year 1810 by Miss Brown her owner &amp; was there <gap extent="one word" reason="strikethrough"/> kept for more than a year, <del>but</del> and that the Petr was born within the year from the importation of the mother, &amp; was kept in said County after his birth with his said mother for more than a year, then the <del>importation of said mother &amp; birth of said Petitioner</del> said Petitioner though born of a mother then a slave, &amp; consequently himself a slave, was to be removed by his master, &amp; if not so removed but kept in the said County for more than a year, then the Petr. would be free by the said act of 1792.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p006" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.006.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p><del>Ple</del></p>

<p>Petitioners Importation.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p007" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.007.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p><del>Th</del></p>

<p>If the Jury believe that Milly &amp; her issue were sold by Miss Brown to Mrs Alexander for a term of years, then the said will of Miss Brown does not give freedom to the petitioner.</p>

<p>refused 24 Apl 1839</p>

<p>but if the Jury believe from the evidence that the Deft., the admr of Mrs Alexander, admitted that the Petitioner was entitled to her freedom at 31, then it is competent for the Jury to infer that the terms &amp; conditions of the sale made of Milly by Miss Brown to Mrs Alexander, were that the issue were to be free at 31 years of age</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p008" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.008.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>382.</p>

<p>Petitioner's inference from ad of <unclear reason="illegible">admr</unclear> of sale for term</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p009" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.009.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>admitted</p>

<p>If the Jury believe from the evidence that Miss Brown sold &amp; delivered the mother of petitioner to Mrs <del>B</del> Alexander in &amp; about the year 1813, as a slave for life &amp; not for a term of years, then the will of Miss Brown is inoperative to <del>give</del> manumit the petitioner.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p010" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.010.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Deft</p>

<p>Sale for life &amp; issue born afterwards</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p011" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.011.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>But even should the Jury be of opinion that <del>the</del> no female ancestor <del>should</del> of the Petitioner was in Virginia in Oct. 1785, yet if the Jury farther find that the Petitioners mother was <del>from</del> imported in Alexandria County <del>within</del> in or about the year 1813 <del>th</del> &amp; that the Petitioner was born within twelve moths after such Importation, then the Petitioner <del>was born a slave</del> is not entitled to recover under the <bibl type="code">first section of the act of 1792</bibl></p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p012" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.012.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Deft</p>

<p><del>No applic</del></p>

<p>Importation</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p013" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.013.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>refused</p>

<p>But if the Jury believe that said statements of said Alexander were made alone in reference to the will of Parson Brown, then it is not competent for the Jury to infer from said statements that Mrs Alexander had no greater estate than a term of years in the Petitioner</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p014" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.014.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Instruction</p>

<p>Parson Brown will</p>

<p>A</p>

<p>admission made, <unclear reason="illegible">Soley</unclear> in reference to Parson Browns will made by administrator</p>

<p>Defendant</p>

<p>Refused</p>

<p>Parson Brown</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p015" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.015.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>admitted.</p>

<p><del>That</del> If the Jury believe that the mother of the Petitioner was sold by Miss Brown to Mrs Alexander for a term of years, without any agreement that the issue thereafter born should be entitled to freedom at any future time,  &amp; if they farther find that the Petitioner was born after said sale &amp; before the expiration of the term of servitude then he is not entitled to recover</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p016" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.016.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Deft</p>

<p>Sale for term &amp; issue born to them</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p017" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.017.jpg"/>

<div2 type="body">

<p>refused</p>

<p><del>That</del> if the Jury believe from <del>the</del> evidence, that Elizabeth Brown did in or about the year 1813 <del>sold &amp; delivered</del> sell &amp; deliver the mother of the Petitioner to Mrs Alexander, absolutely for life, &amp; <del>without</del> not for a term of years, then the said will of Miss Brown is not competent testimony in this cause &amp; is not to be considered by the Jury.</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p018" facs="oscys.case.0179.011.018.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Ins. as to non admissibility of Miss B's will after proof that Milly was sold for life</p>

<p>refused</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
