<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.report.0053.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Rachael Brent v. John Armfield. Circuit Court Report</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2014</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.report.0053.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0453</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Reports of Cases Civil and Criminal in the United States Circuit Court of the District of Columbia, from 1801 to 1841</title>
<author n="Cranch, William, 1769-1855">William Cranch</author>
<publisher>Little, Brown and Company</publisher>
<biblScope>Volume IV</biblScope>
<date when="1852">1852</date>
<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Court Report</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1835-10">October 1835</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.000904">Buckner, Ariss</term>
<term xml:id="per.000064">Thruston, Buckner, 1763-1845</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Virginia</term>
<term>Washington County (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>          
 
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Brent, Rachael</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000866">
<persName>Armfield, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.000001">
<persName>Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.002883">
<persName>Taylor, Robert I.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>
<change when="2016-08-01" who="#kln">reviewed; edited</change>             
<change when="2016-07-19" who="#snc">transcribed; encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p579" facs="oscys.report.0053.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption"> 

<p>Negro Rachel Brent v. John Armfield.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="syllabus"> 

<p>A person cannot be a resident of two States at the same time.</p>

<p>In order to protect the title of a sojourner to his slave, brought in under the <bibl type="code">4th section of the Maryland Act of 1796, c. 67</bibl>, it is not necessary that he should bring the slave with him.</p>

<p>The title of the defendant to the slave is not protected by the 4th section of the act, if he suffer the slave to remain two years after he himself has returned.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>This was a petition for freedom</p>

<p>The defendant claimed under Mr. Ariss Buckner, of Virginia.</p>

<p>The petitioner claimed freedom by having been brought into

<pb xml:id="p580" facs="oscys.report.0053.001.002.jpg"/>

the county of Washington, D.C., by Mr Buckner, from Virginia, to reside, or for sale, contrary to the <bibl type="code">1st section of the Maryland Act of 1796, c. 67</bibl>.</p>

<p>The defendant claimed a right to bring in his slaves, under the 2d section of the act; as being a person coming into Washington with a <term>bonâ fide</term> intention of settling therein; and if not with intention to settle in Washington, he claimed the right, under the 4th section, as a sojourner.</p>

<p>The court, (Thruston, J., absent,) at the prayer of Mr. Key, for the petitioner, instructed the jury that Mr. Buckner could not be a settled and <term>bonâ fide</term> resident in Virginia and Washington at the same time, within the meaning of the 2d section of the act; and that, in order to find for the defendant upon that section, they must be satisfied, by the evidence, that when he removed to Washington he intended to renounce his residence in Virginia, and become a <term>bonâ fide</term> resident of another place.</p>

<p>Mr. Taylor then prayed the Court to instruct the jury, that if, from the evidence aforesaid, the jury should believe that the said Ariss Buckner removed to Washington as a sojourner, then he was not entitled, under the <bibl type="code">4th section of the Maryland Act of 1796, c. 67</bibl>, to import the petitioner, unless he brought her with him for his own use at the time of his removal.</p>

<p>Which instruction, the Court refused to give; but, at the prayer of Mr. Key, for the petitioner, instructed the jury in substance, that the defendant was not protected under the said 4th section of that act, if the said Ariss Buckner returned and removed his family to Virginia in December, 1830, and left the petitioner hired out in Washington till June, 1832, and did not attempt to remove her until that time when he sent for her.</p>

<p>Mr. Key, for the petitioner. Mr Taylor, for the defendant.</p>

<p>Verdict for the petitioner.</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
