<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0416.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Daniel Wells v. Benjamin F. Lewis. Affidavit of P. R. Fendall</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0416.002</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0443</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Affidavit of P. R. Fendall</title>
<date when="1823-11-15">November 15, 1823</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 2</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Affidavit</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1824-11">November 1824</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001183">Ashton, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.003328">Casanave, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.003329">Morsell, Richard I.</term>
<term xml:id="per.000473">Randall, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.003330">Shorter, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.002176">Soper, Nathan</term>
<term xml:id="per.000499">Wells, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.003322">Wells, Kitty</term>
<term xml:id="per.003323">Wells, Monica</term>
<term xml:id="per.003324">Wells, Rachael</term>
<term xml:id="per.002602">Young, Nicholas</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Montgomery County (Md.)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Washington County (D.C.)</term>
<term>Alexandria (Va.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson> 
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.003326">
<persName>Wells, Daniel</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.003327">
<persName>Lewis, Benjamin F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001002">
<persName>Fendall, Philip Ricard, 1794-1868</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>    
<change when="2017-06-01" who="#kln">changed Morsell middle initial from J to I</change>
<change when="2016-09-21" who="#lkw">added xml:ids</change>           
<change when="2016-07-01" who="#snc">reviewed</change>  
<change when="2016-06-13" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0416.002.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>To the Honorable the Judges of the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia sitting at Alexandria</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>In obedience to an order of your Honors assigning me counsel for Daniel Wells, who has petitioned to sue, in forma pauperis, for his freedom, in your Honorable Court, and requiring me to report on his face, I report.</p>

<p>That a commission has issued from this Court sitting at Washington, directed to Richard I. Morsell Esq. to take depositions in the case of Rachael Shorter and others against Ann Cazenave, and that the depositions are expected during the present term. The Plaintiffs in that case claim their freedom as direct descendants of one Ann Wells, a white woman, under whom the petitioner Daniel also claims. I have conversed with Messrs Ashton, and Randall, the counsel for the Plaintiffs in Washington, and from their statements connected with the information derived from the petitioner's mother, I <del>found</del> am of opinion that the petitioner Daniel is the son of Monica, that Monica is the daughter of Rachael, that Rachael was the daughter of Kitty, that Kitty was the daughter of the said Ann Wells, and that the said Ann Wells was a white woman. I have also been furnished by Mr. Nicholas Young, who sold the petitioner to the Defendant, with the two annexed affidavits. Nothing affirmative affecting the present case appears in these affidavits, except Mr Soper's statement <del>was a dark mula</del> that Rachael was a dark mulatto and had short woolly hair. The former of these circumstances seems to indefinitely stated to authorize any precise inference, and the latter rather to operate in Favor of the petitioner's claim, it being, I understand, the opinion of some eminent physiologists that the child's chair resembles the father, and the said

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0416.002.002.jpg"/>

Ann Wells having certainly been a white woman, Capt. Randall informed me that before bringing the suit at Washington, he had satisfied himself in regard to this fact by sundry affidavits, and also that some of her posterity for one or two generations, I do not exactly remember which, were those from whom the petitioner Daniel claims to be descended. The subsequent <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> on the claim of descent can, I am informed by the petitioner's mother, be proved by competent testimony in the counties of Montgomery and Prince Georges in Maryland, and in Washington County in the District of Columbia, but I have, of course, had hitherto no opportunity to prosecute the investigation.</p>

<p>On the whole, after considering the facts and circumstances argued on each side of the petition, and respecting in the same degree, as to their authority, the statements made on behalf of the petitioner, with the annexed informed affidavits on the other side, I am of opinion that the petitioner claims his freedom on probable grounds.</p>

<p>All which is respectfully submitted.</p>

<p>P.R.Fendall<lb/>
Alexandria Novr. 15, 1823</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="back">

<p>David Wells's petition for freedom</p>

<p>Report of Counsel</p>

<p>Copyed Depos. for deft. &amp; Cert &amp; Seal $1.25</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
