<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0008.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Mahoney v. John Ashton. Deposition of Mary Crawford</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0008.005</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0481</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Deposition of Mary Crawford</title>
<date when="1796-06-01">June 1, 1796</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgments)</collection>
<idno>MSA S498-220</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Deposition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1799-05">May 1799</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004570">Crawford</term>
<term xml:id="per.004569">Crawford, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.001522">Craufurd, David</term>
<term xml:id="per.004571">Cross, Ann Joyce</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.004476">
<persName>Mahoney, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.000215">
<persName>Ashton, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>  
<change when="2017-07-21" who="#kln">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.005.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Charles Mahoney<lb/>
vs<lb/>
John Ashton</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in the General Court</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The deposition of Mary Craufurd aged Eighty Seven years or thereabouts being first Sworn in the above suit on the Holy evangells of almighty god. Answered the several Questions as follow to wit</p>

<p>1st Question. Do you know the parties in the above suit</p>

<p>Answers. She does not.</p>

<p>2d Question. Did you Know a Woman by the name of Ann Joyce who formerly belonged to Henry Darnall and who is said to have died at the Woodyard</p>

<p>Answers. She does not.</p>

<p>3d Question. Do you Know or have you heard that Francis Hall of Prince George's County deceased or his father Benjamin Hall in his lifetime; at any time and when; did say: that Joyce before mentioned was free or entitled to be free and for what reason; relate any Conversation that you may have heard from them or either of them or any other person on the Subject</p>

<p>Answers. That she has never heard Benjamin Hall or Francis Hall say any thing on the subject but that she has heard; her Mother: say there was a Woman by the name of Joyce came in with Lord Baltimore and that she; her mother; dose say the said Ann Joyce or any of her Children would be free if they made any stir to obtain their freedom that the said Joyce always lived in the family with Mr Darnall as she was informed and that Frank a Carpenter was son to the said Joyce and Servant to Mr Darnall that this deponants

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.005.002.jpg"/>

husband had hired the said Frank and two others of Mr Darnall to build him a dwelling house</p>

<p>4th Question. Do you Know <del>and</del> or have you heard and from whom that Joyce or Ann Joyce the woman alluded to in the second Question came from England and when: and whether she ever resided in England and how long: and do you recollect ever to have heard who were passengers with the said Joyce at the <del>????</del> Time she came from england.</p>

<p>Answers. She Knews nothing more than she has declared in her answer to the 3rd Question</p>

<p>5 Question. Do you Know <del>and</del> or have you heard and from whom that the before mentioned Joyce was ever adjudged in Prince Georges County Court to serve for a Term of years for having bastard children</p>

<p>Answers. She does not Know</p>

<p>6 Question. Do you Know or have you heard and from whom How many Children the said Joyce had; what were their names and in whose possession did they respectively die. and when. and did you or do you know any of the grand Children of said Joyce and to whom did they or do they belong respectively.</p>

<p>Answers. She did not nor does not Know.</p>

<p>7 Question. Do you Know or have you heard of any Conversation which have at any time passed respecting Charles right or the Right of his Mother Grand Mother or great grand Mother or any of his Ancestors to freedom when and between whom. what was the Conversation. relate it fully and freely</p>

<p>Answers. She does not Know nor has she heard of any conversation.</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.005.003.jpg"/>

<p>8th Question. Do you know and from whom that one of the children of Ann Joyce by the name of Ann Joyce Cross was bound to John Chaplaine in the year 1701 by Prince George's County Court</p>

<p>Answers She does not Know</p>

<p>9th Question. Do you Know and have you heard and from whom what became of Ann Joyce Cross mentioned in the preceeding Question and how and for what reason and on what Account She was bound out by Prince Georges County Court</p>

<p>Answers. She does not Know</p>

<p>10th Question. Have you any farther Knowledge Concerning the right of the Petitioner or of any of his Ancestors to freedom if you have relate it fully and freely.</p>

<p>Answers. She has not</p>

<p>Sworn to before me the subscriber one of the Associate Justices of Prince Georges County Court this 17th day of October 1792</p>

<p>David Craufurd Associate Justice for P. G. County Court</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.mdcase.0008.005.004.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>7 1/2 sides</p>

<p>1</p>

<p>Mahoney<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Ashton</p>

<p>The depostion of Mary Craufurd.<lb/>
(her mother <gap extent="three words" reason="illegible"/> family would <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> their freedom)</p>

<p>filed 1 June 1796</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
