<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.008">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Teresa Shorter v. Anne Chunn. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.008</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0523</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1795-05">May 1795</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-24 JG 27</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1795-05">May 1795</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005277">Rozer, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.005276">Shorter, Basil</term>
<term xml:id="per.005289">Shorter, Charity</term><!-- child of Teresa Shorter; enslaved by Anne Chunn -->
<term xml:id="per.005217">Shorter, Elizabeth</term><!-- family of Teresa Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005290">Shorter, Henny</term><!-- child of Teresa Shorter; enslaved by Anne Chunn -->
<term xml:id="per.005291">Shorter, John</term><!-- child of Teresa Shorter; enslaved by Anne Chunn -->
<term xml:id="per.005292">Shorter, Moses</term><!-- child of Teresa Shorter; enslaved by Anne Chunn -->
<term xml:id="per.005293">Shorter, Phillis</term><!-- child of Teresa Shorter; enslaved by Anne Chunn -->
<term xml:id="per.002691">Simms, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005252">
<persName>Shorter, Teresa</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.005071">
<persName>Chunn, Anne</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-07-16" who="#kln">reviewed and edited transcription; encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p042" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Teresa Shorter.<lb/>
against<lb/>
Anne Chunn.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore towit on the Twelfth day of January in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two; Teresa Shorter by Gabriel Duvall her attorney, preferred and filed in the General Court here, her Petition for Freedom, for herself and her Five children, which is in form following towit. To the honorable the Judges of the General Court: The Petition of Teresa Shorter, humbly sheweth that she, together with her Five children are held in Slavery by Mrs Anne Chunn of Charles County, altho' she is entitled to her Freedom, being descended in the female line from Elizabeth Shorter a Free white woman. She therefore prays your honors, the premises considered to discharge her from further custody, &amp; in the mean time to grant to your Petitioner an order to prevent her present Mistress from selling her out of the State. And she will pray. G. Duvall. 12th Jan. 1792.</p>

<p>Thereupon, it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Summons issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the Petition aforesaid of the said Teresa Shorter, which was accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland towit, To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. You are hereby commanded to summon Anne Chunn late of Charles County, that all delays and excuses be set aside she be and appear before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of May next, to answer unto the Petition of Teresa Shorter, preferred against her for Freedom: Hereof she is not to fail, and fail not at your peril, and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Twenty ninth day of December in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety one. Issued the 12th day of January 1792. (G. Duvall) John Gwinn Clk.</p>

<pb xml:id="p043" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.002"/>

<p>At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, being the day of the return of the said aforegoing writ of Summons, comes into the General Court here the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, And the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Summons was inform aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here, thus endorsed towit, "Non Est. James Simmes, Sheriff." Thereupon, it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Summons again issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer into the Petition aforesaid of the said Teresa Shorter, which is accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland towit, To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. You are hereby commanded to Summon Anne Chunn late of Charles County, that all delays and excuses be set aside she be and appear before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of October next, to answer unto the Petition of Teresa Shorter preferred against her for Freedom; Hereof she is not to fail, and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Thirtieth day of June in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two. Issued the 6th day of July 1792. G.D. Jno Gwinn Clk. At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two, being the day of the return of the said last aforegoing writ of Summons, comes into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, And the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Summons was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here, thus endorsed towit. "Summoned, James Simmes, Sheriff. And the said Anne Chunn, although so forewarned, does not come, but makes default; Thereupon, on motion of the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Attachment issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the State of Maryland for her contempt in not appearing according to the command of the said Summons, after being thereto legally summoned; which is accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff

<pb xml:id="p044" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.003"/>

of Charles County, in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct. To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. You are hereby commanded to Attach Anne Chunn and her safe keep so that you have her body before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of May next, to answer unto the State of Maryland, touching a certain contempt by her committed in not appearing to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter preferred against her for the Freedom, after being thereto legally summoned: Hereof fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court of the nineteenth day of November in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two. Issued the 22d day of December 1792. GD. Jno Gwinn Clk. At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three, being the day of the return of the said aforegoing writ of Attachment, comes again into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Attachment was inform aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed towit. "Non Est James Simmes, Sheriff Thereupon, on motion of the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Attachment again issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the State of Maryland for her contempt in not appearing according to the Command of the Summons aforesaid, after being thereto legally summoned; which is accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct. To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. You are hereby commanded to Attach Anne Chunn and her safe keep so that you have her body before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of October next, to answer unto the State of Maryland touching a certain contempt by her committed in not appearing to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter, preferred against her for Freedom, after being thereto legally summoned: Hereof fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Fifteenth day of June in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and

<pb xml:id="p045" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.004"/>

ninety three. Issued the 18th day of July 1793. (G.D.) Jno Gwinn Clk. At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three, being the day of the return of the said last aforegoing writ of Attachment, comes again into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Attachment was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed towit. "Non Est, James Simmes, Sheriff." Thereupon, on motion of the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, it is ordered by the court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Attachment again issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the State of Maryland for her contempt in not appearing according to the command of the Summons aforesaid, after being thereto legally summoned; which is accordingly issued, directed to Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting, you are hereby commanded to attach Anne Chunn and her safe keep so that you have her body before the General Court, to be held at the City of Annapolis on the Second tuesday of May next, to answer unto the State of Maryland, touching a certain contempt by her committed in not appearing to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter, preferred against her for Freedom, after being thereto legally summoned; Hereof fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Twelfth day of November in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three. Issued the 12th day of November 1793. (G.D.) Jno Gwinn Clk. At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, being the day of the return of the said last aforegoing writ of Attachment, comes again into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles County, to whom the said writ of Attachment was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed towit. "Non Est. James Simmes, Sheriff." Thereupon, on motion of the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, it is ordered, by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Attachment again issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the

<pb xml:id="p046" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.005"/>

State of Maryland for there contempt in not appearing according to the command of the Summons aforesaid, after being thereto legally summoned; which is accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct. To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting, You are hereby commanded to attach Anne Chunn, and her safe keep so that you have her body before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis in the Second tuesday of October next, to answer unto the State of Maryland, touching a certain contempt by her committed in not appearing to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter, preferred against her for Freedom after being thereto legally summoned: Hereof fail not at your peril, and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Thirty first day of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety four. Issued the 17th day of June 1794. (G. Duvall) Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, being the day of the return of the said last aforegoing writ of Attachment, comes again into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Attachment was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here, thus endorsed towit. "Non Est. James Simmes, Sheriff. Thereupon on motion of the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Attachment again issue against the said Anne Chunn to answer unto the State of Maryland for his contempt in not appearing according to the command of the Summons aforesaid, after being thereto legally summoned; which is accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. You are hereby commanded to attach Anne Chunn and her safe keep so that you have her body before the General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of May next, to answer unto the State of Maryland, touching a certain contempt by her committed in not appearing to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter, preferred against her for Freedom, after being thereto legally summoned: Hereof fail not at your peril, and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable

<pb xml:id="p047" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.006"/>

Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of the said Court the Tenth day of February in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety five. Issued the 10th day of February 1795. (G.D.) Jno Gwinn Clk. And now at this day towit, the said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety five, being the day of the return of the said last aforegoing writ of Attachment, comes again into the General Court here, the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ of Attachment was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed, towit. "Non Est. Joseph Green, Sheriff. Nevertheless, the said Anne Chunn by Philip Barton Key her attorney voluntarily comes into the General Court here, and defends the force and injury, when andsoforth; Whereupon, the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid again that the Depositions taken and filed in the case Basil Shorter against Henry Rozier be received as evidence in this cause; which said Depositions are in form following towit. (Here insert them from Liber JG No. &#160; folio 242 &amp;ca. Basil Shorter against Henry Rozier, Judgment October Term 1794.) And thereupon the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid agree to submit this case to the decision of the Court here on the Testimony filed in Court here in this Case: Whereupon all and singular the premises between the parties aforesaid by the Court here being seen, heard and fully understood, and mature deliberation thereupon had, for that it appears to the Court here, that the said Teresa Shorter the petitioner aforesaid, is entitled to her Freedom, being descended in the female line from Elizabeth Shorter a Free white woman, as she by her petition to the Court here hath alleged: Therefore it is considered by the Court here, that the said Teresa Shorter the petitioner aforesaid, and her Five children towit, Phillis, John, Moses, Charity and Henny be free and discharged of and from the service of the said Anne Chunn; And that she the said Teresa Shorter the petitioner aforesaid, and her Five children towit, the said Phillis, John, Moses, Charity and Henry go thereof discharged, and soforth. And it is further considered by the Court here, that the said Teresa Shorter, the petitioner aforesaid, recover against the said Anne Chunn the quantity of</p>

<p>by the Court here, unto her the said Teresa Shorter on her assent adjudged,

<pb xml:id="p048" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.008.007"/>

for her costs and charges by her about the prosecution of her Petition aforesaid, laid out and expended; and that she have thereof her Execution andsoforth. Test John Gwinn Clk</p>

<p>(vide, May Term 1796. Liber JG. No. &#160; Folio 743.)</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
