<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0020.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Adam v. Andrew F. Leverton. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hayes, Sophia F." xml:id="sfh">Sophia F. Hayes</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L. " xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0020.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0674</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1789-09-08">September 8, 1789</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Eastern Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S482-7, S482-12</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1789-09">September 1789</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.006987">Chitham, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006996">Clayton, Solomon</term>
<term xml:id="per.006986">Costin, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.006988">Costin, Elizabeth</term>
<term xml:id="per.006995">Costin, Hannah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006989">Costin, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.006990">Costin, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006991">Costin, Nancy</term>
<term xml:id="per.006992">Costin, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006997">Costin, Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.007000">Costin, Susanna</term>
<term xml:id="per.006922">Earle, James, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006994">Emory, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.006998">Seney, Jonathan</term>
<term xml:id="per.006999">Sherwood, Hugh</term>
<term xml:id="per.007001">Tomlinson, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.007002">Wright, Solomon</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">    
<term>Queen Anne's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Easton (Md.)</term>
<term>Wilmington (Del.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Dismissed</term>
<term>Appealed by Petitioner</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006982">Adam</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.006983">Leverton, Andrew Foster</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.004871">Wright, Robert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.006985">Tilghman, James</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>   
<change when="2023-07-14" who="#kln">Reviewed, edited.</change>            
<change when="2023-06-09" who="#sfh">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" n="IMG_8199.jpg"/>

<p>Negro Adam<lb/> 
against<lb/>
Andrew F. Leverton</p>

<p>Be it remembered that Negro Adam to the Court 
here prefers the following Petition Towit, To the 
Honorable the Judges of the General Court of the state 
of Maryland for the Eastern Shore of said state now 
sitting. The Petition of negro Adam most humbly 
sheweth that he is illegally detained in slavery by a certain Andrew Foster Leverton
of Queen Anns County planter. He therefore prays your Honors to direct a subpoena 
out of your said to command said Andrew Foster Leverton to appear immediately
and answer to the above complaint and that your Honors will take the premises into
your human consideration and give your petitioner an early hearing in the premises
and do therein what may be consistent with law and Justice and as is duty bound &amp;c</p>

<p>Robert Wright pro plff.<lb/>
Adam</p>

<p>which petition being read and granted. It is by the said Court ordered that a summons
issue against the said Andrew Foster Leverton for his immediate appearance
to answer the Complaint of the aforesaid Petitioner which said summons being
issued and return being made of the same by Jonathan Seney Sheriff of Queen
Ann's County for the time being that he had summoned the aforesaid Andrew Foster
Leverton to appear and answer according to the exigence of the same summons
and thereupon at the same Court came the aforesaid Andrew Foster Leverton
by James Tilghman his attorney agreeable to the said summons Thereupon
day was given as well to the said Negro Adam as the said Andrew Foster
Leverton by their attorneys aforesaid <unclear>to him</unclear> allegations and Evidence as well on 
the part and behalf of the said Negro Adam as the said Andrew Foster Leverton
of and upon the premises aforesaid untill the second Tuesday of September next
following; At which day towit the second Tuesday of September Anno Domini
one thousand seven hundred and eighty nine comes again as well the said negro
Adam by his attorney aforesaid as the said Andrew Foster Leverton by his 
attorney aforesaid. Whereupon all said singular the premises aforesaid &amp;
the Allegations and Evidences as well on the part and behalf of the said Negro
Adam as the said Andrew Foster Leverton being by the Court have seen heard 
and fully understood and mature deliberation thereupon had It is considered 
by the Court here that the Petition be <sic>dissmissed</sic> and that the said negro Adam
return to the service of Andrew Foster Leverton his master again.</p>

<p>James Earle</p>

<p>And the said negro Adam by his attorney aforesaid prays that he may appeal

<pb xml:id="p002" n="IMG_8200.jpg"/>

from the Judgment aforesaid of the Court here to the States High Court of Appeals
and to him the same is granted by the Judges here: and it is ordered by the Judges
aforesaid that the Record and proceedings aforesaid together with all things relating
to the same be transmitted to the high court of appeals aforesaid that the Judges of the
said court may further proceed therein as to Justice appertains and soforth.
And be it remembered that the following State of the case was filed of Record 
at the Trial of the above cause.</p>

<p>Negro Adam<lb/> 
against<lb/>
Andrew Foster Leverton</p>

<p>Petition for Freedom</p>

<p>This cause is submitted to the Court on the following
State of facts. John Costin the late proprietor
of negro Adam in March seventeen hundred and eighty four, made his 
will a copy whereof is hereto annexed as part of the case and shortly after 
died That Elizabeth Costin his widow and executive proved the said will 
and took upon herself the Burthen of the Execution thereof by taking 
Letters Testamentary and proceeding to the settlement of the Estate That the 
said Elizabeth Costin shortly after moved to Wilmington in the Delaware 
State towit in seventeen hundred and eighty five, and carried with her negro 
Adam the Petitioner, that the said Elizabeth Costin shortly after her
removal to Wilmington intermarried with a Certain Joseph Tomlinson
of Wilmington in said state where she has continued to reside ever since
her first removal, that she before her marriage aforesaid and she &amp;
said Tomlinson after the intermarriage aforesaid kept the said negro 
Adam in the state of Delaware for the space of one year and nine
months in the whole after which the said Tomlinson and wife brought
the said negro Adam to Maryland to reside and remain in said state
and hired the said negro Adam with the farm devised in the said will 
of the said Tomlinson and wife to said Andrew Foster Leverton for and 
during the year seventeen hundred and eighty eight, and also during 
the year seventeen hundred and eighty nine, where he still is. That 
the Estate of the said John Costin is not yet settled that taxes have 
been paid in this State regularly for said Adam during his twenty
one months Residence in Delaware and still are, that the 
personal Estate of said John Costin is not sufficient to pay all his 
debts but his real and personal Estate fully sufficient</p>

<p>Robert Wright pro petr<lb/>
Ja Tilghman for Joseph Tomlinson &amp; wife<lb/>
Extr of John Costin who claims as Exr and 
for A <sic>H</sic> Leverton</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" n="IMG_8201.jpg"/>

<p>and the following will of John Costin referred to in the aforegoing case as being annexed
thereto being also filed of Record in this Cause. In the name of God amen
I John Costin of Queen Anns County in the State of Maryland, being greatly
afflicted and weak in body but of sound and disposing mind memory and understanding 
and knowing the <sic>uncertaintty</sic> of human life and the certainty of death, do therefore
for the purpose of settling my temporal affairs and of being better prepared for
the time when it shall please God to call me, make this writing as and for my 
last will and Testament hereby revoking all former and other will by me made
Imprimis. I hereby resign my soul into the hands of Almighty God in hope of a 
Joyful Resurrection at the last day thro the merits and meditation of my blessed Savior
and Redeemer Jesus Christ our lord and my body to be decently buried at the Discretion
of my Executive hereafter named and as to such <sic>worldy</sic> Estate wherewith it hath pleased
God to bless me I give and dispose thereof in manner following. I do will and devise
that the whole Rents and profits of my real and personal Estate shall be applied by my
Executrix hereafter named to the payment &amp; and Discharge of my lawful debts and
to the support and <sic>maintainance</sic> of herself and my four children until my said
debts are discharged not to exceed seven years from the day of my decease. Item after
my lawful debts are paid and discharged, in manner aforesaid. I give and devise unto 
my dear wife Elizabeth Costin all my part of a tract of Land called Kendal containing
one hundred acres with my Dwelling plantation and all the Improvements thereon  
for and during the Term of her natural
Item I give and bequeath unto my 
two Daughters Susan and Hannah all that part of a tract of Land called Timber 
neck or Timberland which I purchased of Rachel Chitham and all that part of 
a Tract of Land called Coursey's Addition whereof I stand sured and possessed (and 
also the Residual and remainder of the parcel of Land called Kindal and my
Dwelling plantation and of my Estate therein whensoever happening by and after
the death of my wife) to be equally divided between my said two Daughters and the
Issue of their Respective Bodies lawfully begotten forever but if either of my 
said Daughters should die without Issue as aforesaid then I will and devise
the lands before devised to my Daughter who should so die without Issue as aforesaid
and also the Residue and Remainder aforesaid whensoever happening unto my Daughter 
Ann and the Issue of her Body lawfully begotten forever and for want of 
such Issue to my Daughter Sarah and the heirs of her Body Lawfully begotten
forever. and if both my said Daughters Susanna and Hannah should die without
Issue as aforesaid then I will and devise all my Lands Tenements and the residue 
and remainder aforesaid whensoever happening to my Daughters Sarah and

<pb xml:id="p004" n="IMG_8202.jpg"/>

Ann and the issue of their Bodies lawfully begotten respectively to be equally
divided between them and to the survivor of them and the issue of such survivor
lawfully begotten of her body forever. And <unclear>pursuant</unclear> of such Issue to my nephew
Henry Costin the son of Richard Costin and his heirs forever. Item. I give and 
devise my whole personal Estate of what nature soever after my just debts are 
discharged in manner aforesaid to be equally divided between my aforesaid wife
and two Daughters Sarah and Ann and their assigns forever. but if either
of my Daughters shall die before the age of sixteen or day of marriage then,
that the survivor shall have the sisters part thereof to her and her assigns forever
Item. in order to raise the Portions of my two Daughters Sarah and Ann
nearer to an Equality with their sisters Landed Estate It is my will and
desire that the Rents and profits of my real Estate (except the part 
thereof devised to my wife) or in Case of her death the Rents and profits of my whole
real Estate after the discharge of my Debts in manner aforesaid and the 
support and <sic>maintainance</sic> of my Daughters Susan and Hannah during
the time of three years shall be for the said term of three years added to my
personal Estate devised to my Daughters Sarah and Ann, and paid to my said
Daughters Sarah &amp; Ann by my Executrix at their age of sixteen or day of 
Marriage, but if either of them die before sixteen or day of Marriage then
the whole to be paid to the survivor of them at her age of sixteen or day of 
Marriage. Item I do hereby constitute and appoint my said wife Guardian
of my said Daughters and every of them and to have the care of their respective
Estates until they respectively arrive to the age of sixteen or day of Marriage
And Lastly I do constitute and appoint my said wife Executrix of this my 
last will and Testament. In Witness whereof I have hereto set my 
hand and seal this twenty sixth day of March seventeen hundred and eighty
four, Signed Sealed and Delivered by the Testator
and published and pronounced as and for 
his last Will and Testament in presence
of us who have signed our names as
Witnesses in his presence and at his request.</p>

<p>John Costin</p>

<p>Ann Emory Nancy Costin<lb/>
Hugh Sherwood  So Wright.</p>

<p>Queen Ann's County Sct<lb/>
the 19th day of June 1784</p>

<p>Then came Elizabeth Costin and made oath
on the holy Evangels of Almighty God, that the 
within Instrument of Writing is the true and whole will and Testament
of John Costin late of Queen Ann's County deceased, that hath come to her hands
or possession and that she doth not know of any other. Certified <unclear>ss</unclear> Sol Clayton Regr of Wills</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" n="IMG_8203.jpg"/>

<p>Queen Ann's County Sst<lb/>
the 19th day of June 1784</p>

<p>Then came Ann Emory one of the subscribing Witnesses
to the within last will and Testament of John Costin, late of 
Queen Ann's County deceased, and made oath on the holy Evangels of Almighty God, that 
she did see the Testator therein named sign and seal this will and that she heard him
publish pronounce and declare the same to be his last will and Testament that at the 
time of the so doing he was to the best of her apprehensions of sound and disposing mind
memory and understanding and that she subscribed her respective name as a Witness
to the same will and saw Nancy Costin and Hugh Sherwood subscribe their respective
names as Witness to this will in the presence and at the request of the Testator and
in the presence of each other.</p>

<p>Certified <unclear>ss</unclear> Sol Clayton Regr of Wills for Queen Ann's County.</p>

<p>Queen Anns County Sst</p>

<p>(Seal of Orphans Ct. for Q. A. Coty.)</p>

<p>In Testimony that the aforegoing is a true copy of the
last will and Testament of John Costin late of said County, (and 
the Endorsements thereon) deceased I have hereunto set my
hand and affixed the public seal of the Orphans Court for
the Court aforesaid this 12th day of June Anno Domini 1786.</p>

<p>Sol Clayton Regr of Wills
for Queen Ann's County.</p>

<p>Therefore it is ordered by the Court here that the record of the proceedings
be transmitted to the State of Maryland's high Court of appeals and they are
hereby transmitted accordingly.</p>

<p>James Earle Cl.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
