<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 
<!-- is this fine above?-->

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0013.001">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Anthony Boston v. Gassaway Rawlings. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Anna Krause" xml:id="ak">Anna Krause</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0013.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0543</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0544</idno>


<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1793-05">May 1793</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-24 JG 27</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
<!-- help me fill out above-->

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1793-05">May 1793</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.42639490">Chase, Samuel</term><!-- judge, General Court of the Western Shore -->
<term xml:id="fill in">I Toy Chase?</term>
<term xml:id="??">Boston, Anthony</term>
<term xml:id="??">Rawlins, Gassaway</term>
<!-- do I need to include people that they mention in the case?-->

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>
<!-- Do I fill in that he won? -->
</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" >
<persName>Rawlins, Gassaway</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" >
<persName>Boston, Anthony</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" >
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
<!-- Help with this-->

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019" who="#ak">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p582" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Gassaway Rawlings<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Anthony Boston</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>It being admitted that the petitioner is a discendant of Violet, the Daughter of Linah the Daughter of Maria or Marea and it appearing to the court on the examination of the despositins taken in this case that Maria or Marea was Spanish woman and that her daughter Linah was born before she came into Maryland and was of yellow colour or complexion with long black hair the court are of oppinion that the said Maria or Marea was not a slave, but free. the court order and adjudge that the petitioner be free, and discharged from all further servitude and that the said Gassaway Rawlings pay him the costs of prosecuting his petition.
</p>

<p>Test. who?</p>

<div3 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p586" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.002"/>

<div4 type="caption">

<p>Gassaway Rawlings<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Anthony Boston</p>

</div4>
<div5 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that now here on the second tuesday of May being the tenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven and ninety one the justices of Anne. Arundel county court in pursuance of the act of assembly in such case made and provided, transmit to the General court here the record and proceedings of a plaint which was lately depending before them in the said County court between Anthony Boston plaintiff and Gassaway Rawlings Defendant, and wherein the said County court gave judgement for the said Anthony Boston against the said Gassaway Rawlings, and from which said Judgement the said Gassaway Rawlings prayed an appeal into the General Court here; the terror (???) of which said record and proceedings is in the form of following to wit. Anne Arundel County set. At a county court of the state of Maryland begun and held in the City of Annapolis i and for the County aforesaid on the first Monday of November being the first day of the same month in the year 1790.
</p>

<p> Were Present
The worshipful Nicholas Worthington, Allen Luynn, John Brice, Robert Couden, Gent. Justices
Benjamin Howard Esq Sheriff Nich: Harwood Ak
In the record and proceedings of the same court is the following to wit.
</p>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.003"/>

<p>Anthony Boston<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Gassaway Rawlings</p>

<!-- This is a petition-->


<p>To the Worshipped the justives of Ann Arundel County court the petition of Anthony Boston humbly sheweth that is detained in slavery by a certain Gassaway Rawlings of the County aforesaid when he is entitled to freedom being descended from a free yellow woman being one of the Portuguies whose name your petitioner is informed was Catherine Boston. Your petitioner therefore prays your worships to take your petitioners case into consideration and discharge him from the servive of said Gassaway Rawlings and he as in duty bound will pray. 

</p>
<p>G. Durvall for ???</p>

<p>Which being nead and heard and mature deliberation therefore had it was ordered that summons us issue against Gassaway Rawlings which issued accordingly and was by Sheriff of Ann Arundel County to whome the same was directed returned thus endorsed. Summoned David Seuart. Sheriff.</p>

<p>And the said Gassaway Rawlings by William Cooke his attorney comes and defends the force and injury whereand so forth and prays leave to imparte here unto until next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also. At which said next court to wit, the second Tuesday in November seventeen hundred and eightty eight come again teh said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to in parte here unto next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>
<p>At which said next Court the first Monday in March seventeen hundred and eighty nine come again teh said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the Said</p>

<pb xml:id="p588" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.004"/>

<p>Said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparte here untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court the first Monday in March seventeen hundred and Eighty nine comes again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparte hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>It is agreed by and between the parties that the depositions of any witnesses taken on those days ntoice to the adverse party be read as evidence in this cause.
</p>

<p> At which said next court to wit the first Monday in August seventeen hundred and eighty nine come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendent by his said attorney orays further leave to imparte hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.
</p>

<p>At which said next court to with the first Monday in November seventeen hundred and eighty nine. Come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to Imparte hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit, the first Monday of march seventeen hundred and ninety come again teh said parties plaintiff and defendant by thier attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparte hereunto untill next Court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit the first Monday in August seventeen hundred and ninety come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendant</p>

<pb xml:id="p589" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.005"/>

<p>Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparte hereunto next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>The following depositions were agreed to and read as evidence in this cause.</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in Anne Arundel County Court. July 20 1789 Anne Harwood of Anne Arundel County of lawful age being first duty sworn on the holy Evangels of Almighty God touching her knowledge of the above dispute desposeth and saith that she this Deponent knew old Lenah from whom Anthony the petitioner descended that she the said Lanah has been dead about forty years and died as a part this deponents fathers estate that she lived with him as a slave and taht she this deponent never heard of said Lenah Claiming her freedom till lately that she understood said Lenah was brot into this country in a Guinea Ship amoungst other slaves and sold as such as was purchased by one Lockwood and she this deponent has been informed who will'd her to Mrs Hones the grandmother to this Deponent which Mrs Jones left her by will to Gassaway Wathins farther to this deponent that her complexion was yellow and her hair strait and black that this deponent Never understood said woman was a portugea nor knew what Country she came from and that Anthony Boston was the son of Violet who was the daughter of Lenah and further this Deponent saith not. Sword this 20th July before me one of the justices of Ann. Arundel County
</p>
<p>James Disney.</p>

<p>Elizabeth Rawlings of Lawful age of Ann Arundel County being duly sworn in the dispute above mentioned deposeth and saith that she knew old Lenah who foremerly belonged to Samual Lockwood upon whose death Mrs Jones the Deponents</p>

<pb xml:id="p590" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.006"/>

<p>Deponents grand mother owned her and after Mrs Jones death she belonged to this deponents father Gassaway Watkins and died his property upwards of forty years ago this deponent never heard that she claimed her freedom. That the complexion was yellow and her hair long and black and tied up it was not woolly like the hair of Negroes she never understood that she received wagers from this deponents father and further this deponent saith not. Sworn to this 20th day of July 1789 before the subscriber one of the justices of Anne Arundel County.
</p>

<p>Ja. Disney</p>

<p>Richard Watkins being of Lawful age  maketh oath that he knew Leaner who belonged to his grand mother Jones and after her descease belonged to his father and died a slave in his service that she was a dark brown Complexion always claimed as a slave and never to the knowledge or belief of Deponent ever claimed any title to her freedom This deponents father held one of her children, John Watkins another and Mrs Elizabeth Smith another who all died slaves and never as the Department believes claimed freedom. The department has heard that Leaner formerly belonged to one Lockwood and that he heard she came originally from beyond sea. This deponant saith he never heard that Leaners Mother was even in this Country that he first Knew her fifty years ago and upwards and thinks she was then sixty years of age and very Grey headed This deponent never heard of any other woman named Leaner that lived with Lockwood Mrs Jones or his this deponents father. he further saith that he has heard that Lenah was a Spainiard but dont recollect to have heard from what Country the ship Came in which she was brought to this country that he never heard that Lenah wore a golden cross at any time being asked if at the distribution of his fathers estate any of the representatives objected to take any of the descendants of Lenah from an apprehension that they might one day or other get their freedom. Ansers no; that they were fond of taking that family they being more trusty about their business.</p>

<p>Sworn in open court 10th March 1790.</p>

<pb xml:id="p591" n="oscys.mdcase.0013.001.007"/>

<p>The Deposition of Richard Richardson of Lawful age being one of the people called Quakers did solemnly Declare and affirm that he knew a woman named Leaner who lived with and was owned by Mrs. Jones a widow this affirmant thinks her name was Anne Jones.</p>

<p>This affirmant declares that he always understood and has heard that Leanor formerly belonged to one Lockwood that he always understood and has heard his father say she was imported from beyond Sea in a negro ship and was sold as a slave and up to the time after her death the said Leaner was always held as a slave this deponent says that he never of the said womans claiming freedom that she was of a dark brown complexion and this dponent thinks greatly resembled in her complexion and appearance a slave held by his father that was said to have been brought from Madegascar. This deponant further saith that his grand father owned three of Leaners children who died in his service and they were held as Slaves and never to his knowledge or belief any title to freedom This deponent know two other of her children one held by Nicholas Watkins and the other by John Galloway and they died Slaves and never as this deponent believes claimed to be free. This Deponent further says that near 20 years ago he has neard his father say that a negro man one of Learner children held by Thomas Rateleff applied to the County court of this county for freedom but that he could make nothing appear to show her was entitled to it and was order into his masters service by the Court and this Deponents thinks his father said he was wiped but is not certain. This deponent say that at the time Learner lived with Mrs Jones there was another Mulatto or swarthy woman that lived in the family but was no relation to Leaner Being asked if he knew Lenah's Mother saith he never heard she had a mother in this Country. That he knew Lenah upwards of fifty years ago and she was then an Elderly woman whom she lived with Mrs. Jones affirmed to in open Court 10th March 1790.</p>

<p>Richard Richardson</p>



</div5>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
