<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0013.031">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Boston v. John Francis Mercer &amp; Sophia Mercer. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0013.031</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0662</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1800-05">May 1800</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-35 JG 47</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1800-05">May 1800</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.006719">Bacon</term>
<term xml:id="per.006720">Batson, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.006721">Bet</term>
<term xml:id="per.006711">Boston, Anthony</term><!-- sibling of Nanny -->
<term xml:id="per.006722">Boston, Bacon</term>
<term xml:id="per.006834">Boston, Benjamin</term><!-- sibling of Maria -->
<term xml:id="per.006853">Boston, Betty</term><!-- child of Nanny; sibling of Daniel (Hall) -->
<term xml:id="per.006723">Boston, Caesar</term>
<term xml:id="per.006713">Boston, Daniel</term><!-- enslaved by Samuel Watkins - petitioner against Anne Watkins -->
<term xml:id="per.006724">Boston, Daniel</term><!-- petitioner against Henry Hall; sibling of Betty; child of Nanny -->
<term xml:id="per.006856">Boston, Daniel</term><!-- petitioner against Richard Sprigg -->
<term xml:id="per.006715">Boston, Lenah</term><!-- alt: Lenna -->
<term xml:id="per.006716">Boston, Maria</term><!-- spanish woman; free -->
<term xml:id="per.006725">Boston, Maria</term><!-- child of Lenah -->
<term xml:id="per.006846">Boston, Maria</term><!-- parent of George, Nathan, and Daniel; lived with Dr. Steuart; sibling of Ben -->
<term xml:id="per.006852">Boston, Nanny</term><!-- parent of Betty and Daniel; enslaved by Gassaway Watkins and Henry Hall; sibling of Anthony; child of Violet -->
<term xml:id="per.006726">Boston, Nat</term>
<term xml:id="per.006857">Boston, Nathan</term><!-- petitioner against Richard Sprigg -->
<term xml:id="per.006727">Boston, Ned</term>
<term xml:id="per.006728">Boston, Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006729">Boston, Simon</term>
<term xml:id="per.006730">Boston, Toney</term>
<term xml:id="per.006717">Boston, Violet</term><!-- parent of Nanny -->
<term xml:id="per.002083">Brice, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006731">Brown, Anne</term><!-- acquaintance of Betty and Nanny and Violet, George, Nathan, Daniel -->
<term xml:id="per.006732">Brown, Isaac</term>
<term xml:id="per.006733">Brown, Lucy</term>
<term xml:id="per.006734">Brown, Mark</term>
<term xml:id="per.006735">Brown, Mary</term><!-- Mulatto Moll -->
<term xml:id="per.006736">Brown, Ned</term>
<term xml:id="per.006737">Brown, Tom</term>
<term xml:id="per.004601">Bullen, J.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006738">Carr, Benjamin</term>
<term xml:id="per.002102">Chase, Jeremiah Townley, 1748-1828</term>
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.006739">Cowman, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.006740">Cruckley, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.006741">Disney, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006742">Farro, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.006743">Farro, Stephen</term>
<term xml:id="per.006744">Ferrara, Andrew</term><!-- alt: Fenander -->
<term xml:id="per.006745">Ford, Hannah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006747">Ford, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.006749">Galloway, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006750">Gibbs, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006752">Grey, Susannah</term><!-- alt: Susanna -->
<term xml:id="per.006753">Hall, Henry</term><!-- slaveholder of Nanny -->
<term xml:id="per.006858">Harwood</term><!-- Colonel -->
<term xml:id="per.006754">Harwood, Anne Watkins</term>
<term xml:id="per.005410">Harwood, Richard, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006859">Harwood, William</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Margaret Watkins -->
<term xml:id="per.006758">Hill, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.001491">Ijams, Plummer</term><!-- alt spelling Iiams -->
<term xml:id="per.006759">Jacob</term>
<term xml:id="per.006760">Jones, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.006764">Lockwood</term>
<term xml:id="per.006765">Lockwood, Robert</term><!-- Robert, not Samuel -->
<term xml:id="per.006766">Mayo, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.006767">Metcalf</term><!-- Mrs. -->
<term xml:id="per.006768">Metcalf</term><!-- Mr. -->
<term xml:id="per.006769">Metcalf, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006770">Nan</term>
<term xml:id="per.006771">Norris, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006772">Peter</term>
<term xml:id="per.001477">Quynn, Allen</term>
<term xml:id="per.006774">Ratcliff, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.006775">Ratcliff, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006776">Rawlings, Elizabeth Watkins</term>
<term xml:id="per.006712">Rawlings, Gassaway</term>
<term xml:id="per.006777">Richardson, Daniel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006778">Richardson, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006779">Richardson, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.006780">Sappington, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006781">Sellman, Jonathan, Jr.</term><!-- alt: Selman -->
<term xml:id="per.006782">Smith, Elizabeth</term>
<term xml:id="per.006783">Smith, Robert John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006785">Sprigg, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006860">Steuart</term><!-- doctor; annapolis -->
<term xml:id="per.005401">Taylor, Alice</term>
<term xml:id="per.006787">Toby</term>
<term xml:id="per.006788">Tydings, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006789">Watkins</term><!-- spouse of Ann Watkins; child of Margaret Watkins -->
<term xml:id="per.006790">Watkins, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.006791">Watkins, Dinah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006792">Watkins, Gassaway</term><!-- slaveholder of Nanny -->
<term xml:id="per.006793">Watkins, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006794">Watkins, Margaret Lamb</term>
<term xml:id="per.006795">Watkins, Margaret Gassaway</term>
<term xml:id="per.006796">Watkins, Nicholas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006797">Watkins, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006798">Watkins, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006799">Watkins, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.006861">Wayson</term><!-- Mr. in .002, Mrs here -->
<term xml:id="per.005413">Welch, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006801">Welch, Robert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
<term>London Town (Md.)</term>
<term>Queen Anne (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006854">
<persName>Boston, George</persName><!-- child of Maria; -->
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006829">
<persName>Sprigg, Richard</persName><!-- slaveholder of Nathan and Daniel -->
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006832">
<persName>Mercer, John Francis</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006855">
<persName>Mercer, Sophia</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.006805">
<persName>Jenings, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.004360">
<persName>Pinkney, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001496">
<persName>Cooke, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.004664">
<persName>Martin, Luther</persName>
</person> 
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.005384">
<persName>Sprigg, Richard, Jr.</persName>
</person> 
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-11" who="#kln">transcription and encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>George Boston<lb/>
against<lb/>
John F. Mercer &amp;
Sophia his wife Ex of<lb/>
Richard Sprigg</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit,
on the First day of November in the year of our
Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety
one; George Boston by George Jenings his
attorney produced and filed in the General
Court here his Petition against Richard
Sprigg for Freedom, the tenor whereof is in form following towit.
To the Honorable the Judges of the General Court, The Petition of George
Boston humbly sheweth, that he is detained in slavery by a certain
Richard Sprigg of Anne Arundel County when he is entitled to his
Freedom being descended from a Free yellow woman being one of the
Portuguese whose name your petitioner is informed was Lenah
Boston. Your petitioner therefore prays your Honors to take
your petitioners case into consideration and to discharge him
from the services of the said Richard Sprigg and he as in duty
bound will pray &amp;ca G. Jenings for Petr<lb/>
Whereupon, it is ordered by the Court here, that Summons issue against
the said Richard Sprigg to answer the Petition of the said George
Boston prefered against him for Freedom, which is accordingly issued
directed to the sheriff of Anne Arundel County in form following towit.
The State of Maryland towit, To the Sheriff of Ann Arundel County
Greeting: We command you that you summons Richard Sprigg late
of Ann Arundel County that all delays and excuses be set aside he
be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at
the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of May next to answer
unto the petition of George Boston prefered against him for Freedom
Hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you
then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire
Chief Judge of our said Court the 1st day of November Anno domini 1791.
Issued the 2d day of November Anno domini 1791. (G.J.) Jno Gwinn Clk
At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One
thousand seven hundred and ninety two, being the day of the return 
of the aforegoing summons, comes into the General Court here, the
said George Boston by his attorney aforesaid, and the sheriff of
Anne Arundel County to whom the said summons was in form
aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here that he
hath summoned the said Richard Sprigg to answer the petition of
the said George Boston prefered against him for Freedom, as by the
said summons he was commanded: Whereupon the said Richard
Sprigg by William Cooke, his attorney appears in Court here, and defends
the Complaint when the Court shall take the same into Consideration,
and prays leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second tuesday

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.002"/>

of October next, and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the
said George Boston also. At which said second tuesday of October
in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two,
come again into the General Court here, as well the said George
Boston by his attorney aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by
his attorney aforesaid: Whereupon the said Richard Sprigg by his
attorney aforesaid as before defends the Complaint andsoforth, and prays
leave of the Court here further to imparle until the second tuesday of
May next, and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the
said George Boston also. At which said second tuesday of May in
<sic>in</sic> the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three,
come again into the General Court here as well the said George Boston
by George Jenings, Gabriel Duvall and William Pinkney his attornies
as the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the
complaint and soforth, and prays leave of the Court here further to
imparle until the second tuesday of October next, and to him it is
granted, the same day is given to the said George Boston also.
At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One
thousand seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General
Court here, as well the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid
as the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid: Whereupon
the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the
complaint and soforth, and prays leave of the Court here further to
imparle until the second tuesday of May next, and to him it is granted
the same day is given to the said George Boston also. At which said
second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred
and ninety four, come again into the General Court here as well the
said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard
Sprigg by William Cooke and Luther Martin his attornies: Whereupon
it is agreed by and between the parties aforesaid that all the Testimony
taken in the cause of Anthony Boston against Gassaway Rawlings in
Anne Arundel County Court and removed by Appeal to this Court, and
all Testimony taken since the said Appeal, be received as Evidence
in this cause: which said Testimony is as follows towit. July 20th 1789
Anne Harwood of Anne Arundel County of lawful age being first duly
sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God, touching her knowledge of
the above dispute, deposeth and saith, that she this deponent knew
old Lenah from whom Anthony the petitioner descended, that she the
said Lenah has been dead about forty years and died as a part of
this deponents Fathers estate, that she lived with him as a slave
and that she this deponent never heard of said Lenah's claiming her
Freedom till lately, that she understood said Lenah was brought into

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.003"/>

this Country in a Guinea ship amongst other slaves and sold as such
and was purchased by one Lockwood as she this Deponent has been
informed, who willed her to Mrs Jones the Grand Mother of this
Deponent which Mrs Jones left her by will to Gassaway Watkins,
hair strait and black, that this Deponent never understood said
woman was a Portugea, nor knew what Country she came from,
and that Anthony Boston was the son of Violet who was the
daughter of Lenah; and further this deponent saith not. Sworn
this 20th July before me one of the Justices for Anne Arundel County.
Jas Disney. Elizabeth Rawlings of lawful age of Anne
Arundel County being duly sworn in the dispute above mentioned
deposeth and saith that she knew old Lenah who formerly belonged
to Samuel Lockwood upon whose death Mrs Jones the Deponents
grand mother owned her and after Mrs Jones' death she belonged to
this deponents Father Gassaway Watkins and died his property
upwards of forty years ago, this deponent never heard that she
claimed her Freedom, that the complexion was yellow and her
hair long and black &amp; tied up, it was not woolly like the hair
of negroes; she never understood that she received wages from this
Deponents Father; and further this Deponent saith not. Sworn to
this 20th day of July 1789 before the subscriber one of the Justices of
Anne Arundel County. Jas Disney. Richard Watkins being
of lawful age maketh oath that he knew Leaner who belonged to his
Grand Mother Jones and after her decease belonged to his Father
and died a slave in his service, that she was a dark brown
complexion always claimed as a slave and never to the knowledge
or belief of Deponent ever claimed any title to her Freedom this 
Deponents Father held one of her children, John Watkins, another and
Mrs Elizabeth Smith another, who all died slaves and never as the
Deponent believes claimed Freedom, the Deponent has heard that
Learner formerly belonged to one Lockwood &amp; that he has heard
she came originally from beyond sea, this Deponent saith he
never heard that Leaners mother was ever in this County, that
he first knew her fifty years ago and upwards and thinks she
was then 60 years of age &amp; very Grey headed, this Deponent never
heard of any other woman named Leaner that lived with Lockwood
Mrs Jones or his this Deponents Father: he further saith that he
has heard that Lenah was a Spaniard but don't recollect to have
heard from what country the ship came, in which she was
brought to this Country, that he never heard that Lenah wore
a golden cross at any time. Being asked if at the distribution
of his Fathers Estate any of the Representatives objected to take any
of the descendants of Lenah from an apprehension that they might

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.004"/>

one day or other get their Freedom? Answers no: that they were fond of
taking that family, they being more trusty about their business. Sworn
to in open Court 10th March 1790. The Deposition of
Richard Richardson of lawful age being one of the people called Quakers
did solemnly declare and affirm that he knew a woman named
Leaner who lived with and was owned by Mrs Jones a widow, this
affirmant thinks her name was Anne Jones, this affirmant declares
that he always understood &amp; has heard that Leaner formerly belonged 
to one Lockwood, that he always understood and has heard his
Father say he was imported from beyond sea in a negro ship
and was sold as a slave and up to the time of her death the
said Leaner was always held as a slave, this deponent says
that he never heard of  the said woman claiming Freedom that
she was of a dark brown complexion, and this deponent thinks
greatly resembled in her <sic>complection</sic> and appearance a slave
held by his Father, that was said to have been brought from
<sic>Madegascar</sic>, this deponent further saith that his Grand Father
owned three of Learners children who died in his service, and
that they were held as slaves and never to his knowledge or belief
any title to Freedom, this deponent knew two other of her children
one held by Nicholas Watkins and the other by John Galloway and
they died slaves and never as this deponent believes claimed to
be Free, this Deponent further says that near 40 years ago he
has heard his Father say that a negro man one of Leaners children
held by Thomas Ratcliff applied to the County Court of this County for
Freedom, but that he could make nothing appear to shew he was
entitled to it, and was ordered into his masters service by the Court,
and this Deponent thinks his Father said he was <sic>whiped</sic> but is not
certain, this deponent says that at the time Leaner lived with Mrs Jones
there was another mulatto or swarthy woman that lived in the family
but was no relation to Leaner: Being asked if he knew Leaners
Mother? Saith he never heard she had a mother in this Country:
that he knew Lenah upwards of fifty years ago and she was then an
elderly woman when she lived with Mrs Jones. affirmed to in
open Court 10th March 1790. Richard Richardson.</p>

<p>Plummer Iiams aged 72 years being sworn in this cause says he
has seen the petitioner and has understood that he is the son of
Violet, that he did not know Lenah and never heard she or any of
her family claimed their Freedom until Capt Thomas Watkins
was buried about then years ago when Thomas Watkins and
Samuel Watkins informed him that Daniel the property of the
said Samuel claimed his Freedom and asked the Deponent if he
knew any thing about it, and he answered he did not &amp; further

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.005"/>

saith not. Sworn to this 4th day of August 1790 in open court.</p>

<p>Mary Batson a woman of colour and born of a Free woman whose mother
was a Free white woman aged between sixty and seventy years being
first duly sworn to say the truth in this cause deposeth and saith, that
she knows Violet his mother ever since the deponent was a small Girl,
that she knew old Lenah Boston many years before she died, and that
she thinks she has been dead upwards of Forty years that this Deponent
was born in Anne Arundel County not far from the neighbourhood of
Lenah and her descendants and has always resided in Anne Arundel
that Lenah was a bright yellow woman with long black hair, which
was straight; This Deponent further saith that she has always
understood that Lenah the Grand Mother of the Petitioner was a Spanish
woman and often has heard her mother say that she was entitled to
be free. The Deponent knew several children of the said Lenah towit
Daniel, Ned, Toney, Caesar, Simon, Nat, Bacon, Violet, Sarah, Maria
She further saith that the Deponents mother was born on the Eastern
Shore as she has informed her, and that she was brought over when
young to Anne Arundel County and was brought up in the Swamp;
that she was brought up by old Robert Lockwood in the Swamp and
she has often heard her mother say that she knew the mother of
Lenah and she was a Spanish woman and that Lenah was very
young when she came into this Country with her mother, and she
has often heard her mother say that Lenahs mother died at Robert
Lockwoods in his lifetime and was buried there and that she used
commonly to wear a golden cross round her neck and that it
was buried with her; The Deponent being asked how old the
Deponents Mother was when she was born, saith she cannot tell but
that her mother had sixteen children and the Deponent was the youngest
but two; That she has frequently heard her mother say that Lenah
Mother took care of her when she was young; This Deponent further
saith that he has understood that Ned one of the sons of Lenah many
years ago attempted to get his Freedom and that he was stopped at
London Town when on his way to Annapolis and their whipt and
prevented from going further. This Deponent saith that she has heard
Ned say that he was whipped at London Town and his Indentures
burnt and that he thought he was used very ill, and has understood
that his masters name was Thomas Ratcliff and further she saith not.
Being <sic>ask</sic> if Lenahs children were born before she came to this 
country? Says no, they were all born in Maryland, This Deponent says
she is now upwards of sixty years old and can remember Lenah ever
since she was ten years old. Lenah had then <sic>then</sic> children; This
Deponent being asked how long Lenah has been dead? says near forty

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.006"/>

years. Sworn before the subscriber, this seventh day of August 1790. Allen
Quynn. The Deposition of John Welch son of Robert aged sixty two
years being duly sworn in this cause saith, that he knew old Lenah
who belonged to Gassaway Watkins and whom he got from Mrs Jones
his Mother, she was a bright yellow woman with remarkably long
black straight hair; This Deponent was young when he knew her
and has understood she was an East Indian she had many children
one of which was named Violet who was the mother of the Petitioner
this Deponent saith that Violet if living would be upwards of seventy
years of age. This Deponent knew Violet well when he was about
eleven years old and used to see her often and he thinks she
must have been about twelve or fourteen years older than himself;
This Deponent further saith that about forty seven or forty eight years ago
he heard Richard Watkins son of the aforesaid Gassaway Watkins and
in his life time curse the said old Lenah and tell her that she
wanted to be free, but that she never would and further he does 
not remember to have heard of her claiming her Freedom. Sworn
before me this 3d day of February 1791. Richd Harwood Junr.
The Deposition of Robert John Smith of Anne Arundel County aged forty
four years or thereabouts being first duly sworn on the Holy Evangelists
of Almighty God, saith that he was born in Annapolis &amp; served his
apprenticeship in the neighbourhood where Gassaway Watkins deceased
lived &amp; that he never knew the person called Lenah nor ever in his
life heard that such person or her descendants were entitled to their
Freedom until about eight or ten years since &amp; that he at no time
ever had any conversation with either John Tydings or Joseph Mayo
deceased respecting Daniel the slave of Samuel Watkins brother of
Gassaway Watkins, but that about eight or ten years ago the time
above alluded to, he recollects having a conversation with the said
Samuel Watkins the master of said Daniel in which the said Samuel
said there was a talk that the said Daniel intended to try to get
Free, but that he was quite easy about it, for that he was no more
entitled to Freedom than that Boy Jacob, alluding to a Boy then
present who was then a slave of the said Samuel &amp; Still continues
a slave in possession of his widow &amp; further this Deponent says not
Sworn Before Saml Chase. Robt J. Smith.
The Deposition of Anne Watkins of Anne Arundel County of lawful
age being first duly sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God
saith that she knows the Defendant in this suit but knew nothing
of his mother or Grand Mother; that she has often heard old people
in the neighbourhood talk about old Lenah, but does not remember
the particulars of such conversations, except one that about thirty
years ago or nearly about that time, there was a report that the

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.007"/>

descendants of some woman named Lenah intended to try to get Free, and
Mr Thomas Sprigg deceased came to the house of Margaret Watkins the
mother of this Deponents Husband &amp; with whom this deponents Husband then
lived, and asked Margaret Watkins if she had heard it, and said that
they were going to try to get Free, to which the said Margaret Watkins
Answered, that they ought to be Free, and that it was their right,
upon which Mr Sprigg told her to be still about it and said he had some of
them. This Deponent has often heard her mother in Law talk about
Lenah, and she always said she was no Slave, and that she was
not counted a slave by the family: And she further saith that her
Mother in Law has been dead about sixteen years, and was an old
woman when she died perhaps about sixty years of age; that she
was the daughter of John Lamb &amp; Elizabeth his wife who lived in
Anne Arundel County near Queen Anne, and was the wife of
Nicholas Watkins who has been dead upwards of twenty years and
this Deponent believes was eighty years old or upwards when he died:
and she has heard him say that Lenah and her family ought to be
Free. Being asked if she heard Mr Watkins or Mrs Watkins give
any reason why Lenah ought to be Free? Says she did not. Sworn
to this Fourth day of June 1791. Before Jno Brice.
The Deposition of John Tydings of Anne Arundel County aged sixty one
years or thereabouts being first duly sworn on the holy Evangels of
Almighty God, saith that he knew old Lenah who he understands
formerly lived with Robert Lockwood, and afterwards was in the family
of Mrs Jones and afterwards in that of Gassaway Watkins. that he knew
Lenah when she lived at Mr Watkins's forty odd years ago she was
a yellow woman, and the Deponent thinks he never saw a person
of her complexion before nor since she had long black straight hair
like the hair of an Indian; and he further saith that about seven
or eight years ago he happned at the House of Joseph Mayo <unclear>Senior</unclear>
late deceased, and the said Joseph Mayo mentioned that he had
heard that Mrs Watkins's  Daniel was making a move to get Free,
and asked this Deponent if he had heard it, to which he answered,
that he had, and on being asked by the said Joseph Mayo of whom
he heard it, this Deponent replied, of Robert Smith: <unclear>Ay</unclear> said
Mr Mayo Smith knows every thing; the said Joseph Mayo observed
old Lenah when she lived with one Lockwood, and that she was
as Free as he was, but did not mention how she was entitled to her
Freedom; and told this Deponent when he knew her first, he was an
Apprentice Boy to Mr John Sappington, this Deponent saith that
Daniel before mentioned is the Brother of the Petitioner and son of
Violet who the Deponent understood always was the Daughter of old

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.008"/>

Lenah and she was a yellow woman, and had some thing of the 
complexion of her mother: And the Deponent further saith that
Lenah had not the looks of a negro or mulatto, and he knew
Mareer a daughter of Lenahs who was a very yellow woman.
This Deponent lived in the neighbourhood of the aforesaid Gassaway
Watkins and often saw Lenah. Sworn to before the Subscriber
one of the Justices of Anne Arundel County this 25th day of October
1791. Jno Brice. Thomas Gibbs aged upwards of 62 years
being first sworn on the holy Evangels of Almighty God deposeth &amp;
saith that he has seen old Lenah at the time she was the property
of Mrs Jones when she appeared to this Deponent very aged, who
was himself at that time about seven years of age, that he hath
ever understood that the said Lenah was a slave &amp; never has
heard until lately that either she or her descendants were entitled
to Freedom. The Deponent further saith that he knew Mulatto
Moll, who he is informed was the mother of Mary Batson &amp; has
always understood that she came a servant out of old Lockwoods
family &amp; served her time out, in the family of old William
Richardson &amp; was then set free: This Deponent further saith that
he has known Mrs Anne Watkins ever since she was a small
Girl, that she was the reputed daughter of Parson Spencer a man
of very bad character &amp; that she lives adjoining to his plantation &amp;
is considered a great injury to the neighbourhood from her connection
with negroes: Being asked from whom he understood that Mulatto
Moll came out of Robert Lockwoods family? Answers that he
cannot particularly recollect: Being also asked from whom he
understood that Mulatto Moll was the mother of Mary Batson? Answers
That he knew Moll who he is informed now calls herself Mary Batson
when she was a small Girl at which time she lived with her mother
Mulatto Moll &amp; that he thinks the said Mary Batson is about
his age, &amp; tht he was born not more than a mile from the place
where the said Mary was born as he is informed &amp; believes. Being
asked whether the said Mulatto Moll was born Free or a Slave?
Answers that he has understood that she was born of a white mother
by a black Father. Being asked whether he knows of any connections
of Mrs Watkins with negroes other than negroes assembling at
her House to hear preaching? Answers he does not. Being asked
when &amp; in what numbers they assemble there? Says chiefly by night &amp;
understands in numbers. Being asked if he knew any of the Brothers
of Mary Batson? Answers he knew Tom &amp; Mark. Being asked whether
they were considered as slaves or Free persons? Answers that he thinks
he has understood that they were to be Freed at such an age.

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.009"/>

Being asked if Tom died in the possession of Mrs Richardson? Answers
he believes so, &amp; that he has understood that the person? Mulatto Moll
came to serve so long was by her having children by a slave.
Being asked whether Tom was worked as a slave? Answers that he
was worked in the same manner as Mr Richardsons other negroes
Being asked whether he ever heard Mr Richardson claim him as a
slave? Answers that he never heard him say any thing about him
Taken in the presence of the counsel of the parties &amp; sworn to before
me this 3d of November 1791 Jas Disney. Thos Gibbs.
Mary Cruckly aged more than seventy six years being first sworn
on the Holy Evangelists of Almighty God deposeth &amp; saith that she
was born in Anne Arundel County near the place where Rawling
Tavern now stands &amp; was carried as she has been informed &amp; believes into
the Swamp an infant at the breast where she lived adjoining the
plantation of old Robert Lockwood &amp; within one mile of his House,
until she was sixteen years of age, that she always understood Lenah
was a slave of old Robert Lockwood &amp; after his death came as such
into the possession of Mrs Jones, that the Deponents mother as she
believes was well acquainted with old Robert Lockwood &amp; his
family &amp; that from every thing she has ever heard from her mother &amp;
others during her whole life, she has been informed &amp; verily believes
that the said Lenah was a slave &amp; had no title to her Freedom &amp;
that she well remembers one of her (Lenahs) family trying to get Free
a number of years ago when it could be well proved who Lenah
was &amp; all about her &amp; she understood it was then proved that they
had no right to their Freedom. And this Deponent further saith
that she never heard of such a person as Lenahs mother being
in this Country &amp; she believes no such person ever lived in the
Swamp or on Robert Lockwoods plantation or she thinks she
must have known or heard of her. that she knew old Mulatto
Moll who she is informed was the mother of the person called
Mary Batson &amp; always understood <sic>their</sic> she served her time out
with old William Richardson, that she also knew several mulattos
who did belong to the estate of old Robert Lockwood &amp; were distributed
about after his death, towit, among others Toby, Nan, &amp; Bet who
came to old Mrs Metcalf &amp; some to Mrs Jones's &amp; some to old
William Richardson. Being asked whether she had any other
reason to believe Lenah was a slave, other than seeing her in
the possession of Mrs Jones? Answers that she has no other than seeing
her there among other slaves &amp; never hearing that she was Free,
whom she lived &amp; died as a slave. Being asked what reason she
had to believe that her mother was well acquainted with old Robert
Lockwood &amp; his family? Answers that her Father possessed &amp; lived on the

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.010"/>

plantation adjoining old Robert Lockwood's plantation &amp; that her mother
lived there about ten years before this Deponent was born, before which
time she the Deponents mother lived with her Father the Deponents 
Grand Father near where Rawlings Tavern now stands, not more
than five miles from where Robert Lockwood lived. Being asked
what age she supposed her mother was when she was married?
Answers, that she supposes she was about 18 or 19 years of age. Being
asked whether she recollects any conversation of her Father respecting
Lenah? Answers she does not recollect to have heard any. Being
asked whether she recollects from whom she heard that Toby, Nan &amp;
Bet came from old Robert Lockwoods estate? Answers that she
knew the persons, but cannot recollect particularly from whom
she heard that they came from Lockwoods estate. Being asked
how long she has known Mulatto Moll? Answers about 20 years
or more, &amp; does not believe that Mulatto Moll was older than herself.
Being asked if Mulatto Moll has been dead 8 or 10 years? Answers
she believes she has been dead 8 or 10 years &amp; that she was an old
woman when she died. Mary Cruckly her K mark  Taken in 
the presence of the Counsel of the parties &amp; sworn to before me
this 4th day of Novr 1791. Jas Disney. The Deposition of
Benjamin Carr of Anne Arundel County aged about sixty six years
being duly sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God saith that he
has known Mary Batson a witness sworn in this cause many years,
and the said Mary Batson lived with the Deponent and on his
plantation about ten years &amp; during the whole time conducted
herself honestly and behaved well, and the Deponent thinks her
honest and deserving of credit; and the Deponent never heard any
charge against the honesty or veracity of Mary Batson who has
raised several children since he knew her. Sworn to in open
Court the 16th October 1792. Jno Gwinn Clk. Benjamin
Atwell of Anne Arundel County who says he was born on the first
day of January and he thinks in the year seventeen hundred
and five, being duly sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty
God deposeth &amp; saith, that he does not remember Lenah who
formerly lived with Robert Lockwood: but he remembers some
thing of Robert Lockwood, and thinks he saw him when he the
Deponent was a small Boy: he does not remember nor does
he know any thing of Lenah nor does he remember ever to have
heard Joseph Ford or his Father talk of her; he further saith that
he knew Joseph Mayo when he was an apprentice Boy to John
Sappington: and he thinks Mayo was rather older than himself
but he does not ever recollect ever to have heard him speak of

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.011"/>

Lenah, and he knows nothing about it. Being asked if he knew Mulatto
Moll who lived with William Richardson? Says he did; And that he
knew her son Mark. Being asked if he knows at what age Mark
was set Free? Answers he thinks at the age of thirty one years.
Being asked if he knew how long Mulatto Moll has been Free?
Says he does not, but he knew her and she has not been dead many
years; he has not seen her these seven or perhaps ten years; he
further saith that he knew William Ford and his wife Hannah
Ford and was frequently at their House at reapings, but does
not remember ever to  have heard either of them mention any
thing about Lenah; he further says that he never heard Mulatto
Moll called any thing but Free Moll, and she lived in a House
between Mary Thomas's and William Richardson's when he first
knew her and he has known her for a great number of years,but
how long he cannot remember. Sworn this 21st day of May 1792.
Before Jas Disney. Benjamin Atwell his B mark.
The Deposition of Mrs Alice Taylor aged about seventy seven years
being first duly sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God saith
that she well knew old Mulatto Moll otherwise called Free Moll;
and often heard her say that she came out of the widow Lockwoods
estate into the family of old William Richardson, and served her
time out with him, and Mr Richardson afterwards settled her
on a part of his land and gave her her maintenance. Being
asked what time Moll served Mr Richardson? answers that she
did not remember how long, but from frequently hearing her call
Daniel Richardson master, asked her why she called him so, being
then Free, Moll answered and said she came from out of the swamp
from widow Lockwoods and had served her time with his Father
old William Richardson but do not remember that she heard
Moll or any other person say how long she had served; Being asked
if she knew old Lenah who lived with old Mrs Jones? Answers
that she never knew that there was such a person as Lenah;
Being asked if she knew whether Moll had any children while
she lived with Mr Richardson? Answered that she heard 
Moll often speak of her daughter Lucy who lived with old Joseph
Hill near Annapolis, that she had before she came to Mr
Richardson that she also knew Isaac, Mark Ned &amp; Tom, Mary 
Batson and Ann, but how many of the later number she had
after she came to Mr Richardsons she does not know, but she
heard Mary Batson say about two years ago thta she was far
advanced in forty and further sayeth not. Taken after due notice
to the counsel for the plaintiff Daniel Boston against Henry Hall
Defendant, and in the presence of the Defendant this Twenty
third day of June 1792. Richd Harwood Junior.

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.012"/>

Anne Brown of Anne Arundel County aged about sixty years being 
sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God deposeth and saith that
she knows Anthony the Defendant, but has not much acquaintance
with him, that she knew Vy his mother very well, and she knew
old Lenah the mother of Vy as well as she knew her own mother, that
she the Deponent is the Daughter of Mary Brown known by the
name of Mulatto Moll; that she has always understood from her
Mother that she lived in the family of old Robert Lockwood in
the Swamp in Anne Arundel County, that she was to serve the
said Robert Lockwood until she was thirty one years old, and
that when Mrs Lockwood died she was big with her first child and
she further saith that her mother has told her many times that
the mother of Lenah brought her up and took care of her when
she was small; and that she has often heard her said mother
say that the said Lenah's mother was to be Free and was a 
Spanish woman and she has also heard old Mrs Wayson say
that Lenah's mother was a Spanish woman and they some times
called her a Hispaniola woman, and the Deponent has heard
the said Wayson who lived in the swamp say she was a Free
Spanish Woman, and she has heard the said Wayson talk
many a time to her mother about getting her children Free,
and she further saith that she has heard Mary Ratcliff who was
a white woman and lived in the family of Robert Lockwood
say that Lenah's mother was a Free woman and she has heard
her say so, many a time; as she has also heard Thomas Ratcliff
Husband of the said Mary Ratcliff who also lived in the family
of Robert Lockwood say that Lenahs mother was a Free woman;
and she has also heard old Mr Metcalf in the Swamp who she
thinks was Father of the present old John Metcalf say that Lenah's
mother was a Spanish woman and Free; and she has heard the
same from his wife; and she further saith that she has heard
the aforesaid Mary Ratcliffe and the mother of the Deponent say
that Lenahs Mother wore a gold cross and gold bobs in her ears;
and she has heard the aforesaid Thomas Ratcliffe and Mary
Ratcliffe say that Lenahs mother came into this Country Free;
and had good Cloths and gold rings on her Fingers; and she has
heard the said Mary Ratcliffe Thomas Ratcliffe and the mother
of the Deponent and Lenah all say the Lenah was born before
she came to this Country: And the Deponent further saith that
she never heard any old person in the neighbourhood of the Swamp
say that Lenah's Mother was a slave, and she has often heard
them talk of her; and she further saith that she very well knew

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.013"/>

old William Foard in the Swamp, and has been at his House oftener
than she has fingers &amp; toes, and she used to go with her mother to the
said William Foard who employed the mother of the Deponent to do
sewing work for his negroes, and she has often heard the said
William Foard say that Lenah was a Spanish woman and Free;
and she has often heard the said William Foard and her mother
talk about the mother Lenah; and she has heard the said William
Foard say that Lenah was born before she came upon land and
she has heard every one say so who knew Lenah and whom she
heard speak of her, being asked if she ever heard whom William
Foard married answered she has heard he married Hannah
Galloway daughter of old Samuel Galloway; being asked if she
ever heard that William Foard was a servant to the said Samuel
Galloway answers she never did hear that he was a servant
to any one, being asked if he was a man respected and esteemed?
Answers she can't say he was a man who had a very good
living and had a good many slaves and kept a very good House:
and the Deponent says that the said William Foard got by his
said wife a negro named Peter who came out of old Robert
Lockwoods estate, as she has understood from her mother and she
has heard her said mother say that Peter's mother was her
fellow servant but a slave and further she saith not. Sworn
before the subscriber one of the Aldermen of the City of Annapolis
Bullen. Whereas the subscriber is desired to say what
I know concerning a negro named Ned Formerly belonging to ye
Widow Lockwood and now in possession of William Glover, which
is as follows, That the said Ned's Grandmother old Maria was
always deemed to be a Madargasco Slave bought by Robert
Lockwood and served as a slave during life and her Daughter
Lenna was born at ye said Lockwoods House and served as a
slave till death August ye 10th 1747. William Foard.
The Deposition of John Norris aged about seventy two years who being
duly sworn on the holy Evangels of Almighty God saith that he has
been perfectly acquainted with the hand writing of old William
Foard who formerly lived in the swamp ever since he the said
Norris was a Boy, and have seen <sic>a bundance</sic> of the said Foards
writing at various times and that the certificate hereunto annexed
(respecting a negro man named Ned formerly belonging to the widow
Lockwood and now in the possession of William Glover) bearing date
the 10th day of August 1747 and signed by the said William Foard is
all in the hand writing of the said William Foard. Taken this Eighth
day of October 1792. Before Richd Harwood Junr.

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.014"/>

This Deponent being again sworn and being asked if he knew how long
the said William Foard has been dead answered about thirty years
and he thinks not more that he does not know the age of said Foard,
but that he the said Foard had several children other than this
Deponent. This Deponent further saith that Ned above mentioned
was an old man when he died and that he died some time before
the commencement of the late war, but how long he doth not know
and that he has heard that the above Ned went to Annapolis in
order to get his Freedom but returned home without it, and understood
he served contentedly afterwards as a slave; This latter Deposition
taken in the presence of Mr Gabriel Duvall this 13th day of
October 1792. Before Richd Harwood Junr.
Margaret Gassaway Watkins of Anne Arundel County of lawful age
being sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God touching her
knowledge of the claims of the family of people called Bostons and
being asked if she had ever heard her Father John Watkins speak
of them the said Bostons and their right to Freedom? Answers she
did not, and saith also that she heard her mother on being asked
by Daniel Boston as to her Husband speak of them; that her Father
has been dead about sixteen years, and the Deponent was
young when he died. Sworn before me the 21st day of May
Sworn to before Richd Harwood Junr. Richard Hopkins son
of Philip of Anne Arundel County aged fifty three years &amp; upwards
being sworn on the holy Evangely of Almighty God touching his
knowledge of the right of the family of the Bostons to Freedom, saith
he knows nothing of them, and never heard of the name of Boston:
Being asked if he knew Ratcliffs Ned answers he did &amp; that his
Father purchased him of William Glover when the Deponent
was a small Boy: that he lived to be an old man and lived many
years after the death of his Father, that he never heard Ned claim
his Freedom, nor did he ever hear any one say any thing concerning
his Freedom, until lately; that he was yellow fellow a bright mulatto
and had long hair like a mulatto's Hair, and as long as he ever
saw mulatto's hair. Taken this 21st of May 1793. Sworn to Before
Richd Harwood Jun. Dinah Watkins of Anne Arundel
County of lawful age being duly sworn on the holy Evangels of
Almighty God deposeth and saith that she remembers Lenah a
small yellow woman in the possession of her Grand Mother Mrs
Jones: but the Deponent was then small and does not remember
to have heard any thing said about her Freedom, but seeing her
among her Grand Mothers people supposed she was a servant of

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.015"/>

her Grand Mother, what makes her remember Lenah more particularly,
she recollects she was a cripple, and was disliked by the children:
Being asked if she recollects whether Mrs Jones was a kind indulgent
mistress, or otherwise? Answers she was reckoned an indulgent mistress.
Being asked if she recollects to have heard her Husband speak of
Lenah's right to Freedom? Answers she does not. Being asked if
she recollects ever to have heard Nicholas Watkins or his wife
(which Nicholas was Father in Law to the Deponent) say any thing
about Lenah's Freedom? Answers she does not recollect to have them
or any other person ever say any thing about Lenah's Freedom.
Taken this 21st day of May 1793. Before Richd Harwood Junr.
Mary Farro wife of Stephen Farro of Anne Arundel County aged
about thirty two years being sworn on the Holy Evangely of Almighty
God to testify the truth of her knowledge respecting the claim of
the people who call themselves Bostons to Freedom, deposeth and
saith, that she has at many times heard her mother say that
she knew Lenah a small yellow woman who was lame and that
if she had her right, she was as Free as she was; and that she
understood she was a Spaniard: that she had long black hair and
resembled much a yellow man who lived with Major Jonathan
Selman whose name was Andrew Fenander and who the deponent
has understood was a Spaniard. That her mother has been dead
going on three years, was named Susanna Grey when she died, &amp; 
her maiden name was Rosenquest: Being asked if she has ever heard
her mother say where she was brought up and lived when she was
young? Answers she does not recollect; Being asked if she knew
how old she was when she died? Answers she does not know, nor does
she recollect that she has heard her mother mention her age so as to
remember it, but she was an old woman when she died. Being asked
if any person was present when she heard her mother speak as
above related? Answers her Husband Stephen Farro was present
and heard her frequently. Being asked when she first heard her
mother say so? Answers when she the Deponent was a small Girl,
and she heard her mention it about three or four years before she
died; and she heard her say she had a Husband named Bacon who
was a slave, and she wondered why she did not claim her Freedom.
Being asked if she ever heard her mother say that she lived near
Mrs Jones in Anne Arundel County? Answers she has heard her
say she lived in the neighbourhood where Lenah lived &amp; near to her.
Taken this 21st day of May 1793. Before Richd Harwood Junr.
Joseph Cowman of Anne Arundel County being one of the people
called Quakers personally appeared before the subscriber one of the
Justices of Anne Arundel County and did solemnly &amp; truly declare and
affirm that he has known Mrs Anne Watkins a witness sworn in

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.016"/>

this cause for Twenty years at least having lived within a few miles of
her, and saith that he has never heard any thing to the prejudice of
her character in any respect in his life; and has never heard of any
ill consequences arising from any persons attending at her House to
hear preaching: That the said Anne Watkins is of the society of people
called Methodists: and he believes that the meetings at her House
to hear preaching were held from religious motives. Affirmed before
me this 25th May 1793. John Randall. Thereupon further
process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid
by order of the Court here, is continued until the second tuesday of 
October next. At which said second tuesday of October in the
year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety four, come
again into the General Court here, as well the said George Boston by
his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his attornies
aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid
between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further
continued until the second tuesday of May next. At which said
second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven
hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here
as well the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said
Richard Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid: Whereupon the said George
Boston by his attornies aforesaid produced and filed in Court here the
Deposition of William Harwood, which ensues in form following towit.
William Harwood of Anne Arundel County being sworn on the Holy
Evangels of Almighty God deposeth and saith that in the year
Seventeen hundred and seventy four, as well as he recollects, he
happened in company with a Mrs Margaret Watkins an old Lady
at Colonel Harwoods and in the course of some conversation that 
passed between them she informed this Deponent that there were
some negroes in the neighbourhood entitled to be Free and that
it was her opinion they would some time or other obtain their
Freedom; he well remembers that she named negroe Daniel who
was at that time in the possession of Mr Samuel Watkins as one
of the persons who ought to be Free. This Deponent is informed
that the said negro Daniel has since the death of Samuel
Watkins been discharged and set at liberty. This Deponent has
been informed that Margaret Watkins was the wife of Nicholas Watkins
who was the son of Mrs Jones. Sworn before me one of the Justices
of the peace for Anne Arundel County this 25th day of May 1795.
Allen Quynn. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises
aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, but order of the Court here is
further continued until the second tuesday of October next.
At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord one

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.017"/>

thousand seven hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here
as well the said George Boston by his attorneys aforesaid, as the said Richard
Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid: Whereupon the said George Boston by his
attornies aforesaid, produced and filed in Court here the Deposition of Anne
Brown, which ensues in form following towit. Anne Brown of Anne
Arundel County aged sixty six years being sworn on the holy Evangely of
Almighty God deposeth &amp; saith that she knows Betty the petitioner &amp; has
known her ever since she the said Betty was a girl; she is the daughter 
of Nanny who formerly belonged to Gassaway Watkins and afterwards to
Henry Hall; that the said Betty is sister of Daniel who obtained his
Freedom on a petition against said Henry Hall; that she knew Nanny
aforesaid before she had any children; she is sister of Anthony Boston
who obtained is Freedom on petition against Gassaway Rawlings,
and is daughter of Violet whom the Deponent knew before the
aforesaid Nanny was born; Violet belonged to the aforesaid Gassaway
Watkins, and was the reputed daughter of Lenah Boston whom
the Deponent knew when she the Deponent was a Girl, that the
Deponent always understood that Violet aforesaid was the daughter of
Lenah and she never heard it contradicted. That the Deponent
knows George Boston, Nathan Boston &amp; Daniel Boston who petitioned
against Richard Sprigg, they are sons of Maria who some years ago
lived with Dr Steuart in Annapolis: that the aforesaid Maria is sister
of Ben who obtained his Freedom against the aforesaid Richard
Sprigg, and is daughter of Nelly whom the Deponent has known ever
since she the deponent was a girl, they being born on the same
plantation, &amp; Nelly was the reputed daughter of Maria Boston whom
the deponent knew until her death which happened about eighteen or
twenty years ago; That the said Maria was reputed to be the
daughter of old Lenah aforesaid &amp; the Deponent never heard it contradicted.
Sworn to this third day of June 1797. Before Bullen.
Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the
parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued until the
second tuesday of May next. At which said second tuesday of May
in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety six,
come again into the General Court here as well the said George Boston
by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid:
Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the
parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued until the
second tuesday of October next. At which said second tuesday of
October in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety
six, come again into the General Court here as well the said George
Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his
attornies aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the premises

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.018"/>

aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further
continued until the second tuesday of May next. At which said second
tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and
ninety seven, come again into the General Court here, as well the said
George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his
attornies aforesaid: Thereupon further process, of and upon the premises
aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further
continued until the second tuesday of October next. At which said second
tuesday of October in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and
ninety seven, come again into the General Court here, as well the said
George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his
attornies aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid
between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued
until the second tuesday of May next. At which said second tuesday of
May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety eight
come again into the General Court here, as well the said George Boston by
his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid:
Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the
parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here, is continued until the second tuesday
of October next. At which said second tuesday of October in the year
of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety eight, come again into the
General Court here, as well the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid;
as the said Richard Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid: Thereupon further
process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by
order of the Court here, is further continued until the second tuesday of May next.
At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand
seven hundred and ninety nine, come again into the General Court here, as
well the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard
Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid; Thereupon further process of and upon the
premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here, is
further continued until the second tuesday of October next. At which said
second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One thousand seven
hundred and ninety nine, come again into the General Court here,
the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid; and the said Richard
Sprigg by his attornies aforesaid does not come: Whereupon the said
George Boston by his attornies aforesaid suggests to the Court here; that
after the last continuance of the plea aforesaid, towit, after the second
tuesday of May last, and before this time, towit, on the &#8212; day of &#8212; at the
County aforesaid, the said Richard Sprigg departed the life, and the same
is not denied; Whereupon it is ordered by the Court here, on the prayer of the
said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, that a summons be forthwith
issued, returnable to the next Term, directed to a certain John Francis
Mercer and Sophia Mercer his wife Executive of the Testament and last

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.019"/>

will of the said Richard Sprigg, commanding them to be and appear before
the General Court here on the second tuesday of May next, to defend
the action aforesaid, according to the Act of Assembly in such case made
and provided; and such summons accordingly issues in form following
towit. The State of Maryland Sct To the Sheriff of Anne
Arundel County, Greeting. Whereas Richard Sprigg late of Anne
Arundel County Gentleman, was heretofore summoned to be in the
General Court, held at the City of Annapolis, to answer unto
George Boston in a plea of Freedom and soforth; to which said
plea the said Richard Sprigg appeared and <sic>impared</sic>; And
Whereas the said Richard Sprigg is since deceased, as it hath
been suggested in the said General Court: Therefore you are
hereby commanded to summon John Francis Mercer and Sophia
his wife Executrix of the Testament and last will of the said
Richard Sprigg, that they be and appear before the said General
Court, to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday
of May next, to answer unto the said George Boston in the
plea aforesaid, according to the directions of the Act of Assembly in
such case lately made and provided, if to them it shall seem meet.
Hereof fail not at your peril, and have you then and there
this writ. Witness the honorable Jeremiah Townley Chase esquire
chief Judge of the said General Court, the Eighth day of October
in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety
nine. Issued the Eleventh day of November 1799. <unclear>JRW.</unclear>
Jno Gwinn Clk. the same day is given to the said George
Boston then and there and soforth. And now at this day towit
the said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand
eight hundred, comes again into the General Court here, the said
George Boston by his attorney aforesaid, and the said Sheriff of
Anne Arundel County to whom the said aforegoing writ was in form
aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here that he hath
summoned the said John Francis Mercer and Sophia Mercer his wife
to answer to the said George Boston, as by the said Summons he
was commanded: Whereupon the said John Francis Mercer and
Sophia his wife Executrix of the said Richard Sprigg by Richard
Sprigg their attorney appear in Court here, and say, that they cannot
deny the complaint aforesaid of the said George Boston the petitioner
aforesaid, so as aforesaid made, nor but that the said George Boston the
petitioner aforesaid, is entitled to his Freedom, being descended, in the
female line, from a free yellow woman being one of the Portuguese, in manner and form as the said
George Boston by his said Petition to the Court here preferred against
the said Richard Sprigg above hath alleged; and thereupon the said
George Boston by his attorney aforesaid, prays that he may be dismissed

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.020"/>

and discharged from the service of the said John Francis Mercer and Sophia
his wife Executrix as aforesaid, together with his costs and charges by him about
the prosecution of his said petition, to him to be adjudged and soforth.
Therefore it is considered by the Court here, that the said George 
Boston the petitioner aforesaid recover of and against the said John
Francis Mercer and Sophia his wife Executrix as aforesaid, his Freedom,
and that he be hence freed and discharged of and from the service of the
said John Francis Mercer and Sophia his wife Executrix as aforesaid,
and that he the said George Boston the petitioner aforesaid go freed
and discharged thereof without day and soforth: And it is further
considered by the Court here, that the said George Boston the petitioner
aforesaid, recover against the said John Francis Mercer and Sophia his
wife Executrix as aforesaid the sum of One thousand five hundred and
twenty five pounds of tobacco, by the Court here unto the said George
Boston on his assent adjudged, for his costs and charges by him about
the prosecution of said petition in this behalf laid out and expended
and that he have thereof his Execution and soforth.</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>111 sids</p>

</div2>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>