<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0013.031">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Boston v. John F. Mercer &amp; Sophia Mercer. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0013.031</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1800-05">May 1800</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-35 JG 47</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1800-05">May 1800</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Boston, Anthony</term>
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term>Rawlings, Gassaway</term>
<term>Sprigg, Richard</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Boston, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Mercer, John Francis</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Mercer, Sophia</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Jenings, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.004360">
<persName>Pinkney, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001496">
<persName>Cooke, William</persName><!-- add attorney occupation to personography -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.004664">
<persName>Martin, Luther</persName>
</person> 
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-11" who="#kln">transcription and encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>George Boston<lb/>
against<lb/>
John F. Mercer &amp;
Sophia his wife Ex of<lb/>
Richard Sprigg</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit,
on the First day of November in the year of our
Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety
one; George Boston by George Jenings his
attorney produced and filed in the General
Court here his Petition against Richard
Sprigg for Freedom, the tenor whereof is in form following towit.
To the Honorable the Judges of the General Court, The Petition of George
Boston humbly sheweth, that he is detained in slavery by a certain
Richard Sprigg of Anne Arundel County when he is entitled to his
Freedom being descended from a Free yellow woman being one of the
Portuguese whose name your petitioner is informed was Lenah
Boston. Your petitioner therefore prays your Honors to take
your petitioners case into consideration and to discharge him
from the services of the said Richard Sprigg and he as in duty
bound will pray &amp;ca G. Jenings for Petr<lb/>
Whereupon, it is ordered by the Court here, that Summons issue against
the said Richard Sprigg to answer the Petition of the said George
Boston prefered against him for Freedom, which is accordingly issued
directed to the sheriff of Anne Arundel County in form following towit.
The State of Maryland towit, To the Sheriff of Ann Arundel County
Greeting: We command you that you summons Richard Sprigg late
of Ann Arundel County that all delays and excuses be set aside he
be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at
the City of Annapolis on the second tuesday of May next to answer
unto the petition of George Boston prefered against him for Freedom
Hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you
then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Samuel Chase Esquire
Chief Judge of our said Court the 1st day of November Anno domini 1791.
Issued the 2d day of November Anno domini 1791. (G.J.) Jno Gwinn Clk
At which said second tuesday of May in the yeaar of our Lord One
thousand seven hundred and ninety two, being the day of the return 
of the aforegoing summons, comes into the General Court here, the
said George Boston by his attorney aforesaid, and the sheriff of
Anne Arundel County to whom the said summons wasa in form
aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here that he
hath summoned the said Richard Sprigg to answer the petition of
the said George Boston prefered against him for Freedom, as by the
said summons he was commanded: Whereupon the said Richard
Sprigg by William Cooke, his attorney appears in Court here, and defends
the Complaint when the Court shall take the same into Consideration,
and prays leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second tuesday

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.031.002"/>

of October next, and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the
said George Boston also. At which said second tuesday of October
in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two,
come again into the General Court here, as well the said George
Boston by his attorney aforesaid, as the said Richard Sprigg by
his attorney aforesaid: Whereupon the said Richard Sprigg by his
attorney aforesaid as before defends the Complaint andsoforth, and prays
leave of the Court here further to imparle until the second tuesday of
May next, and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the
said George Boston also. At which said second tuesday of May in
<sic>in</sic> the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three,
come again into the General Court here as well the said George Boston
by George Jenings, Gabriel Duvall and William Pinkney his attornies
as the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the
complaint and soforth, and prays leave of the Court here further to
imparle until the second tuesday of October next, and to him it is
granted, the same day is given to the said George Boston also.
At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One
thousand seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General
Court here, as well the said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid
as the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid: Whereupon
the said Richard Sprigg by his attorney aforesaid as before defends the
complaint and soforth, and prays leave of the Court here further to
imparle until the second tuesday of May next, and to him it is granted
the same day is given to the said George Boston also. At which said
second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred
and ninety four, come again into the General Court here as well the
said George Boston by his attornies aforesaid, as the said Richard
Sprigg by William Cooke and Luther Martin his attornies: Whereupon
it is agreed by and between the parties aforesaid that all the Testimony
taken in the cause of Anthony Boston against Gassaway Rawlings in
Anne Arundel County Court and removed by Appeal to this Court, and
all Testimony taken since the said Appeal, be received as Evidence
in this cause: which said Testimony is as follows towit. July 20th 1789
Anne Harwood of Anne Arundel</p>

</div2>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>