<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.020">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Teresa Shorter v. Joseph Boarman. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.020</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0535</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1796-05">May 1796</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-26 JG 31</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1796-05">May 1796</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004601">Bullen, J.</term>
<term xml:id="per.002096">Dyson, Thomas A.</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.002097">Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819</term>
<term xml:id="per.005224">Shorter, Jenny</term>
<term xml:id="per.005233">Shorter, Lucy</term>

<!-- TERESA/BOARMAN, JENNY DEPO -->
<term xml:id="per.005298">Boarman, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.005054">Boarman, Raphael</term> 
<term xml:id="per.005327">Brent, William Chandler</term>
<term xml:id="per.005119">Jordan, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.005174">Neale, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.005236">Shorter, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.005199">Shorter, Basil</term>
<term xml:id="per.005201">Shorter, Betty</term>
<term xml:id="per.005214">Shorter, Clem</term>
<term xml:id="per.005225">Shorter, Jenny</term>
<term xml:id="per.005315">Shorter, Letty</term>
<term xml:id="per.005316">Shorter, Minta</term>
<term xml:id="per.005318">Shorter, Nell</term>
<term xml:id="per.005322">Shorter, Phillis</term>
<term xml:id="per.005249">Shorter, Robert</term>
<term xml:id="per.005254">Shorter, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.005325">Wakefield, Benjamin</term>

<!-- TERESA/BOARMAN, TERRY DEPO -->
<term xml:id="per.005295">Boarman, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005056">Bradford, Eleanor</term>
<term xml:id="per.005279">Carroll, Charles</term>
<term xml:id="per.005071">Chunn, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.005301">Fenwick, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005303">Hazle, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.005328">Howell, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.005123">Lancaster, John, Sr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004640">Mason, John T. (John Thomson), 1787-1850</term>
<term xml:id="per.005282">Matthews, Ignatius</term>
<term xml:id="per.005153">Neale, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.001483">Randall, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005200">Shorter, Betty</term>
<term xml:id="per.005208">Shorter, Charity</term>
<term xml:id="per.005308">Shorter, Gerrard</term>
<term xml:id="per.005309">Shorter, Ignatius</term>
<term xml:id="per.005238">Shorter, Ignatius</term>
<term xml:id="per.005310">Shorter, Jenny</term>
<term xml:id="per.005229">Shorter, Jim</term>
<term xml:id="per.005317">Shorter, Monica</term>
<term xml:id="per.005237">Shorter, Nanny</term>
<term xml:id="per.005241">Shorter, Nell</term>
<term xml:id="per.005246">Shorter, Patty</term>
<term xml:id="per.005320">Shorter, Patty</term>
<term xml:id="per.005323">Shorter, Priscilla</term>
<term xml:id="per.005294">Shorter, Stephen</term>
<term xml:id="per.005252">Shorter, Teresa</term>
<term xml:id="per.005165">Simms, Mary</term>
<term xml:id="per.005256">Simms, Robert</term>
<term xml:id="per.005281">Smith, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005329">Stone, Thomas</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005324">
<persName>Shorter, Teresa</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.005297">
<persName>Boarman, Joseph</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.004534">
<persName>Wilmer, Jonathan Roberts</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-08-05" who="#kln">transcription, encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p037" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Teresa Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/>
Joseph Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit on the 
fourteenth day of November in the year of our Lord 
one thousand seven hundred and ninety Teresa 
Shorter by Gabriel Duvall her attorney prefers 
to the Court here her petition for Freedom against Joseph Boarman in 
form following towit.</p>

<p>To the honourable the Judges of the General Court.</p>

<p>The petition of Teresa Shorter humbly sheweth, that she is held as a Slave by 
Joseph Boarman of Charles County, although she is entitled to her freedom 
being descended from a free woman your petitioner is the daughter of Lucy 
Shorter, who was the daughter of Jane Shorter who was the Daughter of
Elizabeth Shorter a free woman She therefore prayeth that your honours
would take her case into consideration and discharge her from the
custody of the aforesaid Joseph Boarman and that Summonses may
issue for her Witness and soforth.</p>

<p>G Duvall for petitioner</p>

<p>Thereupon it is ordered by the Court here that <sic>that</sic> the writ of the
State of Maryland of <sic>Subpena</sic> ad respondendum issue against the said Joseph
Boarman to answer unto the said petition and so forth, and the same accordingly
issues directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sst To the Sheriff of Charles County. We command
you that you Summon Joseph Boarman late of Charles County that all
excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before the Judges of our
General Court to be held at the City Of Annapolis on the Second Tuesday of
May next to answer the Petition of Teresa Shorter preferred against him for
freedom hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you then
and there this writ witness the Honourable Thomas Johnson Esquire Chief Judge
of our said Court the 24 day of November Anno Domini 1790.</p>

<p>Issued the 7th day of December 1790. Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>G Duvall</p>

<p>The same day is given to the said Teresa <sic>Butler</sic> there and soforth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the tenth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one
and the day of the return of the aforegoing writ, comes into the General Court
her the said Teresa Butler by her attorney aforesaid, and the Sheriff of Charles 
County to whom the said writ was directed makes return thereof to the Court 
here thus enclosed towit.</p>

<p>"Summonded" Thos A Dyson Shff Charles County.</p>

<p>And the said Joseph Boarman by Philip Barton Key his attorney appears
in Court here and defends the force and injury when and soforth and prays
leave of the Court here to imparle untill the Second Tuesday of October next
and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eleventh day of the
same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and
ninety one, to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave <catchwords>to</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p038" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.002"/>

imparle come again into the General Court here as well the petitioner as
the Defendant by their attornies, and the said Joseph Boarman by his said 
attorney as before defends the force and injury when and soforth and prays
further leave of the Court here to imparle until the second Tuesday of May
next, and to him it is granted the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the Eighth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two
to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle, come
again into the General Court here as well the petitioner as the Defendant
by their attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney
as before defends the force and injury when and soforth, and prays
further leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of
October next and to him it is granted, the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also.</p>

<p>At which said Second Tuesday of October being the ninth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two
to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle, come
again into the General Court here as well the said Petitioner as the
Defendant by their attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney
as before defends the force and injury when and so forth and prays leave o
the Court here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next, and to him
it is granted the same day is given to the said Teresa Butler also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the fourteenth day of the
same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety
three, to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle
come again into the General Court here as well the petitioner as the Defendant
by their attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said Attorney (as before)
defends the force and injury when andsoforth and prays leave of the Court
here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of October next and to him it is
granted the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eighth day of the same 
month in the year of our Lord one Thousand seven hundred and ninety three
to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle, come again
into the General Court here as well the petitioner as the Defendant by their
attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney (as before) defends
the force and injury when andsoforth and prays leave of the Court here to 
imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next, and to him it is granted
The same day is given to the said Teresa Butler also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one Thousand seven hundred and ninety four to 
which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle come again
into the General Court here as well the petitioner as the defendant by
their attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney (as before) defends
imparle untill the second Tuesday of October next, and to him it is granted 
the same day is given to the said Teresa Butler also.</p>

<p><catchwords>At</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p039" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.003"/>

At which said second Tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one Thousand Seven hundred and ninety four
to which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle come again
into the General Court here as well the said Petitioner and the Defendant by
their attornies and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney (as before)
defends the force and injury when andsoforth, and prays further leave of the 
Court here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next and to him it
is granted the same day is given to the said Teresa Butler also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the twelfth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one Thousand seven hundred and ninety five to
which day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle, come again into
the General Court here as well the Petitioner as the Defendant by their attornies
and the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney (as before) defends the force
and injury when andsoforth and prays further leave of the court here to
imparle untill the second Tuesday of October next and to him it is granted
the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the thirteenth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one Thousand seven hundred and ninety five, to
which said day the said Joseph Boarman had leave to imparle, come again
into the General Court here as well the Petitioner as the Defendant by their attornies
and the said Teresa Shorter by her attorney aforesaid files in Court here the
following Deposition towit.</p>

<p>The Deposition of Terry Shorter aged fifty eight years being sworn 
on the Holy evangely of Almighty God, deposeth &amp; saith that she knows
Teresa Shorter who petitioned against Joseph Boarman &amp; has known her 
eighteen or nineteen years, that she is sister of Charity Shorter who obtained
her freedom against Ignatius Matthews, and also a Sister of Basil Shorter
who petitioned against Charles Carroll &amp; obtained his freedom.</p>

<p>That Robert Shorter who petitioned against Mary Neale now Mary Simms 
by intermarriage with Robert Simms, is also a brother of Basil who
petitioned against Charles Carroll, being the son of Lucy Shorter who
formerly belonged to William Neale near Port Tobacco.</p>

<p>That Jim Shorter who petitioned against Mrs Bradford is also son 
of Lucy aforesaid &amp; brother of Basil who obtained his Freedom
against Charles Carroll.</p>

<p>That Stephen Shorter who petitioned against John Boarman
is son of Jenny who petitioned against Mrs Bradford which Jenny is 
full sister of this Deponent and this deponent obtained her freedom
against Mrs Chunn.</p>

<p>That Anne Shorter who petitioned against Raphael Boarman is
also a Daughter of this deponents sister Jenny aforesaid:</p>

<p>That Monica Shorter who petitioned against Edward Hazle is the
Daughter of Jenny Shorter who belonged to Henry Neal of St
<catchwords>Mary's</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p040" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.004"/>

Marys county which Jenny is sister of Basil who obtained his freedom against 
Charles Carroll. That Priscilla Shorter who petitioned against John Smith
is Daughter of Appy, &amp; sister of George Shorter who petitioned against Henry
Neale. That Baptist who petitioned against the said John Smith is son
of the said Priscilla. That Ignatius Shorter who petitioned against John
Fenwick is the son of Nanny Shorter which Nanny is aunt of this
deponent and this deponent knew Nanny ever since she the said Nanny
was a child &amp; she is about five years younger that the deponent. that
Nanny was the Daughter of Patty Shorter who belonged to old John Lancaster
and was grandmother of this Deponent; That she has understood that
said Nanny is now in Kentucky with a Mr Fenwick who claims Nase.</p>

<p>That Phillis Shorter who has petitioned against Mary Boarman
is Daughter of this deponents sister Jenny who petitioned against Mrs Bradford
and Letty who as petitioned against the said Mary Boarman is Daughter 
of said Phillis. That Thomas Shorter who belongs to Richard Jordan she
has always understood was son of the Deponents <del>mother</del> sister Betty that
Betty's mother was the deponents mother, and Betty was many years younger
than the deponent the deponent knew her ever since she the said Betty
was a child, being both born in the same family. That when the deponent
went to see her mother and her sister at John Smith or Patuxent the
said Tom was a Boy and appeared to be about six or seven years old, that
the Deponents mother Nelly was then sick at Mr Smiths &amp; died of that
illness; that this deponent had never seen the said Tom but once before
that &amp; he then seemed to be about two years old; that her said sister Betty
was then big with her next child &amp; Tom always passed for Betty's child
&amp; she never heard it contradicted or questioned. That Clem Shorter who
petitioned against Raphael Neale is about three years older than Tom 
and she has known Clem ever since she knew Tom having first seen
them at the same time, &amp; Clem always past as the son of the deponent's
sister Betty aforesaid and she never heard it contradicted, and he was 
owned by Betty as her child. That Ignatius Shorter who petitioned against
Henry Howell is brother of this deponent and son of her mother Nelly
and the deponent has known him ever since he was a child.</p>

<p>That Gerrard Shorter who petitioned against Mary Boarman is son
of this deponents sister Jenny who petitioned against Mrs Bradford.</p>

<p>That Patty Shorter who has petitioned against Thomas Stone this deponent
has known ever since she was a child; she is Daughter of Betty who was
aunt of this deponent and sister of this deponents Mother Nelly and was always
reputed as such and she never heard it Contradicted: the said Betty was
Daughter of Patty who belonged to old John Lancaster as the deponent
always understood &amp; never heard it contradicted.</p>

<p>Sworn this 17th day of October 1795 before John Randall</p>

<p>Taken before John T. Mason &amp; Gabriel Duvall</p>

<p><catchwords>And</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p041" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.005"/>

And the said Joseph Boarman by his said attorney (as before) defends the
force and injury when and soforth and prays further leave of the Court here
to imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next and to him it is granted
the same day is given to the said Teresa Shorter also.</p>

<p>And now at this day towit the said Second Tuesday of May being 
the tenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand
seven hundred and ninety six, to which said day the said Joseph
Boarman had leave to imparle, come again into the General Court
here as well the Petitioner as the Defendant by their attornies and the
said Teresa Shorter by Jonathan Roberts Wilmer her attorney files in
Court here the following Deposition towit.</p>

<p>Jenny Shorter aged sixty two years and upwards being sworn on the 
holy evangely of Almighty God deposeth &amp; saith that she knew Terry Shorter
who petitioned against Joseph Boarman; she was Daughter as the deponant
always understood of Lucy Shorter who belonged to William Neale near Port
Tobacco &amp; afterwards to the widow of said Neale which Lucy was sister of Henny
who petitioned against Henry Barnes, and of Basil who petitioned against
Charles Carroll; that she knows Robert Shorter commonly called Bob Russiton
who was always reputed to be the brother of the said Lucy, Henny &amp; Basil.</p>

<p>The Deponent also saith that Anne Shorter who petitioned against Raphael
Boarman is Daughter of this Deponent &amp; was sold &amp; sent to the Havanna as she
has been informed; that the said Anne was sent away by Raphael Boarman
sometime after she had petitioned; being asked if raphael Boarman knew
that she had petitioned, answers she thinks he did he was in the house
when the deponent heard Benjamin Wakefield read the order of Court
about her petitioning, that she was to be used well &amp; the like, &amp; she was
sent away some months afterwards; that it was at the house of the mother
of Raphael Boarman when the deponent heard the order of Court 
read and from said house she was sent. That Nell Shorter who petitioned
against William Chandler Brant is Daughter of Minta now deceased
who was Daughter of this deponent, &amp; the deponent knew said 
Nell ever since she was a child. That Phillis who petitioned against
Mary Boarman is Daughter of this Deponent, and Letty who petitioned
against said Mary Boarman is Daughter of said Philis.</p>

<p>That Tom who petitioned against Richard Jordan this Deponent
has known ever since, he was about two years old; he is the son of
Betty who was sister on the mother's &amp; father's side of this Deponent
That Clem who petitioned against Raphael Neale is a full brother 
of said Tom.</p>

<p>Sworn to this 16th day of May 1796 before J Bullen</p>

<p>Whereupon all and singular the premises between the parties aforesaid by the
Court here being seen heard and fully understood and mature deliberation
thereupon had for that it appears to the Court here that the said Teresa Shorter
<catchwords>the</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p042" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.006"/>

the petitioner aforesaid is entitled to her Freedom as she by her petition
to the Court here hath alledged. Therefore it is considered by the Court
here that the said Teresa Shorter the petitioner aforesaid be free and
discharged of and from the service of the said Joseph Boarman and that
she the said Teresa Shorter the petitioner aforesaid go thereof without day &amp;ca.
It is further considered by the Court here that the said Teresa Shorter
recover against the said Joseph Boarman the quantity of Eight hundred
and four pounds of Tobacco by the Court here unto her on her assent
adjudged for her costs and charges by her about the prosecution of her 
petition laid out and expended and that she have thereof her execution &amp;ca.</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clk.</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
