<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0014.094">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Agnes Butler v. Rachel Boarman. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0014.094</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0602</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>
Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1792-05">May 1792</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-17</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1792-05">May 1792</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Butler, Anne</term><!-- parent of Agnes, child of Eleanor -->
<term>Butler, Anne</term><!-- parent of Eleanor, child of Irish Nell -->
<term>Butler, Eleanor</term><!-- parent of Anne, child of Anne -->
<term>Butler, Eleanor</term><!-- Irish Nell, parent of Anne -->
<term xml:id="per.002096">Dyson, Thomas A.</term><!-- sheriff -->
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term><!-- clerk -->
<term xml:id="per.002097">Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819</term><!-- judge -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Dismissed</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Butler, Agnes</persName><!-- child of Anne, died before May 8, 1792 -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Boarman, Rachel</persName><!-- Charles County --> 
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1818-1859</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. Court of Appeals</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-02-21" who="#kln">transcribed; encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0014.094.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Agnes Butler<lb/>
against<lb/>
Rachel Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore towit, on the Twenty first day of October in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety; Agnes Butler by Gabriel Duvall her attorney, preferred and filed in Court here, her Petition for Freedom against Rachel Boarman, in the words and of the tenor following towit. To the Honorable the Judges of the General Court: The Petition of Agnes Butler, humbly sheweth that she is held as a Slave by Rachel Boarman of Charles County altho' she is entitled to her Freedom, being descended from a Free woman whose name was Eleanor Butler. Your Petitioner is the Daughter of Anne Butler who was the Daughter of Eleanor Butler who was the Daughter of Anne Butler who was the Daughter of Eleanor Butler aforesaid a Free white woman: She therefore prays your honors to take her case into consideration and discharge her from the custody of the said Rachel Boarman, and that Summonses may Issue for Her witnesses, andsoforth. G. Duvall for Petr.</p>

<p>Thereupon, on motion of the said Agnes Butler, by her attorney aforesaid, it is ruled and ordered by the Court here that the said Rachel Boarman do not remove the said Agnes Butler out of this State, nor obstruct her from attending this Court from time to time in support of her Petition for Freedom preferred to the Court here; and in the mean time to feed, cloath and use the said Agnes Butler well: It is further ruled and ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Summons issue forth out of the General Court here against the said Roachel Boarman, to answer unto the said Petition of the said Agnes eButler, which Issued accordingly, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in the words and of the tenor following towit: The State of Maryland Sct To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. We command you that you summon Rachel Boarman of Charles County, that all excuses and delays set aside she be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of May next, to answer the Petition

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0014.094.002"/>

of Agnes Butler preferred against her for Freedom. Hereof she is not to fail, and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Thomas Johnson Esquire chief Judge of our said Court the 24th day of November Anno domini 1790. Issued the 7th day of December 1790. (G. Duvall) Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of May, being the Tenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety one, and the day of the return of the aforegoing Summons, comes into the General Court here, the said Agnes Butler by her attorney aforesaid; and the Sheriff of Charles County aforesaid, to whom the said summons was inform aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed, towit: "Summoned. Thos A. Dyson, Shff of Chas County." And the said Rachel Boarman being so forewarned now here comes into the General Court by Philip Barton Key her attorney; Thereupon, further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is continued until the Second Tuesday of October next; the same day is given to the said parties, then andsoforth.</p>

<p>At which said Second Tuesday of October, being the Eleventh day of the said month in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety one, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Agnes Butler by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Rachel Boarman by her attorney aforesaid: Thereupon, further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of May next; the same day is given to the said parties, then, andsoforth</p>

<p>And now at this day towit, the said Second tuesday of May being the Eighth day of the said month in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety two, comes again into the General Court here, the said Rachel Boarman by her attorney aforesaid, and the said Agnes Butler does not come; And the said Rachel Boarman by her attorney aforesaid suggests to the Court here, that since the last continuance of the plaint aforesaid, the said Agnes Butler the Petitioner in this case, departed this life, and the same is not denied: Therefore it is considered and adjudged by the Court here that the Petition, plaint and proceedings aforesaid between the parties aforesaid in this case, abate</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clerk</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>