<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.supp.0002.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Select Committee on Illegal Traffic in Slaves in D.C. Presentment of the Grand Jury of Baltimore</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2014</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.supp.0002.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0484</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Presentment of the Grand Jury of Baltimore</title>
<date when="1810-07">July 1810</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>Record Group 233, Records of the Select Committees of the House of Representatives</collection>
<idno>HR 14A-C.17.4, Papers of the Select Committee to Inquire into the Existence of an Inhuman and Illegal Traffic in Slaves in the District of Columbia</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Presentment</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.004820">Atkinson, Isaac</term>
<term xml:id="per.004821">Barge, Andrew</term>
<term xml:id="per.004822">Corner, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.004823">Daugherty, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004824">Dickson, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.004825">Forney, David</term>
<term xml:id="per.004826">Hadskis, Samuel H.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004827">Heath, Richard W.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004828">Irvine, Alexander</term>
<term xml:id="per.004829">Lynch, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004830">McLaughlin, M.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004831">Miller, George</term>
<term xml:id="per.004832">Moale, R. H.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004833">Murray, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004834">Philips, Isaac</term>
<term xml:id="per.004835">Piper, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.004836">Rogers, Philip</term>
<term xml:id="per.004837">Shrim, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004838">Snyder, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.004839">Stewart, Robert</term>
<term xml:id="per.004840">Welsh, Jacob</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Baltimore County (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>          
<change when="2017-12-13" who="#kln">added caseid</change>   
<change when="2017-12-12" who="#kln">added xml:ids</change>
<change when="2017-12-11" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="document">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.supp.0002.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>July Term 1810</p>

<p>Grand Jury Room.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>We the undersign'd Grand Jurors for Baltimore County respectfully represent, that during our official service at the present court, we have had abundant evidence of the existence of an evil for which in the present state of our laws there seems to be no adequate remedy. To Wit the Evil which necessarily attaches itself to the Slave Trade or to the transportation of Slaves from this, to other states.</p>

<p>It has been represented to us by sufficient testimony that there are in this City, houses appropriated to this trade as prisons for the reception of Negroes intended to be carried to other states And that the manner in which these houses are kept, the slaves being crowded together, male and female in one common dungeon, there being loaded with irons, confined in their filth together with being subjected to various species of Cruelty and Tyranny from their Keepers, presents a scene at once abhorrent to every principle of humanity and in our opinion disgraceful to any civilized community.</p>

<p>Slaves lawfully held are not the only victims of the barbarity It appears that the high price given for negroes, offers so strong a temptation, to the depraved part of our community, That servants for a term of years are sold as slaves for life. Thus are defeated the humane intentions of their former masters who had manumitted them</p>

<p>Free Negroes are decoyed by stratagem or dragged by force into these prisons, are chained and sent away such is the facility with which your laws may be put at defiance when such a system as this is permitted to be established and continues to be tolerated</p>

<p>Indentures are given by virtue of which free children as also grown persons are to be carried away and made slaves for life.</p>

<p>Slaves the legal property of individuals and in some cases the chief support of helpless widows, are stolen away from their owners and deposited in these cells <fw type="catch">of misery</fw>

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.supp.0002.001.002.jpg"/>

of misery to wait transportation.</p>

<p>These are not solitary cares, but the alarming frequency of their occurrence their every day notoriety is such, as to shock every spectator that has the least regard for mercy or for justice the number of cases of these descriptions that during the present sitting of the court have been presented to the jury justify them in believing that the horrible practice of kidnapping both the slaves and the free instead of being checked by the vigilance and exertion of our police is increasing with enormous rapidity Deeply impressed with a sense of the necessity of some measure being adopt'd by the state for the protection of her Citizens in their property and free negroes in their liberty, against those fellonious invaders of Law. and of right. We the Undersign'd Grand Jurors beg leave to be considered among the petitioners for a law that will completely put a stop to such nefarious practices.</p>

<p>Richard W Heath, Foreman<lb/>
Wm Dickson<lb/>
John Daugherty<lb/>
George Miller<lb/>
Alexr Irvine<lb/>
R H Moale<lb/>
John Snyder<lb/>
James Corner<lb/>
Isaac Atkinson<lb/>
Jacob Welsh<lb/>
M. McLaughlin<lb/>
John Shrim<lb/>
Robert Stewart<lb/>
Saml H Hadskis<lb/>
James Piper<lb/>
Philip Rogers<lb/>
David Forney<lb/>
Andrew Barge<lb/>
Isaac Philips<lb/>
John Murray<lb/>
John Lynch</p>

<p>(A. Copy)</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.supp.0002.001.003.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>No 1.</p>

<p>Presentment Of the Grand Jury of Baltimore</p>

<p>Copy</p>

<p>presentment of the Grand Jury for Baltimore county</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
