<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.009">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Stephen Shorter v. John Boarman. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.009</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0524</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1795-10">October 1795</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-25 JG 29</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1795-10">October 1795</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.005043">Barnes, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.005297">Boarman, Joseph</term><!-- enslaved Teresa Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005298">Boarman, Mary</term><!-- enslaved Phillis Shorter; may be per.005052; enslaved Letty Shorter; enslaved Gerrard Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005054">Boarman, Raphael</term>
<term xml:id="per.005056">Bradford, Eleanor</term>
<term xml:id="per.005327">Brent, William Chandler</term><!-- enslaved Nell Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.004601">Bullen, J.</term>
<term xml:id="per.005299">Butler, Sarah</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Priscilla Shorter; enslaved by Henry Neale (son of Roswell Neale); acquaintance of Jenny Shorter (5224) -->
<term xml:id="per.005279">Carroll, Charles</term><!-- slaveholder of Basil Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005071">Chunn, Anne</term>
<term xml:id="per.002096">Dyson, Thomas A.</term><!-- sheriff summoning Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.005300">Edelen, Richard</term><!-- slaveholder of Leonard Shorter; received gifted slave from Philip Ford -->
<term xml:id="per.005301">Fenwick, John</term><!-- enslaved Ignatius Shorter, Nanny Shorter; resides in Kentucky -->
<term xml:id="per.005302">Ford, Philip</term><!-- purchased slave from John Smith; gifted slave to Richard Edelen -->
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term><!-- clerk -->
<term xml:id="per.005303">Hazle, Edward</term><!-- enslaved Monica Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005328">Howell, Henry</term><!-- enslaved Ignatius Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.002097">Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819</term><!-- judge -->
<term xml:id="per.005119">Jordan, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.005123">Lancaster, John, Sr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.004640">Mason, John T. (John Thomson), 1787-1850</term>
<term xml:id="per.005282">Matthews, Ignatius</term><!-- enslaved Charity Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005151">Neale, Henry</term><!-- son of Roswell -->
<term xml:id="per.005153">Neale, Henry</term><!-- (St. Mary's County) enslaved Jenny Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005152">Neale, Henry</term><!-- St. Mary's County; son of Henry Neale; enslaved Lucy Shorter (Appy) -->
<term xml:id="per.005172">Neale, Roswell</term>
<term xml:id="per.005174">Neale, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.005165">Sims, Mary</term><!-- maiden name Neale; enslaved Robert Shorter; -->
<term xml:id="per.005236">Shorter, Anne</term><!-- enslaved by Raphael Boarman; child of Jenny Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005305">Shorter, Anthony</term><!-- child of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005198">Shorter, Appy</term><!-- parent of Priscilla Shorter; child of Jenny Shorter; been dead about 19 years 27 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005306">Shorter, Baptist</term><!-- enslaved by John Smith; child of Priscilla -->
<term xml:id="per.005199">Shorter, Basil</term><!-- enslaved by Charles Carroll; freed; sibling of Robert Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005201">Shorter, Betty</term><!-- sibling of Teresa Shorter (Chunn) -->
<term xml:id="per.005200">Shorter, Betty</term><!-- family of Teresa Shorter (Chunn); parent of Patty Shorter; sibling of Nelly Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005208">Shorter, Charity</term><!-- sibling of Teresa Shorter (Joseph Boarman); enlaved by Ignatius Matthews; obtained freedom -->
<term xml:id="per.005214">Shorter, Clem</term><!-- enslaved by Raphel Neale -->
<term xml:id="per.005220">Shorter, George</term><!-- sibling of Priscilla Shorter; enslaved by Henry Neale (5152); died before 27 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005307">Shorter, Gerrard</term><!-- child of Appy; died before 27 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005308">Shorter, Gerrard</term><!-- enslaved by Mary Boarman; child of Jenny Shorter (Nelly) -->
<term xml:id="per.005222">Shorter, Henny</term><!-- died before 27 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005221">Shorter, Henrietta</term><!-- Henny -->
<term xml:id="per.005309">Shorter, Ignatius</term><!-- enslaved by John Fenwick; child of Nanny Shorter; enslaved by John Fenwick -->
<term xml:id="per.005238">Shorter, Ignatius</term><!-- alt name Nase; enslaved by Henry Howell; child of Nelly Shorter; sibling of Teresa Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005224">Shorter, Jenny</term><!-- acquaintance of Sara Butler; parent of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005225">Shorter, Jenny</term><!-- enslaved by Eleanor Bradford; parent of Stephen Shorter; sibling of deponent Teresa Shorter; deponent; 62, 16 May 1796; acquaintance of Terry Shorter (Joseph Boarman)  -->
<term xml:id="per.005310">Shorter, Jenny</term><!-- enslaved by Henry Neale of St. Mary's; parent of Monica Shorter; sibling of Basil Shorter (Chas Carroll); may be per.005226 -->
<term xml:id="per.005311">Shorter, Jenny</term><!-- child of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005229">Shorter, Jim</term><!-- child of Lucy; enslaved by Eleanor Bradford -->
<term xml:id="per.005312">Shorter, Joshua</term><!-- child of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005313">Shorter, Leonard</term><!-- enslaved by Richard Edelen, John Smith, Philip Ford; child of Priscilla Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005233">Shorter, Lucy</term>
<term xml:id="per.005314">Shorter, Lucy</term><!-- child of Appy; enslaved by Henry Neale of St. Mary's; enslaved by William Neale near Port Tobacco -->
<term xml:id="per.005315">Shorter, Letty</term><!-- enslaved by Mary Boarman; child of Phillis Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005316">Shorter, Minta</term><!-- parent of Nell, child of Jenny Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005317">Shorter, Monica</term><!-- enslaved by Edward Hazle; child of Jenny Shorter (daughter of Lucy) -->
<term xml:id="per.005237">Shorter, Nanny</term><!-- family of deponent Teresa Shorter; parent of Ignatius Shorter (John Fenwick); child of Patty Shorter; in Kentucky -->
<term xml:id="per.005318">Shorter, Nell</term><!-- enslaved by William Chandler Brent; child of Minta -->
<term xml:id="per.005241">Shorter, Nell</term>
<term xml:id="per.005319">Shorter, Nelly</term><!-- child of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005246">Shorter, Patty</term><!-- enslaved by John Lancaster; parent of Nanny Shorter; family of deponent Teresa Shorter --> 
<term xml:id="per.005320">Shorter, Patty</term><!-- enslaved by Thomas Stone; child of Betty Shorter (John Lancaster) -->
<term xml:id="per.005321">Shorter, Peter</term><!-- child of Appy -->
<term xml:id="per.005322">Shorter, Phillis</term><!-- enslaved by Mary Boarman; daughter of Jenny Shorter (daughter of Nelly); parent of Letty Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005323">Shorter, Priscilla</term><!--  deponent; enslaved by John Smith; child of Appy; sibling of George Shorter; acquaintance of Sara Butler; "Prissy"; parent of Leonard Shorter and Baptist Shorter; between 40 and 50, 30 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005249">Shorter, Robert</term><!-- enslaved by Mary Neale; sibling of Basil Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005251">Shorter, Shadrack</term><!-- died before 27 Oct 1795 -->
<term xml:id="per.005324">Shorter, Teresa</term><!-- enslaved by Joseph Boarman; acquaintence of Terry Shorter deponent; acquaintance of Jenny Shorter (per.005225); child of Lucy Shorter  -->
<term xml:id="per.005252">Shorter, Teresa</term><!-- deponent; alt name Terry, age 58, 17 Oct 1795; obtained freedom from Mrs Chunn; sibling of Jenny Shorter (Bradford) -->
<term xml:id="per.005254">Shorter, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.005256">Sims, Robert</term><!-- spouse of Mary Neale -->
<term xml:id="per.005281">Smith, John</term><!-- enslaved Priscilla Shorter; could be per.005259; enslaved Baptist Shorter, Betty Shorter; on Patuxent River; sold slave to Philip Ford -->
<term xml:id="per.005329">Stone, Thomas</term><!-- enslaved Patty Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005325">Wakefield, Benjamin</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005294">
<persName>Shorter, Stephen</persName><!-- son of Jenny (Bradford) -->
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.005295">
<persName>Boarman, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">reviewed; relationship encoding</change>
<change when="2019-07-19" who="#kln">reviewed and edited transcription; encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p045" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Stephen Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/>
John Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore to wit, on the fourth day of June in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one; Stephen Shorter by Gabriel Duvall his attorney preferred and filed in the General Court here his Petition for Freedom against John Boarman, which is in form following to wit.</p>

<p>To the honorable the Judges of the General Court. The Petition of Stephen Shorter humbly sheweth that he is held in slavery by John Boarman of Charles County altho' he is entitled to his freedom being descended from Elizabeth Shorter a free white woman in the female line. He therefore prays your honours the premises considered to discharge him from the service of the said John Boarman <catchwords>and</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p046" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.002"/>

and he will pray and so forth. G. Duvall for Petr</p>

<p>Whereupon in pursuance of the rule and order the Court here in such case made on the sixteenth day of August in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid, prosecuted and sued forth out of the General Court here the writ of the State of Maryland of Subpoena ad respondendum against the said John Boarman directed to the sheriff of Charles County in form following to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sst To the sheriff of Charles County Greeting. We command you that you Summon John Boarman late of Charles County that all delays and excuses set aside he be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of October next to answer the petition of Stephen Shorter preferred against him for Freedom hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honourable Thomas Johnson Esquire chief Judge of our said Court the 16th day of June Anno Domini 1791.</p>

<p>Issued the 16th day of August 1791. John Gwinn Clerk</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eleventh day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one, and the day of the return of the aforegoing Summons, comes into the General Court here the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid; and the sheriff of Charles County aforesaid to whom the said summons was in form aforesaid directed makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed towit.</p>

<p>Summoned. Thomas A. Dyson Sheriff.</p>

<p>Whereupon comes into the General Court here the said John Boarman by Philip Barton Key his attorney and thereupon further process of and upon the promises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is continued until the second Tuesday of May next; the same day is given to the said parties, then, and soforth.</p> 

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the Eighth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, come again in the General <catchwords>Court</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p047" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.003"/>

here as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid, as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of October next; the same day is given to the parties aforesaid, their and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the ninth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid, as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid. And the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid agree that all depositions taken in this case on ten days notice to the petitioner or defendants Council before a Justice of the peace, shall be received and read in Evidence in all the cases of Petitioning negroes under the name of Shorter claiming their freedom as descendants of a certain Elizabeth Shorter claiming their freedom as descendants of a certain Elizabeth Shorter or her female ancestors, on the General question touching the right of Elizabeth Shorter or her female Ancestors to freedom under the laws of this Country. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of May next; the same day is given to the parties aforesaid then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of May being the fourteenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three, comes again into the General Court here as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid as the John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of October next, the same day is given to the parties aforesaid then and there and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eighth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three, comes again into the General Court here as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the Parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second <catchwords>Tuesday</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p048" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.004"/>

Tuesday of May next, the same day is given to the parties aforesaid then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May, being the thirteenth day of the same month on the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid: Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of October next, the same day is given to the said parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the said month in the year of Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, come again into the General Court here as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid, as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid, Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of May next, the same day is given to the said parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of May being the twelfth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of October next, the same day is given to the said parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>And now at this day to wit, the said second Tuesday of October being the thirteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid as the said John Boarman by his attorney aforesaid. And the said Stephen Shorter by his attorney aforesaid files in Court here sundry depositions which are in form following to wit.</p>

<p>Teresa Shorter against Joseph Boarman. The deposition of Terry <catchwords>Shorter</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p049" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.005"/>

Shorter aged fifty eight years being sworn on the holy evangely of Almighty God deposeth and saith that she knows Teresa Shorter who petitioned against Joseph Boarman and has known her Eighteen or nineteen years; that she is sister of Charity Shorter who obtained her freedom against Ignatius Matthews, and also a sister of Basil Shorter who petitioned against Charles Carroll and obtained his freedom That Robert Shorter who petitioned against Mary Neale now Mary Simms by Intermarriage with Robert Simms, is also a brother of Basil who petitioned against Charles Carroll, being the son of Lucy Shorter who formerly belonged to William Neale near Port Tobacco. That Jim Shorter who petitioned against Mrs Bradford is also son of Lucy aforesaid and brother of Basil who obtained his freedom against Charles Carroll. That Stephen Shorter who petitioned against John Boarman is son of Jenny who petitioned against Mrs Bradford, which is full sister of this deponent and this deponent obtained her freedom against Mrs Chunn. That Anne Shorter who petitioned against Raphael Boarman is also a daughter of this deponents sister Jenny aforesaid. That Monica Shorter who petitioned against Edward Hazle is the daughter of Jenny Shorter who belonged to Henry Neale of St Marys County, which Jenny is sister of Basil who obtained his freedom against Charles Carroll. That Priscilla Shorter who petitioned against John Smith is daughter of Appy, and sister of George Shorter who petitioned against Henry Neale. That Baptist who petitioned against the said John Smith is son of the said Priscilla. That Ignatius Shorter who petitioned against John Fenwick is the son of Nanny Shorter which Nanny is aunt of this deponent and this deponent knew Nanny her since she the said Nanny was a Child, and she is about five years younger than the deponent that Nanny was the daughter of Patty Shorter who belonged to old John Lancaster and was grand mother of this deponent; that she has understood that said Nanny is now in Kentucky with Mr Fenwick who claims Nase.</p>

<p>That Phillis Shorter who has Petitioned against Mary Boarman is daughter of this deponents Sister Jenny who petitioned against Mrs. Bradford, and Letty who has petitioned against the said Mary Boarman is daughter of said Phillis. That Thomas Shorter who belongs to Richard Jordan she has always understood was son of the deponents sister who belongs to Richard Jordan she <catchwords>has</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p050" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.006"/>

has always understood was son of the deponent's Sister Betty that Bettys mother was the deponents mother, and Betty was many years younger than the deponent the deponent knew her ever since she the said Betty was a child, being both born in the same family. That when the deponent went to see her mother and her Sister at John Smiths on patuxent the said Tom was a boy and appeared to be about six or seven years old, that the deponents mother Nelly was then sick at Mr Smith's and died of that Illness; that this deponent had never seen the said Tom but once before that, he then seemed to be about two years old, that her said Sister Betty was then big with her next Child, and Tom always past for Betty's child and she never heard it contradicted or questioned. That Clem Shorter who petitioned against Raphael Neale is about three years older than Tom and she has known Clem ever since she knew Tom having first seen them at the same time, and Clem always past as the son of the deponents Sister Betty aforesaid and she never heard it contradicted and he was owned by Betty as her child. That Ignatius Shorter who petitioned against Henry Howell is brother of this deponent and son of her mother Nelly, and the deponent has known him ever since he was a child. That Gerrard Shorter who petitioned against Mary Boarman is son of this deponents Sister Jenny who petitioned against Mrs Bradford. That Patty Shorter who has petitioned against Thomas Stone this deponent has known ever since she was a Child, she is daughter of Betty who was aunt of this deponent and sister of this deponents mother Nelly and she was always reputed as such and she never heard it contradicted; the said Betty was daughter of Patty who belonged to old John Lancaster as the deponent always understood and never heard it contradicted. Sworn this 17th day of October 1795, before John Randall</p>

<p>Taken before John T. Mason and Gabriel Duvall</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption"> 

<p>Priscilla Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/> 
John Smith</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Petition for freedom. Sara Butler of Anne Arundel County aged fifty three years and upwards being sworn on the holy Evangely of Almighty God deposeth and saith that she knows Priscilla Shorter now present and has known

<pb xml:id="p051" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.007"/>

known her ever since she was born, that they were both born in the family of Henry Neale deceased, who was son of Roswell Neale; the said Priscilla Shorter is daughter of Appy Shorter now deceased; the deponent knew Appy well, she belonged to the said Henry Neale; that Appy has been dead about nineteen years; that she had eleven children to wit, Henry, Joshua, Anthony, Jenny, Shadrack, George, Nelly, Peter, Prissy, and Lucy and Gerard; that Henry, Joshua, Jenny, Shadrack, George, Nelly, and Gerrard are dead; that Lucy, belongs to Henry Neale of St Marys County, son of Henry Neale deceased before mentioned, and has petitioned against him. That the deponent knew Jenny Shorter very well, and Appy was always reputed the daughter of Jenny Shorter, and they always claimed one another as mother and daughter and she never heard it contradicted.</p>

<p>Sworn 27 Octo 1795 before J. Bullen</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Leonard Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/>
Richard Edelen</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Priscilla Shorter aged between forty and fifty years being sworn on the holy Evangels of Almighty God deposeth and saith that the petitioner Leonard Shorter now present, is the son of the deponent and her master John Smith sold him to Philip Ford four or five years ago, and Philip Ford gave him to the defendant who married his daughter. That Baptist Shorter who petitioned against John Smith is also son of this deponent and is older than Leonard and is now about twenty four years of age.</p>

<p>Sworn to this 30th day of October 1795, before J. Bullen.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Teresa Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/>
Joseph Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Petition for Freedom.</p>

<p>Jenny Shorter aged sixty two years and upwards being sworn on the holy evangely of Almighty God deposeth and saith that she knew Terry Shorter who petitioned against Joseph Boarman; she was daughter as the deponent always understood of Lucy Shorter who belonged to William Neale near Port Tobacco, and afterwards to the widow of said Neale, which Lucy was Sister of Henry who petitioned against Henry Barnes, and of Basil who petitioned against Charles Carroll, that she knows Robert Shorter commonly called Bob Russeten, who was always reputed to be the Brother of the said Lucy Henry and Basil. The deponent also saith that Anne Shorter who petitioned against Raphael Boarman is daughter of this deponent and was sold and sent to the Havanna as she has <catchwords>been</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p052" n="oscys.mdcase.0012.009.008"/>

been informed that the said Anne was sent away by Raphael Boarman sometime after she had petitioned, answers she thinks he did, he was in the house when the deponent heard Benjamin Wakefield read the order of the Court about her petitioning, that she was to be used well and the like and she was sent away some months afterwards, that it was at the house of the within of Raphael Boarman when the deponent heard the order of Court read, and from said house she was sent. That Nell Shorter who petitioned against William Chandler Brent is daughter of Minta now deceased, who was daughter of this deponent, and the deponent knew said Nell ever since she was a child. That Phillis who petitioned against Mary Boarman is daughter of this deponent, and Letty who petitioned against said Mary Boarman is daughter of the said Phillis. That Tom who petitioned against Richard Jordan this deponent has known ever since he was about two years old; he is the son of Betty who was sister on the mother's and fathers side of this deponent. That Clem, who petitioned against Raphael Neale is a full brother of said Tom. Sworn to this 16th day of May 1796 before J. Bullen.</p>

<p>Whereupon all and singular the premises between the parties aforesaid by the court here being seen, heard and fully understood, and mature deliberation thereupon had for that it appears to the Court here, that the said Stephen Shorter, the petitioner aforesaid is entitled to his freedom being descended, in the female line from a free white woman, as he by his petition to the court here have alleged; Therefore it is considered by the court here, that the said Stephen Shorter the petitioner aforesaid, be free and discharged of and from the service of the said John Boarman and that he the said Stephen Shorter the petitioner aforesaid, go thereof without day, &amp;c. It is further considered by the Court here, that the said Stephen Shorter the petitioner aforesaid recover against the said John Boarman the quantity of eight hundred and forty one pounds of Tobacco by the Court here unto him the said Stephen Shorter on his assent adjudged for his costs and Charges by him about the prosecution of his petition aforesaid, laid out and expended and that he have thereof his Execution, &amp;c.</p>

<p>Test Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
