<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0388.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>William v. George W. Lewis. Petition for Freedom</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0388.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0413</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petition for Freedom</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 1</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Petition</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1819-03">March 1819</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.003080">Butler, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.001326">Hoffman, Jacob</term>
<term xml:id="per.003081">Wynkoop, Augustus</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>New York</term>
<term>Alexandria County (Va.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Dismissed</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.003082">
<persName>William</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.003083">
<persName>Lewis, George W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.000122">
<persName>Lee, Edmund J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>       
<change when="2016-07-25" who="#lkw">added xml:ids; transcription; added Jacob Hoffman to people</change>
<change when="2016-06-23" who="#snc">reviewed</change>       
<change when="2016-05-10" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0388.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>To the Honorable the Circuit Court of the District of Columbia for the County of Alexandria</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The petition of William a negro boy under the age of twenty one by Jacob Hoffman his next friend, respectfully states he was born in the state of New York since the 4th of July 1799. That by the laws of that state all persons of Colour born after <del>that</del> date aforesaid are free but bound to serve as a servant of the owner of the mother in the same manner as if bound to service untill the age of twenty eight years. That his mother belonged to Thomas Buttler of New York &amp; your petitioner was born the servant of the said Thomas Butler who sold <del>the</del> him for <del>a</del> the term of years to a certain Augustus Wynkoop, who sold his interest in the service of your petitioner to a certain

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0388.001.002.jpg"/>

George W: Lewis. Who hath removed your petitioner from New York claiming him as a slave for life and had brought him on to Alexandria with the aim of selling him to some person who is in the practice of buying slaves to take to the South for sale. That he was first taken to the City of Washington in this District &amp; there offered for sale</p>

<p>Your petitioner states that he is unlawfully claimed as a slave by the said George W: Lewis. He therefore prays your honors to allow him to institute a suit in this court for his freedom. against the said George W: Lewis.</p>

<pb xml:id="p003" facs="oscys.case.0388.001.003.jpg"/>

<p>I Edmund J Lee do hereby certify that the facts set form in the petition of negro William can be substituted and that he is in my opinion entitled to his freedom.</p>

<p>Edm: J Lee</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Negro William<lb/>
vs<lb/>
George W: Lewis</p>

<p>Edmund J Lee is appointd Counsel <del>to prosecute his case</del> <del>for</del> to the plaintiff &amp; <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> is given to bring a suit in forma pauperis agt George W. Lewis for his freedom. and it is ordered that <del>pr</del> process be

<pb xml:id="p004" facs="oscys.case.0388.001.004.jpg"/>

issued against the said G. W. Lewis to appear and answer the complaint, and in the mean time that the said Negro William be in custody of the Marshall, until the said G. W. Lewis shall give bond with security in the penalty 800 Dollars with the clerk of this Court to have the said Negro William forthcoming to answer the judgment of the Court, and untill the said G. W. Lewis shall <del>By order</del> give bond<del>s</del> and security as aforesaid it is order'd that the marshall hire the said negro for the best price that can be got  for him, to some reputable person resident in this county, and render to this Court an account of the money which <del>he</del> may be received for his wages.</p>

<p>By order</p>

<p>Entered</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="back">

<p>William</p>

</div2>

<pb xml:id="p005" facs="oscys.case.0388.001.005.jpg"/>

<div2 type="back">

<p>Negro William<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Geo: W: Lewis</p>

<p>papers</p>

<p>1816<lb/>
Nov Term. 14th day<lb/>
E. J. Lee assd. Counsel to Plt. &amp; leave given to bring a suit in forma pauperis &amp; ord. that Process issue to asr. the Complaint, &amp; in the meantime that the sd. Negro William be in custody of the Marshal until the sd. G. W. L. shall give bond &amp; secy in the Penalty of $800. with the Clerk of this Court to have the sd. Negro william forthcoming to ansr. the Judt. of the Ct. &amp; until the sd. G. W. L. shall give Bond &amp; Secy. as afd. ordered, that the Marshal hire the said Negro for the best price that can be got for him to some reputable person resident in this County, &amp; render to this Court an Account of the Money which may be received for his wages.</p>

<p>1818. April Term 9th. day ordered to be retd. to the rules for further proceedings</p>

<p>1819<lb/>
March abates by plffs death</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
