<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.002">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charity Shorter v. Ignatius Matthews. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.002</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0517</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1795-05">May 1795</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-24 JG 27</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1795-05">May 1795</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.002097">Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819</term>
<term xml:id="per.005217">Shorter, Elizabeth</term><!-- parent of Jane/Jenny; free woman -->
<term xml:id="per.005224">Shorter, Jenny</term><!-- Jane, child of Elizabeth Shorter -->
<term xml:id="per.005233">Shorter, Lucy</term><!-- mother of Charity Shorter -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005208">
<persName>Shorter, Charity</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Matthews, Ignatius</persName><!-- Charles County -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-07-08" who="#kln">reviewed and edited transcription; encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p021" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.002.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Charity Shorter<lb/>
against<lb/>
Ignatius Matthews</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore towit, on the Sixteenth day of November in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety; Charity Shorter by Gabriel Duvall her attorney, preferred and filed in the General Court here, her Petition for Freedom, which is in form following to wit. To the Honorable the Judges of the General Court The Petition of Charity Shorter, humbly sheweth, that she is held as a slave by Ignatius Matthews of Charles County, although she is entitled to her Freedom being descended from a Free woman. Your Petitioner is the daughter of Lucy Shorter, who was the daughter of Jane Shorter who was the daughter of Elizabeth Shorter a Free Woman. She therefore prayeth, that your Honors would taker her case into consideration and discharge her from the custody of the aforesaid Ignatius Matthews, and that Summonses may issue for her Witnesses andsoforth. G. Duvall for Petitioner.</p>
 
<p>Whereupon, it is ordered by the Court here, that the writ of the State of Maryland of Summons issue against the said Ignatius Matthews to answer unto the Petition aforesaid of the said Charity Shorter in the plea aforesaid, which was accordingly issued, directed to the Sheriff of Charles County in form following towit. The State of Maryland Sct To the Sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. We command you that you summon Ignatius Matthews late of Charles County that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second
tuesday of May next to answer the Petition of Charity Shorter preferred against him for Freedom. Hereof he is not to fail, and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honorable Thomas Johnson Esquire Chief Judge of our said Court the 24th day of 

<gap extent="one page" reason="missing page"/>

<pb xml:id="p023" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.002.002"/>

cause of petitioning negroes under the name of Shorter, claiming their Freedom as descendants of a certain Elizabeth Shorter, or her Female ancestors, on the general question touching the right of Elizabeth Shorter or her female ancestors to Freedom under the Laws of this country. And the said Ignatius Matthews by his attorney aforesaid, as before, defends the force and injury when andsoforth and prays leave of the Court here further to imparle until the second tuesday of May next, and to him it is granted; the same day is given to the said Charity Shorter also. At which said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Charity Shorter by his attorney aforesaid, as the said Ignatius Matthews by his attorney aforesaid; And thereupon further process of and open the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is continued until the second Tuesday of October next. At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord One than and seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General Court here, as well the said Charity Shorter by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Ignatius Matthews by his attorney aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further continued until the second tuesday of October next. At which said second tuesday of October in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and nintey four, come again into the General Court here, as well  the said Charity Shorter  by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Ignatius Matthews by his attorney aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid, between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is farther continued until the second tuesday of May next. And now at this day towit, the said second tuesday of May in the year of our Lord One thousand seven hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here as well the said Charity Shorter by her attorney aforesaid as the said Ignatius Matthews in his proper person. And the

<pb xml:id="p024" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.002.003"/>



</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>