<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.021">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Phillis Shorter v. Mary Boarman. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.021</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0536</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1796-05">May 1796</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-26 JG 31</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1796-05">May 1796</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.005217">Shorter, Elizabeth</term>
<term xml:id="per.005225">Shorter, Jenny</term>
<term xml:id="per.005252">Shorter, Teresa</term>
<term xml:id="per.002691">Simms, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005322">
<persName>Shorter, Phillis</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.005315">
<persName>Shorter, Letty</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.005298">
<persName>Boarman, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.004534">
<persName>Wilmer, Jonathan Roberts</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-08-06" who="#kln">transcription, encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p042" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.021.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Phillis Shorter &amp;
Letty her Daughter<lb/>
against<lb/>
Mary Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit on the
ninth day of February in the year of our Lord
one Thousand seven hundred and ninety two, Phillis
Shorter and Letty her Daughter by Gabriel Duvall their
attorney prefer to the Court here their petition for
Freedom against Mary Boarman in form following towit</p>

<p>To the honourable the Judges of the General Court</p>

<p>The Petition of Phillis Shorter humbly sheweth, that she is held in slavery
by Mary Boarman of Charles County together with her child Letty; and
she is advised that she is entitled to her freedom being descended in the
female line from Elizabeth Shorter a free white woman. She therefore prays
your honors the premises being considered &amp; facts proved, to discharge her
&amp; her child from the further service of the said Mary Boarman and she
is in duty bound will pray &amp;soforth.</p>

<p>G Duvall for Petr.</p>

<p>Thereupon it is ordered by the Court here that the writ of the State of Maryland 
of Subpena ad respondendum issue against the said Mary Boarman to answer
unto the said Petition &amp;soforth and the same issues inform following towit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sst To the Sheriff of Charles County Greeting We command 
you that you Summons Mary Boarman that all delay and excuses set aside 
she be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the
City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of May next to answer unto the
Petition of Phillis Shorter &amp; Letty her Daughter preferred against her for freedom
hereof she is not to fail, and fail not at your peril, and have you then
and there this writ witness the Honble Samuel Chase Esquire Chief
Judge of our said Court the 29 day of December Anno Domini 1792.</p>

<p>Issued the 20th day of December 1792. GD. Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>The same day is given to the Petitioners andsoforth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the fourteenth day of the 
same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three
and the day of the return of the aforegoing writ comes into the General Court
here the said Phillis Shorter &amp; Letty her Daughter by their attorney aforesaid and
the Sheriff of Charles County to whom the said writ was in form aforesaid
directed makes return to the Court here thus endorsed towit.</p>

<p>"NE. James Simmes Sheriff"</p>

<p><catchwords>and</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p043" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.021.002"/>

And the said Mary Boarman by Philip Barton Key her attorney appears
voluntarily in Court here and defends the force and injury when andsoforth
and prays leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of October
next, and to her it is granted, the same day is given to the petitioners also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the eighth day of the 
same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and
ninety three, to which said day the said Mary Boarman had leave to imparle
come again into the General Court here as well the petitioners as the Defendant
by their attornies, and the said Mary Boarman by her said attorney (as
before) defends the force and injury when adsoforth and prays further
leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next
and to her it is granted, the same day is given to the Petitioners also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth day of the
same month in the year of our Lord one Thousand Seven hundred and 
ninety four, to which said day the said Mary Boarman had leave to
imparle come again into the General Court here as well the petitioners
as the Defendant by their attornies and the said Mary Boarman by
her said attorney (as before) defends the force and injury when andsoforth
and prays further leave of the Court here to imparle untill the second
Tuesday of October next, and to her it is granted the same day is given
to the Petitioners also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the same
month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four to
which said day the said Mary Boarman had further leave to imparle come again
into the General Court as well the Petitioners as the Defendant by their attornies
and the said Mary Boarman by her said attorney (as before) defends the force
and injury when and soforth, and prays further leave of the Court here to
imparle untill the second Tuesday of May next; and to her it is granted
the same day is given to the said Petitioners also.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the twelfth day of 
the same month in the year of our Lord one Thousand Seven hundred
and ninety five to which day the said Mary Boarman had leave to imparle
come again into the General Court here as well the petitioners as the
Defendant by their attornies, and the said Mary Boarman (as before) defends
the force and injury when andsoforth, and prays further leave of the Court
here to imparle untill the Second Tuesday of October next, and to her
it is granted the same day is given to the Petitioners also.</p>

<p>At which said Second Tuesday of October being the thirteenth day of the
same month in the year of our Lord one Thousand seven hundred and 
ninety five to which said day the said Mary Boarman has leave to 
imparle come again into the General Court here as well the
Petitioners as the Defendant by their attornies. And the said Phillis
Shorter and Letty her Daughter file in Court here the
following Deposition towit (here insert the Deposition of Terry Shorter
<gap extent="one or two lines" reason="incomplete image"/>

<pb xml:id="p044" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.021.003"/>

said attorney (as before) defends the force and injury when andsoforth
and prays further leave of the Court here to imparle until the second 
Tuesday of May next, and to her it is granted the same day is given
to the said Petitioners also.</p>

<p>And Now at this day towit the said second Tuesday of May being 
the tenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand
seven hundred and ninety six, to which said day the said Mary Boarman
had leave to imparle come again into the General Court here as
well the petitioners as the Defendant by their attornies. and the said
Phillis Shorter and Letty her Daughter by Jonathan Roberts Wilmer
their attorney file in Court here the following Deposition towit.
(here insert the Deposition of Jenny Shorter as entered in page 41)
Whereupon all and singular the premises between the parties
aforesaid by the Court here being seen heard and fully understood and
mature deliberation thereupon had for that it appears to the Court here
that the said Phillis Shorter and Letty her Daughter the Petitioners aforesaid
are entitled to their freedom as they by their Petition to the Court here
have alledged. Therefore it is considered by the Court here that
the said Phillis Shorter and Letty her Daughter the Petitioners aforesaid be free
and discharged of and from the service of the said Mary Boarman and that
they the said Phillis Shorter and Letty her Daughter the Petitioners aforesaid
go thereof within 1 day &amp;c. It is further Considered by the Court here
that the said Phillis Shorter and Letty her Daughter recover against the said
Mary Boarman the quantity of six hundred and forty three pounds of Tobacco
by the Court here unto them on their assent adjudged for their costs
and charges by them about the prosecution of their petition laid
out and expended, and that they have thereof their execution &amp;ca.</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clk</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
