<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0028.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Peter, et al. v. Susanna Elliott and Rachell Elliott. Judgment Record.</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Krohn, Esme M." xml:id="emk">Esme M. Krohn</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0028.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0682</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1787-04">April 1787</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Eastern Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S482-2</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1787-04">April 1787</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.007075">Carter, Henry, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.007076">Cockey, Susanna</term>
<term xml:id="per.007078">Downes, Charles</term>
<term xml:id="per.006922">Earle, James, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.007081">Elliott, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.007082">Elliott, Thomas</term>
<term xml:id="per.007083">Earickson, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.007074">Isaac</term>
<term xml:id="per.006926">Ridgaway, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.007085">Ringgold, Jacob</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">   
<term>Queen Ann's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Baltimore (Md.)</term>
<term>Kent Island (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term>Judgment for Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007053">
<persName>Peter</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007054">
<persName>Will</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007055">
<persName>Jack</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007052">
<persName>Amos</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007056">
<persName>Joe</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007057">
<persName>Job</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007058">
<persName>Sam</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007059">
<persName>Cesar</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007060">
<persName>Phillis</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007061">
<persName>Violet</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007062">
<persName>Sabina</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007063">
<persName>Sal</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007064">
<persName>Darkey</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007065">
<persName>Rose</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007066">
<persName>Peg</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007067">
<persName>Nan</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007068">
<persName>Esther</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007069">
<persName>Dinah</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007070">
<persName>Andrew</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007071">
<persName>Fann</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007072">
<persName>Sue</persName> 
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.007073">
<persName>Daniel</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.007079"> 
<persName>Elliot, Susanna</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.007080"> 
<persName>Elliot, Rachell</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.006984">
<persName>Wright, Robert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.006932">
<persName>Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>
<change when="2023-07-21" who="#kln">Reviewed, edited.</change>              
<change when="2023-06-08" who="#emk">Transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" n="IMG_8170.jpg"/>

<p>This Judgment was rendered at September Term 1786. vide page 456</p>

<p>Negroes, Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, 
Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis, Violet, 
Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan,
Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue &amp;
Daniel<lb/>
against<lb/>
Susanna Elliot &amp; Rachell Elliot 
Executrix's of John Elliot</p>

<p>Be it remembered that the second
Tuesday of April to wit on the fourteenth
day of the same month Anno Domini
One thousand seven hundred and eighty
five, the aforesaid Negroes Peter, 
Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam,
Cesar, Phillis, <sic>Vioelett</sic>, Sabina, Sal
Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther,
Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, and
Daniel by Robert Wright their Attorney presented to the Judges of our General 
Court here, the following Petition, to wit: To the honorable the Judges
of the General Court. The Petition of the following Negroes, to wit, Peter
Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis Violet, Sabina, Sal,
Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, Daniel

<pb xml:id="p002" n="IMG_8171.jpg"/>

humbly sheweth, that they are unjustly detained as Slaves by Susanna
Elliott and Rachell Elliott, Executrixes of John Elliott, deceased, of Queen
Ann's County, they therefore pray your honors to grant them a Subpenea
against the said Susanna and Rachel, to answer to their complaint afd
and to give them such Relief herein as to your honors may seem meet,
&amp;c and on Duty &amp;ca. Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar
Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah
Andrew, Fann, Sue, Daniel which being read and heard, mature
deliberation being thereupon had, it was ruled and ordered by the Court,
that Summons issue against the said Susanna Elliott and Rachell Elliott,
Executrixes of John Elliott, for them to appear here this Term to answer
to the Petition aforesaid; which Issued accordingly, and was by the Sheriff
of Queen Ann's County, to whom the same writ was directed, <sic>retured</sic>
endorsed. "Summoned Sam Ridgaway Sheriff."</p>

<p>At which said Court, that is to say, the second Tuesday of April
Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred and eighty five came as well
the said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis,
Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew,
Fann, Sue, and Daniel, by Robert Wright their Attorney as the said
Susanna Elliott and Rachel Elliott Executrixs of John Elliott by Gustavus 
Scott their Attorney. Thereupon it was ordered by the Court here, that
the said Susanna Elliott, and Rachel Elliott Executors of John Elliott
enter into Recognizance with good security, that they will not transport the 
said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam Cesar, Phillis, Violet 
Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann
Sue, and Daniel; but shall suffer and permit them the said Negroes 
to appear at the next General Court, the Second Tuesday of September next, to prove unto their petition for freedom and at all times to suffer the said Negroes, or any of them, 
to have reasonable time to advise with their Counsel on their said
Petition: Whereupon Thomas Elliott of Queen Ann's County present 
here in Court acknowledge himself to owe and stand justly indebted

<pb xml:id="p003" n="IMG_8172.jpg"/>

unto the State of Maryland in the sum of one thousand pounds current
money to be made and levied of his body, Goods and Chattels, Lands, and 
Tenements to and for the use of the said State, in case the said Susanna
Elliott and Rachell Elliott Executrix's of John Elliot shall transport the 
said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis, Violet
Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue,
and Daniel or shall not permit them the said Negroes to appear at the
next General Court, the second Tuesday of September next to prosecute their
said Petition for freedom or shall not suffer the said Negroes or any of them
to have reasonable time to advise with their Counsel, on their said Petition
and herewith he acknowledges himself to be content: Thereupon the 
said Cause is Continued until the second Tuesday of September next
At which said second Tuesday of September Anno Domini seventeen
hundred and eighty five, came as well the said Negroes Peter, Will,
Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey
Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, and Daniel by their Attorney 
aforesaid, as the aforesaid Susanna Elliott and Rachell Executrix's as
aforesaid, by their attorney aforesaid; and the said Negroes Peter, Will, 
Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey
Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, and Daniel by
their attorney aforesaid files in Court here the following Deed of Manumission, 
to wit: Queen Ann's County, to wit; October 28th 1784, The following
Instrument of writing was brought to be Recorded, Vizt. Know all
men by these presents, that I John Elliott of Kent Island, Queen Ann's County
in the State of Maryland, do hereby give and grant full Liberty Freedom
and Manumission (which Liberty, Freedom and Manumission shall commence 
on the twenty fifth day of December next) to each and every 
one of my Slaves called and known by the names as follow, to wit, Negro

<pb xml:id="p004" n="IMG_8173.jpg"/>

Man Peter aged forty five years, negro Man Will aged thirty eight years,
negro Man Jack aged thirty two, negro man Amos aged twenty five, 
Negro Man Joe, aged twenty two, negro man Job aged twenty, Negro Lad
Sam aged nineteen, Negro Lad Cesar aged sixteen, Negro Woman Phillis 
aged forty nine, negro woman Violet aged forty seven, negro woman Sabina
aged thirty one negro woman Sal aged thirty, Negro Woman Darkey aged
twenty four, Negro Woman Rose aged twenty five, Negro woman Peg aged
Seventeen, Negro Girl Nan aged fourteen, Negro Girl Esther aged thirteen,
Negro Girl Dinah aged nine, negro Boy Andrew aged nine years, Negro
Girl Fann aged three, Negro Girl Sue aged two years and Six Months, Negro
boy Daniel aged eight months, Negro boy Isaac aged twelve months.</p>

<p>Witness my hand and Seal this twenty third day of October seventeen 
hundred and eighty four.</p>

<p>John Elliott (Seal)</p>

<p>Test. Wm Earickson, Henry Carter Jr.</p>

<p>I hereby Certify, that on the twenty third day of October seventeen hundred
and eighty four, John Elliott appeared before me, and acknowledged the within
Instrument of writing to be his act and Deed for the purposes within mentioned</p>

<p>Jacob Ringgold<lb/>
True Copy <unclear>P</unclear> C. Downes Clk.</p>

<p>And the aforesaid Susanna Elliott and Rachell Elliott by their Attorney
aforesaid, produces in Court here William <sic>Errickson</sic>, who being sworn
in open Court upon the holy Evangels of Almighty God respecting the subject
of the above Petition, deposeth, and saith, that he was present on the twenty
third day of October in the year seventeen hundred and eighty four at the
Execution of a Deed by John Elliott for the <sic>Mannumission</sic> of all his
Negroes, which he said were in number twenty three. That John Elliott
was at that time in a very low State of Health as a man could well
be to exist one minute after the other. That the said John Elliott
on that day kept his Bed, and was not able to set up, and only

<pb xml:id="p005" n="IMG_8174.jpg"/>

did so for the purpose of signing the Deed. That he had been in a very
lingering low way for two Months more or less. That the Deponent can't recollect
how long he liv'd after this, it might be ten days or a Fortnight. That the
Deponent lived about a Mile from the said Elliott. That the Deponent
<sic>say</sic> him two or three times or perhaps more after this and before his Death.
That he heard from him almost every day. That at the time of the Execution
of the Deed he, the deceased, expected his Death momentarily, and seemed to
hurry those that were about him respecting the Business; for that he expected
his Fever every moment and when it raised it might kill him, for that he 
was but a Shell, and upon that Business depended his Salvation. That
the Deponent had been very intimate with Elliott during his Life, and
it was Elliott's opinion for the last five years of his Life that his Negroes
ought to be set free, but he declined doing it because it was against the
Interest of the Public. That the Deponent believes the mind of Elliott was 
perfectly composed at the time of the Execution of the Deed, and that the next day
this Deponent conversed with him upon what he had done, and the deceased
declared he was <sic>extremly</sic> pleased and <sic>woud</sic> not have it otherwise for all the world
and ten thousand worlds. That the said Elliott never had any such disease
after the Execution of the Deed <sic>untill</sic> he died; but the Deponent used to hear of him
every day and that he was sometimes better in the morning and worse in the Evening
that the Deponent never saw him out of his Bed after the signing of the Deed;
till he saw him a Corpse. On being cross examined, the Deponent further 
saith, that he Elliott had been in a low, wasting consumptive State for two
Months before the above Transaction, That he had not been a hearty man
for several years. That the Deponent has heard Elliott often complain
of his Stomach and a Cough, and that the Deponent considered his Complaint  
at the time he executed the Deed, not as a new Complaint, but only
an Increase of his old Disorder. That the Deponent believes the deceased
never had a hope of his Recovery after he executed the Deed. That the

<pb xml:id="p006" n="IMG_8175.jpg"/>

Deponent has often heard the deceased, before he executed the Deed, say he
should not over it. that he heard him say this in his Room. That two 
months before he signed the Deed, Elliott used to visit his Neighbours
now and then, but was in general very much at home, and not fond of going
abroad. That about a Fortnight before he executed the said Deed, he
the Deponent heard Elliot say that if all the Negroes <sic>coud</sic> be sent away,
he <sic>woud</sic> very <sic>chearfully</sic> set his own free; but thought it <sic>coud</sic> not be done
without prejudicing the Public, which <sic>which</sic> amazed the Deponent more.
when he so soon after set them free. And further the Deponent saith not.
And also produce in Court here Thomas Elliott who being also sworn in open
Court upon the holy Evangels of Almighty God respecting the Subject aforesaid
deposeth and saith, That he was present at his Brother's house when the Deed
was Executed. He sent for him. That his said Brother was in such a State
of Health, that he thought he <sic>coud</sic> not live but a very few days. That the
said deceased died on the eighth day of November at about eleven o'Clock at
Night, having executed the Deed on the twenty third day of October. That
the Deponent saw him two or three times or more between the Execution
of the Deed and the Death of his Brother That he lived about four miles
from him, and went to see him as often as he <sic>coud</sic>, being his only Brother
That there were <sic>markes</sic> of an <sic>Inflamation</sic> about his Throat and breast at the
time and before he executed the Deed, and that these appeared worse after till
he died. That the Deponent did not think he <sic>coud</sic> have lived so Long as he 
did after he executed the Deed. That the Deponent went to Baltimore
before the Deed was executed and <sic>than</sic> thought he never <sic>shoud</sic> see his Brother 
again. That the Marks of the <sic>Inflamation</sic> appeared to the best of his 
the Deponents recollections about a Fortnight before he executed the Deed.
That the said <sic>Inflamation</sic> in his Throat and breast certainly was the cause
of his Death. The Deponent and his Brother, the Deceased, had frequent
Conversations together, before he executed the Deed, about the Subject of

<pb xml:id="p007" n="IMG_8176.jpg"/>

manumitting his Negroes. That the deceased was against the mode of setting
Negroes free; but if they all <sic>cou'd</sic> be sent away to same, he <sic>shou'd</sic> not be
against it That when he was sick, this Deponent heard him say the same
thing, and was also much surprised when he was sent for by his Brother
to find he was about to set his Negroes free. That the mind of his Brother
must have been weakened when he executed the Deed, but it seemed to be 
well composed. The Deponent does not know that any person recommended
this measure to his Brother, but supposed some of the Girls had done so, as 
they were Methodists. That the Deponent accused two of his Daughters, but
they denied it, and were against the Proceedings. That the deceased was a member
of the Church of England. That after the Execution of the Deed untill his death,
the Deponent believes his Brother never left his room, nor his Bed, except to
set down by it occasionally whilst they were making up his Bed, and not then
without assistance. On being cross examined, the Deponent further saith,
That for some time, perhaps four or five months before he was confined to his
room, he was in a low State of Health, and was troubled with a Cough
and Spitting. That the Deponent imagines it was an Increase of his
Cough and spitting that was the cause of his death. That he was also in a Decay
for about the same Time before his confinement, and had an <sic>Inflamation</sic>
in his Throat and Breast, which together with his cough and spitting occasioned 
his Death. That the Deponent was with his Brother the day before he died
and at the time of it. That this Deponent cannot say when he saw his Brother
for the first time after the Execution of the Deed and before his Death. That it was
from the information of the Deponent's mother, and being there himself now and 
then, that he believes his Brother was unable to leave his Bed without
assistance. That the Deponent never thought it worth his while to converse
with the deceased about the Manumission of his Negroes after he executed
the Deed, and further this Deponent saith not.</p>

<p>And also produce in Court here Henry Carter Junior 

<pb xml:id="p008" n="IMG_8177.jpg"/>

who also being sworn in open Court on the holy Evangels respecting the 
Subject of the above Petition deposeth and saith he was present at the Execution
of a Deed by John Elliot deceased for the Manumission of all his Negroes which
deed he believes was Executed on the twenty third day of October last. John 
Elliott's State of health at that time appeared to be very desperate. He
was then confined to his Bed and unable to move about without help
or to leave his bed. John Elliot lived afterwards untill the 8th day of 
the November following. this Deponent saw the said John Elliot frequently
after the Execution of the Deed sometimes twice a day. Sometimes every 
day &amp; sometimes every other day, he supposes at least 8 or 10 different
times before his Death, and his State of health appeared to this Deponent
to be worse and worse every time he was him; and the said John Elliot himself
told the Deponent frequently in answer to his inquiries about his heath,
that he was not better. Elliott complained of a Bad Cough &amp; Spitting, &amp; an
<sic>inflamation</sic> in his throat and Breast. It was thought the <sic>inflamation</sic>
killed him and it mortified. his throat was sore &amp; frequently washed.
This Deponent lived within about three quarters of a mile of the said
John Elliot at the time of the Execution of the Deed &amp; untill his Death.
He believes from what he saw that John Elliot from the time of the Execution
of the Deed, to the time of his Death, never left his bed, but for the purpose 
of having it made up, and then not without assistance. On Cross examination 
this Deponent saith, he hath known John Elliott a long time.
for five or six months before his death he was poorly, but till about 
the middle of August, he was able to go a fishing, and that was he believes
the last time he went a fishing. After that time his health was worse,
but he used at times to come over to see this Deponent, it being but a 
Little distance he believes after the middle of August he was not able to go 
fishing, and he seemed otherwise disposed, and to have become
religious; &amp; he believes after this time he continued still worse

<pb xml:id="p009" n="IMG_8178.jpg"/>

and from indisposition cou'd not have gone fishing without fatigue.
John Elliot did live about a quarter of a mile from the head of a Creek,
where he usually kept his Canoe, but when he went fish was further.
John Elliot was very fond of fishing. He this Deponent never heard John 
Elliott say any thing about setting his Negroes free, but hath heard him 
say it would be of bad Consequence to his Neighbour Long, if he set his
Negroes free. This Deponent thinks John Elliott was confined to his
house about the beginning of October, and from that time grew worse.</p>

<p>He was confined to his house from this time, weak &amp; low spirited, but
moved about from Room to Room, &amp; sometimes to the Rooms above
Stairs. This Deponent did not discover that John Elliott's understanding
was at this time impaired; but whether it was the case at the time
of the Execution of the Deed, this Deponent cannot undertake to say;
nor what was the State of his mind, from the execution of the Deed,
to the time of his death: never had any conversation with him
on that subject afterwards: nor does this Deponent know that
John Elliot was in a better Disposition of mind after the manumission, 
then at the time when it was made; and saith, that
John Elliott executed his will on the same day, on which he executed
the deed for the Manumission of his Slaves: but the Will was executed
last, &amp; after dark as this Deponent recollects. The Deed was executed
pretty late in the Evening. Thereupon the said Cause was 
continued until the second Tuesday of April next. At which said
Second Tuesday of April Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred
and eight six came again as well the said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos
Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, 
Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, and Daniel by their Attorney 
aforesaid, as the said Susanna Elliott and Rachell Elliott by their 
Attorney aforesaid; and the aforesaid Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos

<pb xml:id="p010" n="IMG_8179.jpg"/>

Joe, Job, Sam, <sic>Casar</sic>, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose
Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fan, Sue, and Daniel by their 
Attorney aforesaid produces in Court here Doctor Jacob Ringgold
aged about thirty four years and being sworn in open Court 
on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God deposeth and saith, that on the day that 
John Elliott executed the Deed of Manumission, a negro slave of Elliott
came to the deponents house, and told him the deponent that his Master
Mr. Elliott wanted to see him. The deponent went to Mr. Elliott's the 
same day, and when he the deponent, went into Mr. Elliott's room, he
informed the deponent, that he Elliott wanted to manumit his Slaves
and had sent for the deponent, to have it done; The deponent observed,
to Elliott that it was a matter of Consequence and deserved consideration
and asked Elliott if he had considered it well that Elliot informed
him he had. The deponent saith that he then took a List of his 
Slaves, retired into another room and drew the deed of Manumission,
and returned then and read it to him, and asked Elliot if it was
agreeable to his intentions, who answered it was. The deponent then 
returned into the room where he drew the deed, to obtain Evidences
to the deed and called on William <sic>Erickson</sic> who at first refused saying
that he could not think that Mr. Elliott was in his Senses as he had
expressed great <sic>abherience</sic> to the measure a few days before, and 
conceived it to be highly injurious to the Country. The deponent then 
returned to Mr. Elliott, and told Elliott that there was a suspicion 
among some of his Neighbours that he Mr. Elliot was not in his
senses, because that he Mr. Elliot, had expressed contrary sentiment 
two or three days before that Mr. Elliot, in a <sic>fretfull</sic> manner answered
that such changes could be done in an Instant signifying that it
was an act of divine providence. The deponent further saith, that
Mr. Elliott said that his conscience was extremely uneasy, and that

<pb xml:id="p011" n="IMG_8180.jpg"/>

he could not rest until he had set the Negroes free. The deponent
saith, that Mr. Elliott, from his conduct and conversation in the
<sic>oppinion</sic> of the Deponent, appeared to be perfectly in his senses at 
the time of the Conversation above mentioned, and also at the time of
the execution of the said Deed. The deponent then went into the room
where Mr. <sic>Erckson</sic> was and informed him that he the deponent thought
and was perfectly satisfied that Mr. Elliot was perfectly in his senses,
and prevailed with Mr. <sic>Erickson</sic> to be a Witness. which he accordingly
was. The deponent at the time of executing the deed, asked Mr. Elliot
his complaint who from what he the deponent could collect from Elliot,
laboured under an inflammation, in the breast that Mr. Elliot, had
laboured under this complaint for some considerable time before;
The deponent saith that at the time above mentioned he did not
discover any symptoms of a speedy death, but that he the deponent thought
there was no hopes of a recovery. The deponent saith that after the execution
of the deed Mr. Elliott requested him the deponent to draw his Will,
which he the deponent attempted to do but not pleasing him Mr. Elliott
declined as it grew late in the day, and obliged Mr. Elliott to set some other
person to do it. The deponent saith that he was acquainted with Mr. Elliott, 
seven, eight or nine years before, and he appeared to be an infirm
person, tho in the opinions of the deponent he Mr. Elliot did not appear 
to be in a wasting or Consumptive State. The deponent saith that he 
never saw Mr. Elliott after the day of the execution of the Deed, That
Mr. Elliott appeared to the deponent to be under steady solid impressions,
and not under any religious frenzy; but appeared, perfectly in his
senses and that he Mr. Elliott as the Deponent believes never changed
his religions, and that Mr. Elliott expressed to the deponent his belief 
that he should not recover. The deed was executed in the afternoon 
about four O'Clock.</p>

<p><catchwords>(And)</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p012" n="IMG_8181.jpg"/>

And also produces in Court here, Susanna Cockey aged about
seventy four or five who being sworn in open Court on the holy
<sic>Evangles</sic> of Almighty God deposeth and saith, that she was present
at the time John Elliott, made a deed of manumission and That he was 
as she believes in his perfect senses and knows nothing to the contrary,
and that he was so poorly, that he could not git out of his Bed,
at the time of his making the Deed, and never could afterwards without 
help, and that he never had his <sic>Cloaths</sic> on after, that time. Elliott
at that time and afterwards had an <sic>inflamation</sic>, in his throat and 
breast of which he died, which complaint, he long had laboured under
and she believes, from the harvest before. The deponent further saith
that Elliott made his Will, at the same day with the deed, that 
they both laid on the Table, but that she does not know which was 
executed first. That Mr. Elliott was the Deponent's son, and that she
never had heard him mention any thing of setting his Negroes free
till that day. The Deponent also saith that she lived with her said 
son the chief part of the time he Mr. Elliot was sick; and that She
doth not know whether the will was written, when the deed was
executed or not, that believes it was. Upon Cross examination,
the Deponent saith that at the execution of the deed her said son did not
appear melancholy, nor had he lost his shirts; the Deponent saith
that his said son sent for the <sic>Majestrate</sic> as she believes, of his own
accord but she was not present when he gave the orders for sending 
for the <sic>Majestrate</sic> nor doth she know that he gave such orders. The 
deponent further saith that he said Mr. Elliott, was scarcely ever out 
of his bed from the execution of the afsd deed, to his death, and then only 
to have it made, and was never out of the same room afterwards.
Thereupon the said cause was continued until the second Tuesday 
of September next.</p>

<p><catchwords>(And)</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p013" n="IMG_8182.jpg"/>

And now here at this day to wit, the second Tuesday of September 
Anno Domini one thousand seven hundred and eighty six, come here as
well the aforesaid Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, <sic>Casar</sic>, 
Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Daniel, Andrew
Fan, Sue, and Daniel by their Attorney aforesaid, as the aforesaid Susanna
Elliott and Rachell Elliott by their Attorney aforesaid; and the aforesaid Negroes
Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, <sic>Casar</sic>, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal,
Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue and Daniel by their 
Attorney aforesaid agrees and admits that the Deed of Manumission executed 
by John Elliott deceased on the twenty third day of October in the year
one thousand seven hundred and eighty four, and on which alone
the Petitioners founded their claim to freedom, was executed, Sealed and 
delivered by him the same John Elliott in his last sickness, of which 
said last sickness he died: Whereupon all and singular the premises 
aforesaid and the allegations and Evidence, as well on the part and
behalf of the said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, Cesar
Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew,
Fann, Sue, and Daniel; as also on the part and behalf of the said Susanna 
Elliott and Rachell Elliott, being by the Court here seen heard fully 
understood, and mature deliberation thereupon had; It is considered by
the Judges here that the said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job,
Sam, <sic>Casar</sic>, Phillis, Violet, Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan,
Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue, and Daniel, are not entitled to their 
freedom, and that their said Petition be dismissed. Whereupon the 
said Negroes Peter, Will, Jack, Amos, Joe, Job, Sam, <sic>Casar</sic>, Phillis, Violet,
Sabina, Sal, Darkey, Rose, Peg, Nan, Esther, Dinah, Andrew, Fann, Sue
and Daniel by their attorney aforesaid prays an Appeal from the Judgment
of the Court here in form aforesaid rendered, unto the Judges of the States High
Court of Appeals; and the same is granted unto them, and it ordered by the 

<pb xml:id="p014" n="IMG_8183.jpg"/>

Judges here that a Record of the proceedings be transmitted to the Honorable
the Judges of the high Court of Appeals, and the same is accordingly transmitted.</p>

<p>Test James Earle Clk.</p>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
