<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0013.002">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Anthony Boston v. Gassaway Rawlings. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Anna Krause" xml:id="ak">Anna Krause</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0013.002</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0543</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1793-05">May 1793</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-17 JG 18</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1793-05">May 1793</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term/>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term/>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" >
<persName>Boston, Anthony</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" >
<persName>Rawlings, Gassaway</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" >
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-09" who="#kln">reviewed; finished encoding and transcription</change>
<change when="2019" who="#ak">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Gassaway Rawlings<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Anthony Boston</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that now here on the second tuesday of May being the tenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven and ninety one the justices of Anne Arundel county court in pursuance of the act of assembly in such case made and provided, transmit to the General court here the record and proceedings of a plaint which was lately depending before them in the said County court between Anthony Boston plaintiff and Gassaway Rawlings Defendant, and wherein the said county court gave judgment for the said Anthony Boston against the said Gassaway Rawlings, and from which said Judgment the said Gassaway Rawlings prayed an appeal into the General Court here; the tenor of which said record and proceedings is in the form of following to wit.</p>

<p>Anne Arundel County Sct. At a county court of the state of Maryland begun and held in the City of Annapolis in and for the County aforesaid on the first Monday of November being the first day of the same month in the year 1790.
</p>

<p>Were Present<lb/>
The worshipful Nicholas Worthington<lb/>
Allen Quynn<lb/>
John Brice<lb/>
Robert Couden Gent. Justices<lb/>
Benjamin Howard Esq Sheriff Nich: Harwood Clk.</p>

<p>In the record and proceedings of the same court is the following to wit.</p>

</div2>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.002"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>G.D. Anthony Boston<lb/>
vs<lb/>
WC. Gassaway Rawlings</p>

<p>Petition</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>To the Worshipful the justices of Ann Arundel County court The petition of Anthony Boston humbly sheweth that he is detained in slavery by a certain Gassaway Rawlings of the County aforesaid when he is entitled to freedom being <sic>discended</sic> from a free yellow woman being one of the <sic>portuguies</sic> whose name your petitioner is informed was Catherine Boston Your petitioner therefore prays your worships to take your petitioners case into consideration and discharge him from the service of said Gassaway Rawlings and he as in duty bound will pray &amp;.</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Petr.</p>

<p>Which being read and heard and mature deliberation thereupon had it was ordered that summons us issue against Gassaway Rawlings which issued accordingly and was by the Sheriff of Ann Arundel County to whom the same was directed returned thus endorsed. Summoned David Steuart Sheriff.</p>

<p>And the said Gassaway Rawlings by William Cooke his attorney comes and defends the force and injury when and so forth and prays leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also. At which said next court to wit, the second tuesday in November seventeen hundred and eighty eight come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next Court the first Monday in March seventeen hundred and eighty nine come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the 
<catchwords>Said</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.003"/>

Said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court the first Monday in March seventeen hundred and Eighty nine come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attornies aforesaid and the defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>It is agreed by and between the parties that the depositions of any witnesses taken on three days notice to the adverse party be read as evidence in this cause.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit the first Monday in August seventeen hundred and eighty nine come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit, the first Monday in November seventeen hundred and eighty nine. Come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to Imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit, the first Monday of March seventeen hundred and ninety come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next Court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit the first Monday in August seventeen hundred and ninety come again the said parties plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys aforesaid and the said 
<catchwords>Defendant</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.004"/>

Defendant by his said attorney prays further leave to imparle hereunto untill next court and he hath it and the same day is given to the plaintiff also.</p>

<p>The following depositions were agreed to and read as evidence in this cause.</p>

<p>Anthony Boston<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Gassaway Rawlings</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in Anne Arundel County Court.</p>

<p>July 20 1789. Anne Harwood of Anne Arundel County of lawful age being first duly sworn on the holy Evangels of Almighty God touching her knowledge of the above dispute deposeth and saith that she this Deponent knew old Lenah from whom Anthony the petitioner descended that she the said Lanah has been dead about forty years and died as a part of this deponents fathers estate that she lived with him as a slave and that she this deponent never heard of said Lenah claiming her freedom till lately that she understood said Lenah was brot into this country in a Guinea Ship amongst other slaves and sold as such and was purchased by one Lockwood and she this deponent has been informed who will'd her to Mrs Jones the grandmother to this Deponent which Mrs Jones left her by will to Gassaway Watkins <sic>farther</sic> to this deponent that her complexion was yellow and her hair strait and black that this deponent Never understood said woman was a portugea nor knew what Country she came from and that Anthony Boston was the son of Violet who was the daughter of Lenah and further this Deponent saith not. Sword this 20th July before me one of the justices of Ann Arundel County</p>
<p>James Disney.</p>

<p>Elizabeth Rawlings of Lawful age of Ann Arundel County being duly sworn in the dispute above mentioned deposeth and saith that she knew old Lenah who formerly belonged to Samuel Lockwood upon whose death Mrs Jones the 
<catchwords>Deponents</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.005"/>

Deponents grand mother owned her and after Mrs Jones death she belonged to this deponents father Gassaway Watkins and died his property upwards of forty years ago this deponent never heard that she claimed her freedom. That the complexion was yellow and her hair long and black and tied up it was not woolly like the hair of Negroes she never understood that she received <sic>wagers</sic> from this deponents father and further this deponent saith not. Sworn to this 20th day of July 1789 before the subscriber one of the justices of Anne Arundel County.</p>

<p>Jas. Disney</p>

<p>Richard Watkins being of Lawful age maketh oath that he knew Leaner who belonged to his grand mother Jones and after her decease belonged to his father and died a slave in his service that she was a dark brown Complexion always claimed as a slave and never to the knowledge or belief of Deponent ever claimed any title to her freedom This deponents father held one of her children, John Watkins another and Mrs Elizabeth Smith another who all died slaves and never as the Deponent believes claimed freedom. The <sic>deponant</sic> has heard that Leaner formerly belonged to one Lockwood and that he has heard she came originally from beyond sea. This deponant saith he never heard that Leaners Mother was ever in this Country that he first Knew her fifty years ago and upwards and thinks she was then sixty years of age and very Grey headed This deponent never heard of any other woman named Leaner that lived with Lockwood Mrs Jones or his this deponents father he further saith that he has heard that Lenah was a Spaniard but dont recollect to have heard from what Country the ship Came in which she was brought to this country that he never heard that Lenah wore a golden cross at any time being asked if at the distribution of his fathers estate any of the representatives objected to take any of the descendants of Lenah from an apprehension that they might one day or other get their freedom, Answers no; that they were fond of taking that family they being more trusty about their business.</p>

<p>Sworn in open court 10th March 1790.</p>

<p><catchwords>The</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.006"/>

The Deposition of Richard Richardson of Lawful age being one of the people called Quakers did solemnly Declare and affirm that he knew a woman named Leaner who lived with and was owned by Mrs Jones a widow this affirmant thinks her name was Anne Jones.</p>

<p>This affirmant declares that he always understood and has heard that Leanor formerly belonged to one Lockwood that he always understood and has heard his father say she was imported from beyond Sea in a negro ship and was sold as a slave and up to the time of her death the said Leaner was always held as a slave this deponent says that he never heard of the said womans claiming freedom that she was of a dark brown complexion and this deponent thinks greatly resembled in her complexion and appearance a slave held by his father that was said to have been brought from <sic>Madegascar</sic>. This deponant further saith that his grand father owned three of Leaners children who died in his service and they were held as Slaves and never to his knowledge or belief any title to freedom This deponent knew two other of her children one held by Nicholas Watkins and the other by John Galloway and they died Slaves and never as this deponent believes claimed to be free. This Deponent further says that near 40 years ago he has heard his father say that a negro man one of Leaner children held by Thomas Ratcleff applied to the County court of this county for freedom but that he could make nothing appear to shew her was entitled to it and was order into his masters service by the Court and this Deponents thinks his father said he was <sic>wiped</sic> but is not certain. This deponent say that at the time Leaner lived with Mrs Jones there was another Mulatto or swarthy woman that lived in the family but was no relation to Leaner Being asked if he knew Lenahs Mother saith he never heard she had a mother in this Country. That he knew Lenah upwards of fifty years ago and she was then an Elderly woman when she lived with Mrs Jones affirmed to in open Court 10th March 1790.</p>

<p>Richard Richardson</p>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.007"/>

<p>Plummer Iiams aged 72 years being sworn in this cause says he has seen the petitioner and has understood that he is the son of Violet that he did not know Lenah Boston he has often heard talk of Madam Jones's old Lenah and never heard she or any of her family claimed their freedom untill Captain Thomas Watkins and Samuel Watkins informed him that Daniel the property of the said Samuel claimed his freedom and asked the deponent if he knew anything about it and he answered he did not and further saith not.</p>

<p>Sworn to this 4th day of August 1790 in open Court.</p>

<p>Mary Batson a woman of Colour and born of a free woman whose mother was a free white woman aged between sixty and seventy years being first duly sworn to say the truth in this cause deposeth and saith that she knows the petitioner and has known him from a small boy that she knew Violet his mother ever since the deponent was a small girl that she knew old Lenah Boston many years before she died and that she thinks she has been dead upwards of forty years that this Deponent was born in Ann Arundel County not far from the neighbourhood of Lenah and her descendants and has always resided in Anne Arundel County that Lenah was a bright yellow woman with long black hair which was straight this deponent further saith that she has always understood that Lenah the grandmother of the petitioner was a spanish woman and often has <sic>been</sic> her mother say that she was entitled to be free. This Deponent knew several children of the said Lenah to wit: Daniel, Ned, Tomey, Caesar, Simon, Nat, Bacon Violet, Sarah <unclear>Marcer</unclear> she further saith that the deponents mother was born on the easter shore as she has informed her and that she was brought over when young to Anne Arundel County and was brought up in the Swamp that she was brought up by old Robert Lockwood in the swamp and she has often heard her mother say that she knew the mother of Lenah and she was a spanish woman and that Lenah was very young when she came into this country with her mother and she has often heard her mother say that Lenah's mother died at Robert Loockwoods in his life time and was 
<catchwords><sic>burried</sic></catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.008"/>

Buried there and that she used commonly to wear a golden cross round her neck and that it was buried with her the Deponent being asked how old the Deponents mother was when she was born saith she cannot tell but that her mother had sixteen Children and the deponent was the youngest but two that she has frequently heard her mother say that Lenah's mother took care of her when she was young.</p>

<p>This Deponent further saith that she has understood that Ned one of the sons of Lenah many years ago attempted to get his freedom and that he was stopped at London town when on his way to Annapolis and there whipt and prevented from going further. This deponent saith that she has heard Ned say that he was whipped at London Town and his Indentures Burnt and that he thought he was used very ill and has understood that his masters name was Thomas Ratcliff and further she saith not. Being asked if Lenahs Children were born before she came to this Country says no they were all born in Maryland this deponent says she is now upwards of sixty years old and can remember Lenah ever since she was ten years old Lenah had <sic>therrten</sic> Children. This Deponent being asked how Long Lenah has been dead says near forty years.</p>

<p>Sworn before the subscriber this seventh day of August 1790.</p>

<p>Allen Quynn.</p>

<p>The Deposition of John Welch son of Robert aged sixty two years being Duly sworn in this cause saith that he knew old Lenah who belonged to Gassaway Watkins and whom he got from Mrs Jones his mother she was a bright yellow woman with remarkably long black straight hair; this deponent was young when he knew her and has understood she was an East Indian she had many Children one of which was named Violet if living would be upwards of seventy years of age this deponent knew Violet well When he was about eleven years old and used to see her often and he thinks
<catchwords>she</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.009"/>

she must have been about twelve or fourteen years older than himself This Deponent further saith that about forty seven or forty eight years ago he heard Richard Watkins son of the aforesaid Gassaway Watkins and in his life time curse the said old Lenah and tell her that she wanted to be free but she never would and further he does not remember to have heard of her claiming her freedom. Sworn before me this 3d day of Febry, 1791.</p>

<p>Richd Harwood Junr.</p>

<p>At which said next court to wit, the first Monday of November seventeen hundred and ninety come again as well the said Anthony Boston by his attorney aforesaid as the said Gassaway Rawlings by his attorney aforesaid Whereupon all and singular the premises aforesaid and the allegations and process as well on the part of the aforesaid Anthony Boston as the aforesaid Gassaway Rawlings being by the Court here seen heard fully understood and mature Deliberation thereupon had.</p>

<p>It is considered by the justices here that the said Anthony Boston of and from any future servitude to the aforesaid Gassaway Rawlings be hence discharged and freed.</p>

<p>And it is also considered that the said Anthony Boston recover against the said Gassaway Rawlings the sum of seven hundred and sixty one and two fifths pound of tobacco by the court hereunto him on his assent adjudged for his costs and Charges by him laid out and expended by occasion of the premises andsoforth.</p>

<p>Whereupon the said Gassaway Rawlings by his attorney aforesaid prays an appeal from the judgment aforesaid so as aforesaid rendered to the general court and the same is granted.</p>

<p>(Seal) In Testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal of office this 4th day of May in the year 1791.</p>

<p>Nich: Harwood Clk</p>

<p><catchwords>And</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.010"/>

And now here comes into the said General court as well the said Gassaway Rawlings by William Cooke his attorney as the said Anthony Boston by Gabriel Duvall his attorney and thereupon on motion of the said Anthony Boston by his attorney aforesaid it is ruled by the Court here that the said Gassaway Rawlings assign the errors in the record and proceedings aforesaid, or judgment by the Court here will be rendered against him in default thereof and the said Gassaway Rawlings by his attorney aforesaid prays a day in court here untill the second Tuesday of October next to assign errors in the record and proceedings of the judgment aforesaid; and he hath it: the same day is given to the said Gassaway  Ralwings &amp;c. And now at this day towit the said second tuesday of October being the eleventh day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety one which said day was given to the said Gassaway Rawlings to assign errors in the record and proceedings of the judgment aforesaid come again into the General Court here the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid and the said Gassaway Rawlings by his attorney aforesaid says that in the record and proceedings aforesaid and also in the given of Judgment aforesaid there is manifest error in this, to wit that  by the record aforesaid it appears that the judgment aforesaid in the plaint aforesaid given was given for the said Anthony Boston against the said Gassaway Rawlings when by the law of the land that judgment ought to have been given for the said Gassaway Rawlings against the said Anthony Boston therefore in that there is manifest error and he prays that the judgment aforesaid for that error and others being in the record and proceedings aforesaid may be reversed annulled and held entirely as void and that he the said Gassaway Rawlings may be restored to all he has lost by occasion of the said Judgment; and that the said Anthony Boston may rejoin to the errors aforesaid &amp;c.</p>

<p>And the said Anthony Boston by his attorney aforesaid <catchwords>says</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.011"/>

says there is no error in the record and proceedings aforesaid or in the
rendition of the judgment aforesaid and prays likewise that the court
here may proceed to the examination of the matters aforesaid by the said
Gassaway Rawlings above for errors assigned and that the said
Judgment may be in all things affirmed &amp;c.</p>

<p>Whereupon by consent of the parties aforesaid by their attornies
aforesaid leave is given by the court here for either of the said parties
to take depositions of witnesses on giving five days exparte notice and that
such depositions be admitted in evidence on the hearing of this cause
and thereupon with the consent of the parties aforesaid by their
attorneys aforesaid and with the leave of the court here the said
Parties file in court here certain depositions <sic>admited</sic> to be received
and read in this cause and which said depositions are in the words 
following to wit.</p>

<p>Anthony Boston<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Gassaway Rawlings</p>

<p>Petition for freedom.</p>

<p>The Deposition of Robert John Smith of Ann Arundel
County aged forty four years or thereabouts being
first duly sworn on the holy evangelist of Almighty
god saith. That he was born in Annapolis and served his apprenticeship
in the neighbourhood where Gassaway Watkins deceased liv'd and that
he never knew the person called Lenah nor ever in his life heard that such
person or her descendants were entitled to their freedom untill about eight
or ten years since and that he at no time ever had any conversation
with either John Tydings or Joseph Mayo deceased respecting Daniel the
slave of Samuel Watkins, brother of Gassaway Watkins, but that about eight
or ten years ago the time above alluded to, he recollects having a
Conversation with the said Samuel Watkins the master of said Daniel in
which the said Samuel said that there was a talk that the said Daniel
intended to try to get free, but that he was quite easy about it, for that
he was no more entitled to freedom than that boy Jacob alluding to a
boy then present who was then a slave of the said Samuel and 
still continues a slave in possession of his widow and further this
Deponent says not.</p>

<p>Robt J. Smith.</p>

<p>Sworn before Sam Chase.</p>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.011"/>

<p>Gaaassaway Rawlings<lb/>
Against<lb/>
Anthony Boston</p>

<p>In the General court.</p>

<p>The deposition of Ann Watkins of Anne
Arundel County of lawful age being first duly
sworn on the holy evangels of Almighty God
saith that she knows the defendant in this suit but knew
nothing of his mother or grandmother that she has often heard old
people in the neighbourhood talk about old Lenah, but does not
remember the particulars of such conversation except one; that
about thirty years ago or nearly about that time, <sic>their</sic> was a
report that the <sic>desendants</sic> of <sic>som</sic> woman named Lenah intended
to try to get free and Mr Thomas Sprigg deceased came to the house of
Margaret Watkins the mother of this deponents husband and with whom
this deponents husband then lived, and asked Margaret Watkins if she
had heard it and said they were going to try to get free to which 
the said Margaret Watkins answered that they ought to be free and
that it was then right upon which Mr Sprigg told her to be still
about it and said he had some of them. This deponent has often
heard her mother in law talk about Lenah and she always
said she was no slave and that she was not counted a slave by the 
family and she further saith that her mother in law has been <sic>cleared</sic>
about sixteen years, and was an old woman when she died perhaps
about sixty years of age that she was the daughter of John Lamb and
Elizabeth his wife who lived in Anne Arundel County near Queen
Anne and was the wife of Nicholas Watkins who has been dead
upwards of twenty years and this deponent believes was eighty years
old or upwards when he died, and she has heard him say that
Lenah and her family ought to be free. Being asked if she heard Mr
Watkins or Mrs Watkins give any reason why Lenah ought to be free
says she did not. Sworn to this fourth day of June 1791. before
Jno Brice.</p>

<p>Anthony Boston<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Gassaway Rawlings</p>

<p><sic>Retition</sic> for freedom.</p>

<p>The deposition of John Tydings of Ann Arundel
County aged sixty one years or thereabouts being
first duly sworn on the holy evangels of Almighty
<catchwords>God</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.002.012"/>

God saith that he knew old Lenah who he understands formerly lived with
Robert Lockwood, and afterwards was in the family of Mr Jones and
afterwards in that of Gassaway Watkins. That he knew Lenah when she lived with
Robert Lockwood, and afterwards was in the family of Mr Jones and
afterwards in that of Gassaway Watkins. That he knew Lenah when she lived
at Mr Watkins's forty odd years ago, she was a yellow woman, and the
deponent thinks he never saw a person of her complexion before nor since
she had long black <sic>straght</sic> hair like the hair of an Indian and he further
saith that about seven or eight years ago he happened at the house of Joseph
Mayo since late deceased and the said Joseph Mayo mentioned that
he had heard that Mrs Watkins's Daniel was making a move to get free,
and asked this deponent if he had heard it, to which he answered that he
had and on being asked by the said John Mayo of whom he heard it this
deponent replied of Robert Smith; by said Mr Mayo, Smith knows every
thing; the said Joseph Mayo observed that he believed they had let it
alone <sic>to</sic> long and said he knew old Lenah when she lived with one
Lockwood and that she was as free as he was; but did not mention
how she was entitled to her freedom and told this deponent when he</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>