<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.001">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Basil Shorter v. Henry Rozier. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0516</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>
Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1794-10">October 1794</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-23 JG 25</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1794-10">October 1794</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Baden, Robert</term>
<term>Chase, Samuel</term>
<term>Clements, John</term>
<term>Craufurd, David</term>
<term>Cresap, James</term>
<term>Crist, Henry</term>
<term>Duckett, Thomas</term>
<term>Gates, James</term>
<term>Gordon, William</term>
<term>Green, Giles</term>
<term>Gwinn, John</term>
<term>Hall, Dorothy</term>
<term>Hamilton, Patrick</term>
<term>Hammond, William</term>
<term>Hanson, Walter</term>
<term>Hellen, Thomas</term>
<term>Hungerford, Benjamim</term>
<term>Jackson, William John</term>
<term>Jones, Stephen</term>
<term>Lingan, Thomas</term>
<term>Magruder, John R., Jr.</term>
<term>McAtee, John</term>
<term>McComas, William</term>
<term>Onion, John Barrett</term>
<term>Richardson, Benjamin</term>
<term>Shorter, Elizabeth</term>
<term>Stone, Michael Jenifer</term>
<term>Wailes, Edward Lloyd</term>
<term>Young, Notley</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
<term>Upper Marlboro (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
<term>Appealed by Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Basil</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Rozier, Henry</persName><!-- Rozer -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gantt, John Mackall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Dorsey, William Hammond</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-06-05" who="#kln">reviewed transcription, encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p020" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Henry Rozier</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Ha Cor. Petition for Freedom Issues Joined Jurors return and find for the Petitioner upon both Issues. Depositions filed Exception and Copy of a Record filed</p>

<p>Therefore it is considered by the Judges of the Court here that the Petitioner be free and discharged from all further servitude: And that the said Henry Rozier pay him the costs of prosecuting his petition.</p>

<p>Appeal prayed and granted to the High Court of Appeals. Ordered that the proceedings be transmitted.</p>

<list>
<item>1 John Barrett Onion</item>
<item>2 William Gordon</item>
<item>3 James Cresap</item>
<item>4 Henry Crist</item>
<item>5 Benja Hungerford</item>
<item>6 Thomas Hellen</item>
<item>7 Benja Richardson</item>
<item>8 William Hammond</item>
<item>9 Thomas Lingan</item>
<item>10 Robert Baden</item>
<item>11 William McComas</item>
<item>12 Stephen Jones</item>
</list>

</div2>

<gap extent="about 220 pages"/>

<pb xml:id="p242" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.002.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Henry Rozer</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore <unclear>towit</unclear> on the seventeenth day of June in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, the Petitioner by Gabriel Duvall his Attorney sued forth out of the General Court here the writ of the State of Maryland of Certiorari to the Justices of Prince Georges County directed in the words and of the tenor following, to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sct To the Justices of Prince Georges County, Greeting. Whereas lately in our said Court Henry Rozier late of Prince Georges County, was summoned to answer unto Basil Shorter of a Plea for Freedom which said Plea is still depending before you our said Justices in our said County Court, as it is said, undetermined and we being desirous for certain reasons, that the record and Proceeding in the plea aforesaid should by you be certified to us, do command you, that you send under your seals, the record of the Proceedings aforesaid in the Plea aforesaid, with all things touching the same, into our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis the second Tuesday of October next plainly and distinctly and in as full and ample manner, as it now remains before you, together with this Writ so that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what shall appear to us of right ought to be done. Witness the Honourable Samuel Chase Esquire, Chief Judge of our said Court the thirty first day of May Anno Domini 1794.</p>

<p>Issued the 17th day of June 1794.</p>

<p>Jno Gwinn Cl</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four comes here into the General Court the said Basil Shorter by his Attorney aforesaid and the Justices of Prince

<pb xml:id="p243" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.003.jpg"/>

Georges County in pursuance of the command of the said writ make return of a certain Record of Proceedings in the Plea aforesaid in the words and of the Tenor following, to wit</p>

<p>Prince Georges County, to wit.</p>

<p>At a County Court of the State of Maryland held for the County aforesaid at Upper Marlborough Town in said County on the first Monday in September being the first day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four.</p>

<p>Present.<lb/>
Michael Jenifer Stone Esquire Chief Justice<lb/>
David Craufurd and Thomas Duckett Esquires Associate Justices<lb/>
William John Jackson Esquire Sheriff<lb/>
John R Magruder Junr Clk.</p>

<p>In the Record of Proceedings of the same Court among others things is the following to wit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
a<lb/>
Henry Rozer</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Prince Georges County, to wit</p>

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore, to wit on the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety one Basil Shorter by Gabriel Duvall and John Mackall Gantt his Attorney preferred to the Court here his Petition for Freedom against Henry Rozer in the words following, to wit.</p>

<p>To the Worshipful the Justices of Prince Georges County.</p>

<p>The Petition of Basil Shorter humbly sheweth that he is held in slavery by Henry Rozer Esquire of the County aforesaid although he considers himself entitled to his Freedom being lineally descended in the female line from Elizabeth Shorter a free white woman. He therefore prays your Worships to order summons to issue against the said Henry Rozer to attend this Court &amp; answer the Premises and he will pray and so forth.</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Pet.</p>

<p>Which said Petition being read and heard it was by the Court here ordered that summons issue against the said Henry Rozer that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear immediately before the Justices of our County Court now setting to answer the Petition aforesaid which said summons was accordingly issued and return thereof <fw type="catch">made</fw>

<pb xml:id="p244" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.004.jpg"/>

made by Edward Lloyd Wailes Gentleman Sheriff of the County aforesaid that he hath summoned the said Henry Rozer to appear and answer the Petition aforesaid according to the exigence of the said Summons as thereby he was directed.</p>

<p>And thereupon agreeable to the said summons comes the said Henry Rozer by Philip Barton Key and William Hammond Dorsey his Attorney and at the Prayer of the said Basil Shorter by his Attorneys aforesaid it is ordered by the Court here that the said Henry Rozer enter into Recognizance with one sufficient security in the sum of two hundred pounds current money not to transport the said Basil Shorter, but to suffer him to appear to prosecute his Petition for Freedom and at all times allow him a reasonable time to advise with his counsel on his said Petition &amp;ca</p>

<p>Whereupon Henry Rozer and Notley Young present here in Court in the proper persons acknowledge themselves to owe and stand justly indebted to the State of Maryland in the sum of two hundred pounds current money to be levied of their and each of their Bodies, goods and chattels Lands, and Tenements to the use of the said state into whosoever hands they shall come on condition that the said Henry Rozier shall not transport a certain Negro Basil Shorter from the State of Maryland but shall suffer and permit him the said Basil Shorter to appear at the next County Court to be held at Upper Marlborough Town in Prince Georges County on the first Monday in September next to prosecute the said Petition for Freedom and at all times suffer the said Basil Shorter to have a reasonable time to advise with his Counsel on his said Petition. The the above Recognizance to be void, otherwise of force.</p>

<p>And the said Basil Shorter and Henry Rozer by their Attorneys enter into the following agreement which is filed, to wit.</p>

<p>Ruled by the consent of Parties in this cause that the Depositions of Dorothy Hall, Giles Green, James Gates, Walter Hanson, John McAtee, John Clements, and Patrick Hamilton taken on ten days Notice to the adverse Party on their counsel be read as evidence in this cause and in the other Petitions against Notley Young Esqr &amp; Mary Hurley</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Pet.</p>
<gap extent="one signature line"/>

<pb xml:id="p245" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.005.jpg"/><!-- START REVIEWING HERE -->

<p>And thereupon day is given as well to the said Basil Shorter as to the said Henry Rozier by their Attorneys aforesaid to hear the allegation and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozier of and upon the Premises aforesaid until the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day to wit the first Monday in September in the year seventeen hundred and ninety one aforesaid come here again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid and at the prayer of the Parties aforesaid[struckthru} by their said Attorneys aforesaid{struck through} leave is granted by the Court to take depositions on either side on giving five days Notice to the adverse Party.</p>

<p>And thereupon day is further given to the parties aforesaid to hear the Allegations and evidence as well on the Part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozier of and upon the premises aforesaid until the first Monday in April next.</p>

<p>At which day to wit the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety two here come again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid and at the prayer of the said Parties by their said Attorneys leave is granted by the Court to take Depositions by either Party on giving ten days Notice to Notley Young and Henry Rozier on to either of them or either of their Attorneys and thereupon day is further given to the said Parties to hear the allegations, and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozier of and upon the Premises aforesaid until the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day, to with the first Monday in September in the year last aforesaid here come again the parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid, and thereupon day is further given to the said parties to hear the Allegations and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozier of and upon the Premises aforesaid until the first Monday in April next.</p>

<p>At which day to with the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety three here come again the parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid and thereupon by consent of the said parties and their Attorneys aforesaid, day is further given to the said Parties</p>


</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>