<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.case.0381.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Bazil Thomas v. James Kennedy Jr. Statement of Facts</title>
<principal n="Guiliano, Jennifer" xml:id="jeg">Jennifer Guiliano</principal>
<principal n="Mu&#241;oz, Trevor" xml:id="tm">Trevor Mu&#241;oz</principal>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Camerone, Stephanie N." xml:id="snc">Steph N. Camerone</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0381.004</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0406</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Statement of Facts</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia</repository>
<collection>Local Government Records Collection, Arlington County Court Records</collection>
<idno>Arlington County (Va.) Judgments (Freedom Suits), 1795-1858, Box 1</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Statement of Facts</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1805-03">March 1805</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.003010">Sinclair, Jane Blackbourn</term>
<term xml:id="per.002991">Turner, Francina West</term>
<term xml:id="per.002990">Turner, Charles</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Virginia</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.002993">
<persName>Thomas, Bazil</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.002994">
<persName>Kennedy, James, Jr.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Alexandria (Washington, D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>       
<change when="2016-07-18" who="#lkw">added xml:ids; transcription; changed death year from 1794 to 1796</change>   
<change when="2016-06-21" who="#snc">reviewed</change>          
<change when="2016-04-29" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.case.0381.004.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>The case of Bazil</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>On the 11th Sepr. 1794, a marriage settlement was made by a deed of that date whereby sundry lands and slaves the property of Francina West who was about to marry Charles Turner were settled upon her for her separate use and subject to be disposed of by her either by deed or by her last will. This marriage settlement was duly proved by three witnesses in the <del>county</del> court of Fairfax County on the 15th Sepr. in the same year and admitted to record. The parties to the said deed all resided at that time in Fairfax County and the deed is in the words following towit This indenture &amp;c</p>

<p>Bazil was born a slave in Virginia &amp; became the property of Francina by virtue of her fathers will and is one of the slaves in the marriage settlement set forth and mentioned Afterwards towit on the 12th of May in the year 1796 Francina West made her will under her hand &amp; seal which was proved by two witnesses Charles Little and Jane Blackburn who were subscribing witnesses thereto by which instrument Bazil is directed to be sold for the term of eight years and after he shall arrive at the completion of the term <del>that</del> he is to be free. The will is in the words following towit "In the name <unclear reason="illegible">&amp;c</unclear> Charles Turner is one of the executors in the will named but never qualified as such. The will was not proved until <del>june</del> 21st june 1804 sometime after the death of Charles Turner who it is believed suppressed it.</p>

<p>On or about the 27th day of Jany in the year 1802 Bazil was sold and after the death of Francina aforesaid <del>all the title of Charles Turner to</del> as the property of Charles Turner at public auction <del>as a slave for life</del> and James Kennedy the defendant became the purchasor for the sum of 251 dollars by the marshall of columbia district, under an Execution agt the said Charles Turner The value of Bazil and the other slaves for the terms

<pb xml:id="p002" facs="oscys.case.0381.004.002.jpg"/>

of years respectively mentioned in the will exceeds the amount of the legacies directed to be paid out of the product of the sales of the said slaves if they had been sold for those terms respectively and the sale of the said slaves produced a sum greatly exceeding those legacies which sum was <unclear reason="illegible">received</unclear> by Charles Turner aforesaid. More than eight years have passed since the death of Francina the testatrix and prior to the institution of this suit, and for upwards of eight years since the death of the testatrix the negro Bazil has been in the servitude of the said Charles Turner and the benefit of his services has been enjoyed by <gap extent="three or four words" reason="strikethrough"/> him in the character of master. He is now held in servitude by James Kennedy who claims to hold him as a slave by virtue of his purchase aforesaid The testatrix died on or about the month of <del>october</del> June in the year 1796 <del>The question is whether</del> Bazil is or is not a freeman <del>at this period.</del></p>

<p>Charles Turner who suppressed the will is the residency legatee of the money arising form the sale of the terms of servitude of the said slaves in the will mentioned.</p>

<p>The writ in this suit is dated 22d august 1804 It is also agreed that the suit is brought to try the right of the plaintiff to his freedom and that he is held now as a slave by the defendant.</p>

<p>If the law be for the plaintiff then we agree judgment shall be entered for him and one cent damage and the costs &amp; if the law be for defendant then judgment shall be entered for him.</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
