<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0014.001">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>William Butler and Mary Butler v. Richard Boarman. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0014.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0571</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>
Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1770-09">September 1770</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>Provincial Court (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S551-85 DD 17</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1770-09">September 1770</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.006326">Abell, Samuel, Jr.</term><!-- deponent -->
<term xml:id="per.004336">Baltimore, Charles Calvert, Lord, 1637-1715</term>
<term xml:id="per.006321">Beach, Thomas</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Irish Nell -->
<term xml:id="per.006347">Boarman, Francis</term><!-- child of Ignatius Boarman -->
<term>Boarman, Gerrard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006343">Boarman, Ignatius</term><!-- Nasy; hired Charles from John Saunders; enslaved Moll Butler; parent of Francis Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006344">Boarman, John Baptist</term><!-- enslaved Kate Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006318">Boarman, William</term><!-- Major; enslaved Charles -->
<term xml:id="per.006357">Bowling, Thomas</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Kate Butler; neighbor of Major Boarman; acquaintance of Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006307">Branson, John</term><!-- deponent -->
<term xml:id="per.006365">Brooke, Baker</term>
<term xml:id="per.006358">Brookes, Clear</term><!-- spouse of Richard Brooke; child of Major Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006322">Brookes, Leonard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006325">Brookes, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006316">Butler, Catharine</term><!-- child of Nell/Charles; enslaved by John Baptist Boarman; parent of Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006312">Butler, Eleanor</term><!-- spouse of Charles; lived with Leonard Brookes; lived with Maj. Boarman; lived with Pomphrey John Sanders; lived with Nasy Boarman; employed by Major Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006323">Butler, Elizabeth</term><!-- (Abigail) child of Nell; lived with Leonard Brookes; parent of William Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006314">Butler, John</term><!-- child of Nell/Charles -->
<term xml:id="per.006345">Butler, Moll</term><!-- child of Nell; enslaved by Ign. Boarman and Francis Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006346">Butler, Nan</term><!-- child of Nell -->
<term xml:id="per.006348">Butler, Ned</term><!-- enslaved by Joseph Piles; child of Kate Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006342">Butler, Pegg</term><!-- child of Nell; parent of Mary/Molly Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006315">Butler, Sarah</term><!-- child of Nell/Charles -->
<term xml:id="per.006313">Charles</term><!-- spouse of Nell; lived with Maj. Boarman; lived with Pomphrey John Sanders; hired to Nasy Boarman; enslaved by Wm. Boarman -->
<term>Crossen, Mary</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Eleanor Butler; neighbor of Irish Nell -->
<term xml:id="per.006328">Darnall</term>
<term xml:id="per.006317">Davis, Allen</term>
<term xml:id="per.006353">Doynes</term><!-- Mrs. -->
<term xml:id="per.006349">Edelen, Edward</term><!-- deponent; child of Richard Edelen -->
<term xml:id="per.006350">Edelen, Richard</term><!-- parent of Edward Edelen -->
<term xml:id="per.006327">Edwards</term><!-- acquaintance of Samuel Abell -->
<term xml:id="per.006311">Ghiselin, Reverdy</term><!-- clerk -->
<term xml:id="per.006361">Haddock</term><!-- acquaintance of Thomas Bowling -->
<term xml:id="per.006319">Howard, Jane</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Maj. Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006360">Hulbert</term><!-- neighbor of Maj. Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006351">Jameson, Benjamin</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006366">Jameson, Joseph</term><!-- deponent; aquaintane of Irish Nell -->
<term xml:id="per.006308">Love, Samuel, Sr.</term><!-- deponent -->
<term xml:id="per.006340">McPherson, William</term><!-- deponent; acquaitance of Nell Butler; acquaintance of Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006363">Neale, Billy</term><!-- enslaved Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006359">Piles, Joseph</term><!-- enslaved Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006364">Redhead</term><!-- captain -->
<term xml:id="per.006355">Ruthom</term>
<term xml:id="per.006341">Sanders, Pomphrey John</term><!-- hired Charles to Nasy Boarman -->
<term xml:id="per.006354">Short, Ann</term>
<term xml:id="per.006362">Simpson, William</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Nell and Charles and Kate and Ned Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006309">Smith, John Jordan</term><!-- deponent; acquaintance of Eleanor Butler per.006312; acquaintance of Charles per.006313 -->
<term xml:id="per.006339">Soot, Nathaniel</term><!-- parent of Nathaniel Soot -->
<term xml:id="per.006329">Suit, Nathaniel</term><!-- deponent -->
<term xml:id="per.006310">Warring, Elizabeth</term><!-- deponent -->
<term xml:id="per.006324">Whitehorn, Ann</term><!-- acquaintance of Elizabeth/Abigail Butler; acquaintance of Nell Butler; neighbor of Elizabeth/Abigail Butler -->
<term xml:id="per.006352">Witham</term><!-- madam -->
<term xml:id="per.006356">Yates</term><!-- Mr. -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Saint Mary's County (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Petitioners</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006303">
<persName>Butler, William</persName><!-- child of Elizabeth/Abigail Butler -->
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006304">
<persName>Butler, Mary</persName><!-- child of Pegg -->
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006305">
<persName>Boarman, Richard</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.006306">
<persName>Hall, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.002097">
<persName>Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019" who="#kln">transcribed; encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p233" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>William Butler &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
a<lb/>
Richard Boarman</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that on the twenty seventh day of September Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty three the Plaintiffs by John Hall their attorney file in Court here the following Petition to wit.</p>

<p>To the Honourable the Justices of the Provincial Court</p>

<p>The Humble petition of William Butler and Mary Butler sheweth that they are justly Entitled to Freedom; but are detained in a State of perpetual Slavery by Richard Boarman of Saint Mary's County plantor. Your petitioner therefore desire your Honours to consider their case and sett them at Liberty, and otherwise relieve them in the premisses. And as in duty bound they will ever pray &amp;ca</p>

<p>John Hall <unclear reason="illegible">ff.</unclear> Petitioners</p>

<p>which being read and heard and mature Deliberation thereupon had it was ruled and Ordered by the Court that Summons issue against the said Richard Boarman for his appearance here next Court which issued accordingly, and was by the Sheriff of Saint <fw type="catch">Marys</fw>

<pb xml:id="p234" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.002"/>

Marys County to whom the same writ was directed, returned, Summoned.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the Second Tuesday of April Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty four, come again as well the said William Butler and May Butler by John Hall their attorney, as the said Richard Boarman by Thomas Johnson Junior his attorney: Thereupon the said cause is continued till next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit the second Tuesday of September Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty four, come again the Parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid: Thereupon the said cause is further continued untill next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to with the second Tuesday of April Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty five, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid: Thereupon it is ordered and ruled by the said Court, that the Depositions of John Branson, Samuel Love Senior, John Jordan Smith, and Elizabeth Warring be admitted as Evidence on behalf of the Defendant on giving four days notice of the time and place of Examination to the Complainants; and thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the second Tuesday of September Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty five, come again the said parties by their attornies aforesaid; Thereupon the said cause is further continued untill next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the Second Tuesday of April Anno Seventeen hundred and Sixty five, come again the said parties by their attornies aforesaid; Thereupon the said cause is further continued untill next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the second Tuesday of April Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty six, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid Thereupon the said cause is further continued untill next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the Third Tuesday of October Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty six, come again the said parties by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon it is ordered and ruled by the said Court, that the Depositions of all witnesses on both sides to be taken before a majestrate be admitted as Evidence on the argument of this cause, in case the Evidences are not able to attend, the adverse party given two days notice of the time and place of taking each Deposition; and thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit the third Tuesday of May Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty seven, come again the parties aforesaid by the attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said Cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the third Tuesday of October Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty seven, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the third Tuesday of May Anno Domini seventeen hundred and Sixty eight, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<pb xml:id="p235" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.003"/>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the third Tuesday of October Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty eight, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the third Tuesday of May Anno Domini seventeen hundred and sixty nine, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the third Tuesday of October Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Sixty nine, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p> 

<p>At which said next Court to wit the second Tuesday of April, Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Seventy, come again the parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid. Thereupon the said cause is further continued until next Court.</p>

<p>At which said next Court to wit, the second Tuesday of September Anno Domini Seventeen hundred and Seventy, come again as well the said William Butler and Mary Butler by their attorney aforesaid, as the said Richard Boarman by his attorney aforesaid; Whereupon all and Singular the premisses aforesaid, and the allegations and Evidence, as well on the part of the said William Butler and Mary Butler, as the said Richard Boarman, being by the Court here, seen, heard, fully understood, and mature Deliberation thereupon had It is considered by the Justices here that the said William Butler and Mary Butler of and from any further servitude to the said Richard Boarman be hence discharged and Freed. And it is also considered that the said William Butler and Mary Butler recover against the said Richard Boarman the sum of &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; pounds of Tobacco by the Court here unto them or their assent adjudged for their costs and charges by them laid out and expended by Occassion of the premisses eta</p>

<p>And thereupon the said Richard Boarman by his attorney aforesaid prays an appeal from the Judgment aforesaid, so as aforesaid rendered to his Lordships High Court of Appeals and the same is granted. It is therefore ordered that the record and proceedings in the premisses aforesaid be transmitted to the High Court of Appeals accordingly.</p>

<p>Test. Reverdy Ghiselin Clk</p>

<p>Copies of the Depositions of the Witnesses taken and admitted as Evidence on the hearing of the aforegoing cause are hereto annexed.</p>

<p>Charles County Sct September 12th 1767. The Deposition of John Jordan Smith, aged about Eighty five years, taken before me the Subscriber one of the Justices of the said County, he been first sworn on the Holy Evangels Deposeth and saith that above Sixty years ago he was well acquainted with Eleaner Butteler, an Irish woman, and negro Charles and that they lived together several years and that they had three children which then lived with them, one named John, one named Sarah, and one named Catharine, and this Deponent further saith that he believes that the said John was then between nineteen and twenty years of age, and Sarah about seventeen, and Catharine about fifteen years of age, and this Deponent further <fw type="catch">(saith)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p236" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.004"/>

Saith that the said Eleaner Butteler, used to come several times to his father's house to wash for the family, and further saith that the said Eleaner and Charles lived on a plantation of Majr Boarmans, and that he saw them several times at the Majrs, and further this Deponent saith not.</p>

<p>John Jordan Smith.</p>

<p>Allen Davis</p>

<p>I further certifie that William Buttler was present when the above Deposition was taken.</p>

<p>Allen Davis</p>

<p>The Deposition of Jane Howard aged seventy years or thereabouts being sworn on the Holy Evangelists of Almighty God, declares that when she this Deponent was ten, eleven or twelve years of age, she used frequented to be at Major Boarman's House (his wife being Godmother to this Deponent, and at that time there was in Major Boarmans possession two Mulatto's as slaves, the one a young man named Jack twenty years of age or thereabouts, the other a well grown young lusty Wench named Kate, both which Molatto's she this Deponent often heard Major Boarman's family say was the children of Negroe Charles a slave to the said Boarman, and Nell Butler an Irish woman, and also several of the neighbours say the same. likewise that they were married</p>

<p>Jean Howard<lb/>
her + mark</p>

<p>Saint Marys County Sct</p>

<p>I hereby certify that the above Deposition was taken before me one of his Lordships Justices for the County aforesaid.</p>

<p>September 21st 1767. John Reeder Junior</p>

<p>The Deposition of Thomas Beach, aged seventy eight years, being first duly sworn of the Holy Evangels of Almighty God, Deposeth and saith that he knew Irish Nell, that the first of his knowing her was at Mr Leonard Brookes and that she the said Irish Nell appeared to him at that time to be about forty years old, that nell had a Daughter called Abigail that when he first knew her, she was about nine or ten years old, and lived at Leonard Brooke's, and that he this Deponent was then about twenty or twenty one years old, and that he has often heard that William Butler was the son of the said Abigail, and that Irish Nell was a white woman, and that when he first knew Irish Nell he was about twenty or twenty one years old.</p>

<p>Thomas Beach<lb/>
his x mark</p>

<p>Sworn to, in Open Court 28th October 1767.<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>William &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
a<lb/>
Richard Boarman</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court, May 27th 1767.</p>

<p>Ann Whitehorn aged seventy six years the Eleventh day of December next, being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in Open Court, deposeth and saith that William Butler one of the petitioners is a son of Eleanor Butler's Daughter named Elizabeth, commonly called Abigail which said Elizabeth, this Deponent saith was near her age, but something younger, that they were Girls together, and lived within two miles of each other, <fw type="catch">(and)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p237" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.005"/>

and that she never knew or heard that the said Eleanor Butler was in a state of Slavery that she frequently used to come and see her Children, and stay with them for a month and longer at a time as other free people do, that she never knew or heard that the said Eleanor Butler was married to a negro, that the said William Butler is as she believes about forty four years old, that the said Elizabeth, mother of the Petitioner has been dead about thirty years, that she knew Eleanor Butler from the time she this Deponent was seven years old, or thereabouts to the time of the said Eleanor's death, and that she the said Deponent always lived within a mile or two of Elizabeth, commonly called Abigail, Daughter of the said Irish Nell and that the said Eleanor was a Midwife and lived chiefly, among the Boarman in Charles County without being confined to any particular place that she knows of, that Eleanor, bore three or four Children after she this Deponent knew her, and at the time of her first knowing her was a Child bearing woman, that Eleanor she believes was about forty years old when she died; but does not know how long it is since her death, That one of the Children which the said Eleanor used to go and see was at Richard Boarmans that is now, but then Leonard Brooke's in Saint Marys County, and another at Richard Brookes in Saint Marys County, that she heard, but don't know from whom. That Leonard Brooke's wife was of the family of the Sanders; who the wife of Richard Brookes, was that she never heard, may be she was a Sly, she thinks she has hard so, and further saith no.</p>

<p>Ann Whitehorn<lb/>
her 3 mark</p>

<p>William &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
agt<lb/>
Richard Boarman</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court, 27th May 1767.</p>

<p>Samuel Abell Junior aged fifty years next March, being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in Open Court, deposeth and saith that in April one thousand seven hundred and sixty four, as well as he can remember he was at Annapolis attending the Provincial Court with Mr Edwards, and lodged at one house, and Mr Richard Boarman the Defendant came to their lodgings, and in discourse about the matter now in question he the said Boarman told him and Edwards that Lord Baltimore a good many years ago, came into this Country to live; and brought with him a woman named Butler, whose Christian name he do not remember, to wash and Iron and boarded with his Grand Father, and that some time after they had been there the said woman called Butler fell in Love with one of his Grand Father's Negroes and wanted to marry him, and upon my Lord being informed that she wanted to marry the negro, my Lord sent for her in, and chid her, and told her that if she married the negro she would by that means enslave herself, and her posterity, upon which the woman told him that she had rather many  the negro under them circumstances, than to marry his Lordship with his Country, upon which he told her she might go and marry him, and be damned, accordingly she went and was married to the negro, and of that marriage came these two negroes William and Mary Butler the Petitioners, upon which he this Deponent or Mr Edwards he don't remember which <fw type="catch">of</fw>

<pb xml:id="p238" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.006"/>

of them asked him if there were not a good many of that Family? he said there was about one hundred and twenty of them, but the negroes by their Count made near three hundred of them, for that they had taken even some Salt water negroes, into their count, and upon asking him how they came to be slaves as they came of a white woman? He said he claimed them by a Law of this province whereby white women marrying of slaves, should become slaves to the house of their Husbands master, and he took out of his pockett a paper which he said was a copy of the act, and it appeared to be a copy of an act, and under that act he claimed them and thinks as well as he can remember, he said Mr Darnall copyed it for him; afterwards this Deponent and Mr Edwards were talking about the matter, and that they would be summoned as Evidences upon which Mr Boarman said he only spoke to them as friends, and desired they would say nothing about the matter, and after they the said Deponant and Edwards went home, several people came to him and asked what the conversation was which passed between him and Boarman, upon which he knew he never told anybody, and when he see Mr Edwards he asked him, how he came to tell of it? he said it was no secret. Mr Boarman had told it to fifty people besides. and further saith not.</p>

<p>Saml Abell Junior</p>

<p>Sworn to, in open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>William &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
a<lb/>
Richard Boarman</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767</p>

<p>Nathaniel Suit aged forty years the twenty second day of July next being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God, in open Court, deposeth and saith, that his father Nathaniel Soot at the time of his death was in the Eighty ninth year of his age, and that he has been dead ten years last April, and that about seventeen or Eighteen years ago he told his Father that Ned Butler had sued for his freedom, and his father said he was a foolish dog wou'd never get free nor non of Irish Nells Children, for she was married to a negro Fellow of Major Boarman's named Charles, and that enslaved them all, and said he was there when they were married and was a small boy, and went there with his mother, and thinks his Father said they wanted him to kiss the Bride, or she wanted to kiss him, or did kiss him, and he run away, and further saith not.</p>

<p>Nathaniel Suit</p>

<p>Sworn to, in open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk</p>

<p>William &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
a<lb/>
Richard Boarman</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767.</p>

<p>William McPherson aged sixty years the fifth day of September next being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of almighty God, in open Court, deposeth and saith, that he knew Eleanor Butler, commonly called Irish Nell about fifty years ago, when Pomphrey John Sanders married Major William Boarman's Widow and brought his wife home he saw Irish Nell <fw type="catch">(and)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p239" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.007"/>

and a negro Charles at the said Sanders's, that he has seen Nell and Charles together and that negro Charles called the said Nell his old woman, and she called him her old man, that he never knew of the said Nell being held as a slave, that when Charles went to Saunders's quarter Nell went there also and acted as a Cooke, that Nell appeared to him to be as old woman and bore no children after his knowledge of her, that he knew a Daughter of her's called Kate, that Kate was the mother of Pegg, that Pegg was the Mother of Molly one of the Petitioners, that he first knew Kate about forty five years ago, that she then had Children, and died about seven or eight years ago, and thinks she must in his Judgment have been Seventy years old if not more at the time of her death. that Eleanor Butler hath been dead about thirty eight, thirty nine, or forty years ago, that he knew two other Daughters of the said Eleanor called Moll and Nan, that Nan was the youngest of the three, and he believes Moll younger than Kate, that John Saunders hired negro Charles to Nasy Boarman, that Eleanor Butler either came with him or followed him there and acted as a free woman and took in <gap extent="one word" reason="illegible"/> and acted as a midwife, that Charles was afterwards hired to Saunders's son and moved away from Nasy Boarman's, but that Eleanor Butler stayed at Nasy Boarmans till she died, that the said Eleanor appeared to him much broken and an old woman when she died, that when Eleanor first came into the Country she lived with Major William Boarman as he has heard; that the Children of Nell before Spoken of in this Deposition were held as slaves, that is Kate by John Baptist Boarman, Pegg by Ignatius Boarman, and Moll was born at Ignatius Boarman's and fell to a son of the said Boarmans called Francis Boarman that he knew Ned Butler, pretty near twenty seven or twenty eight years ago, that he was then a man grown, and appeared to him to be about twenty seven or twenty eight years old</p>

<p>William McPherson</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>Richard Boarman
ads
Wm &amp; Mary Butler</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court, May 27th 1767.</p>

<p>Edward Edelen aged fifty years or thereabouts being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in open Court deposeth and saith that he heard his Father Richard Edelen say a little before he died which was seven years next fall, that he was Eighty nine years old, or thereabouts, and that he heard his Father say he went to Major Boarmans one morning, and when he came there he said my Lord Baltimore was there, and then lived there, and he heard Lord Baltimore ask for Eleanor Butler a servant woman of Major Boarmans, when she came to him he said, I understand you are going to be married to Day to negro Charles, he said to her what a pitty <unclear reason="illegible">so</unclear> likely a young Girl as you are should fling herself away so as to marry a negro, and he said not only that, but <sic>you'l</sic> make slaves of your children and their posterity, and he heard his Father say he did not stay to see them married, but he understood they were married that day and lived together afterwards as man and wife, this conversation with his Father happened about twenty years ago, that he says that his Sister married one of the Boarmans who had some of the Descendants of Nell Butlers <fw type="catch">(and)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p240" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.008"/>

and her Children as he has heard now claims them &amp; further saith not.</p>

<p>Edward Edelen</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>Richard Boarman<lb/>
ads<lb/>
Wm &amp; Mary Butler</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court May 27th 1767.</p>

<p>Benjamin Jameson aged forty Eight years last November being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in Open Court deposeth and saith that he has heard his mother who is now dead say that she has heard old Madam Witham who is also dead say that she saw Irish Nell or Nell Butler he's not certain which married to negro Charles, that the said Charles at that time belonged to old Major Boarman, further he has heard her say she heard old Mrs Doynes who is also dead say, that she was at Major Boarmans when they were married and thinks she see them married, and further has heard her say that she heard one old Ann Short who is also dead say she was at Major Boarmans whom they were married and thinks said she seen them married, and also heard old Mrs Ruthom who is also dead say, that she was at Major Boarmans when the same Nell and Charles as she understood was married, but that she did not see them married, that she heard several people wish them much Joy, and that she behaved as a Bride; and that he has heard his mother say that she heard many people say that my Lord was at Major Boarmans at the time when they were married and cautioned this Nell Butler against it, that before they were married, that if she married negro Charles she would enslave herself, and all her posterity, my Lord asked her how she would like to go to bed to a negro? She answered him that she rather go to bed to Charles than his Lordship, that he heard Mr Yates who was a majistrate of Charles County, and now also dead say, that they were married under a Law that made them slaves, that Mr Yates at the time of his death was about fifty or Sixty years old, as he apprehends, that Mr yates was not a native of this province as he believes, and was a man when he first saw him, he says he knew Ned Butler, when a man grown that he appeared to him to be above twenty or near thirty or more, about seventeen or eighteen years ago, but that he is unable to form any Judgment of what age he was, and further saith not.</p>

<p>Benja Jameson</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>Richard Boarman
ads
Wm &amp; Mary Butler</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767.</p>

<p>Thomas Bowling aged Sixty three years last March being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God deposeth and saith, that in some discourse with his mother who is now dead, I heard her say, that in some discourse with Irish Nell about her marriage with a negro, Irish Nell told her the day she expected to be married, she was early up intending to clean the house out, and a Gentleman whether it was Lord Baltimore; or any other person he can't remember, asked her if she was the Girl that was to be married that day to the negro? She said yes <fw type="catch">he</fw>

<pb xml:id="p241" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.009"/>

he then chid her, and told her she would put a mark by  that upon her Children and bring them into slavery, that if she would marry a white man her Children might be of credit in the world otherwise they wou'd be in Slavery, upon which she fell a crying, and said it was to her Choice, she wou'd rather have Charles than have your Lordship or his Lordship he can't tell which, upon which he said marry him if you will and so were married, and that this Conversation between him and his Mother happened about thirty years ago, that he knew Kate a Daughter of Irish Nell, who had a Daughter named Pegg, who had several children that he understood Jack was the Elder Child of Irish Nell, that he knew Jack about fifty four or fifty five years ago, and then he appeared to be one or two and twenty years of age, that several young people were with him in the yard who he knew to be about one or two and twenty, and that he appeared to be of their age, he himself at that time being six or seven years old, that he always understood the descendants of the said Irish Nell were held in Slavery during his remembrance, and that several of them who he knew were held as slaves, that he knew Leonard Brookes who he always understood married Major Boarmans Daughter, and Richard Brooke and his wife Clear, which Clear was the Daughter of Major Boarman, that he this Deponent from his Infancy lived in the Neighbourhood of Boarman's family in Charles County until he was forty years old, and then removed into Prince Georges County, that he was nine or ten years old his mother sent him for corn, and then he saw Ned Butler at his master Joseph Piles his house, and that the said Ned Butler was a size bigger than himself, and that he Judged him to be a year or two older than himself, That he has heard that one Hubbert was a Roman Priest, and lived in the Neighbourhood near Major Boarmans, that it was before his time, and that he never saw him as he knows of, that one Haddock succeeded him, and that he knew him very well, and that Mr Hubbert died an old man, as he has heard, that he does not know whether Nell was a Slave or not, for when he knew her she was old and past her Labour.</p>

<p>Thomas Bowling</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>Richard Boarman<lb/>
ads<lb/>
Wm &amp; Mary Butler</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767.</p>

<p>William Simson aged sixty nine years being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in open Court deposeth and saith, that as for Irish Nell and her Husband ever since he knew any Body he knew them likewise, he knew Kate who came from them and he knew the Grand Son Ned who went for Kate's son, and he the said Ned and himself were pretty near of an age, and were children and played together, his master put him out to work, and his master got this Deponent to work with him, he kept on to work for some time, and then went away from this Deponent down to his Master called Billy Neale, who lived at Kob, that he has heard his Father say he was at the wedding at these two old people called Nell Butler and Charles and <fw type="catch">saw</fw>

<pb xml:id="p242" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.010"/>

saw them married, and heard him tell Captn Redhead he was at the wedding, and a fine wedding it was, the Captn told his Father she was a foolish woman for Marrying the negro, for that it would make herself and her children slaves forever after, and as for the two couples he used to work abroad and doth not know whether they lived or died slaves. that the time he went to work abroad, he was two or three and twenty. that he remembers Nell Butler and Negro Charles, and they passed as man and wife and called themselves so, and that Charles he believes was a Salt Water Negro, and always understood was a slave of Major William Boarman, that his this Deponent's Daughter married Baker Brooke's who had one or two Mulatto's, who he understood were of this family, and that Baker Brooke and his wife were both dead without children, that Baker Brooke did not get these Mulatto's by his wife, that he knew the people when he was two or three and twenty years old, by that they did not come into his walks after he went away to work, being asked how old Nell was, when he first knew her? said it was a great while ago, and that he don't know, not very old about thirty or perhaps forty years old, that he has heard his father talk of one Mr Hulbert being a Roman Priest, and that he used to preach at a Chappell pretty nigh Major Boarmans, and that this Deponent dont remember ever to have seen him, and further saith not.</p>

<p>Wm Simpson</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>Richard Boarman<lb/>
a<lb/>
William &amp; Mary Butler</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767</p>

<p>Joseph Jameson aged fifty two years next December, being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in Open Court, deposeth and saith, that he knew Irish Nell very well, that she lived at Mr Nasy Boarman's within a mile of his Fathers, that she had a Daughter living with her, who died as a slave of Mr Boarman, and being asked how he knew she was a slave? says she worked among the other slaves and lived as they did, she there died, and Mr Boarman sent for a spade, and he went and gave it out of the mill, and went with them to the place where they put her in the ground, the old woman Nell was lamenting the loss of her Daughter, and said it was the greatest loss she had met with since she was married, some one there by standing asked her, who married her? and she answered, one Mr Hulbert since that about thirty six or thirty seven years ago, Mrs Doynes happened at his fathers, Major Boarman's Charles was there of an errand sent, and his mother said to Mrs Doynes there was Major Boarman's Charles the Husband of Eleanor Butler, who Mrs Doynes said she and Madam Witham saw married, and the morning before they were married, My Lord Baltimore then was living at Major Boarmans was pleased to ask this Eleanor Butler whether she was going to be married to Negro Charles that day or not? her answer to him was she hoped she was that day to be married, who said to her, he was surprised she was going to marry a negro, which she was likely enough to marry some one of her own colour, her <fw type="catch">answer</fw>

<pb xml:id="p243" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.011"/>

answer was, she had much rather be married to Negro Charles than his Lordship, he then said she did not consider what she was about or going to do, for that she did not bring only Slavery upon herself, but all her posterity, that he knew negro Charles and that he was always reputed to be a negro slave of Major William Boarman, that the said Negro Charles and Irish Nell were always deemed as man and wife, and did acknowledge themselves as such, that he knew several children of Nell Butlers named Kate, Moll, and Nan, that Kate had a Child named Pegg who was the Mother of Moll, that he believes Kate at the time of her death was between Sixty and seventy years old, that all the Descendants of the said Nell that he knew lived and died Slaves they working and living as such except the said Kate who he had heard from the neighbourhood, and one spalding had purchased her freedom, and further saith not.</p>

<p>Joseph Jameson.</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court<lb/>
Test R Ghiselin Clk.</p>

<p>William &amp; Mary Butler<lb/>
a<lb/>
Richard Boarman.</p>

<p>In the Provincial Court 27th May 1767.</p>

<p>Mary Crossen aged seventy four years the fifteenth day of February next, being first sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God in open Court deposeth and saith, that she knew Eleanor Butler a white woman commonly called Irish Nell, that she was Settled by Nasy Boarman then a Single man with her Children at a place where Gerrard Boarman now lives called Zachiah Swamp near the old Bridges, that she lived within two miles of Irish Nell, that she knew some of her Children one called Kate, the other Moll, that she knew Nell as long as she can remember and that she supposes she was twelve or fourteen years old when she first took an account of her Kate; Nells Daughter has been dead between six and seven years <!-- START ENCODING HERE -->Kate had several Children, two of them she knew Jack and Jenny, that Kate was upwards of fifty years old when she died. that Kate and Moll when she first knew them were young women, and that she thinks Kate was fourteen or fifteen years older than herself, but cannot be certain, and that Kate was older than Nan, that she does not know that Nell was a free woman but appeared to her, to do as she pleased, that she was a hard labouring body, and made Good Crops, and she believes Mr Nasy Boarman's family got them, that she has heard that Kate had a Daughter called Pegg to the best of her knowledge, that she has heard that Nell had a Daughter called Abby, and further saith not.</p>

<p>Sworn to in Open Court.</p>

<p>Mary Crosen<lb/>
her II mark</p>

<p>Test R Ghiselin Clk</p>

<p>Charles County Sct September 17th 1767. Mrs Elizabeth Warren aged sixty five years being duly sworn, deposeth and saith, that she knew Negro Charles who was a slave to Mr William Boarman sixty years ago, as also a white woman named Nell, which said Slave and white woman she understood from all her acquaintances of them times, to be man and wife, and never <fw type="catch">(heard)</fw>

<pb xml:id="p244" n="oscys.mdcase.0014.001.012"/>

heard it disputed till some six years ago, and this Deponent further saith that as far back as he can remember she saw a negro man named Jack at Major Wm Boarmans a person who went for the son of the aforesaid Charles and Nell that she always understood from the Neighbours he was a Slave to said Boarman that said Jack runaway from his said Master that Mr Boarman's son followed him to the Lower parts of Virginia, and that said Jack bought his freedom, that he never returned as she knows of</p>

<p>Elizabeth Warren<lb/>
her x mark</p>

<p>Charles County Sct I Certifie that the above Deposition was taken at the Instance of Mr George Boarman in the presence of Negro William Butler this 17th September 1765. By Geo Dent</p>

<p>September the 18th 1765. Mr Samuel Love Senior aged seventy nine or thereabouts being duly sworn on the Holy Evangelists of Almighty God, deposeth and sayeth that his mother and Grand Mother, and old Mr Richard Edelen and several other people about seventy years agoe he has often heard them say that a Negro man slave called John slave to Major William Boarman was married to Eleanor Butler, and he has often heard it said they always went as man and wife; and the Deponent says he often heard Eleanor Butler, call the said Negro John her Husband, and he saith he never heard the said Eleanor Butler had a case born child.</p>

<p>Samuel Love Senr<lb/>
his S mark</p>

<p>Charles County September the 18th 1765. I certify that the above Deposition was taken before me</p>

<p>John <unclear reason="illegible">Dinter</unclear></p>

<p>Saint Mary's County. The deposition of John Branson aged Eighty two years some time next month being first sworn on the holy Evangelist declares. that sixty two years ago he this deponent workt at William Boarman's in Charles County, at which time a Mulatto man called Jack was put to work with him, which he was informed was a son of a white woman called Irish Nell and at that time he declares that the said Jack was about twenty four or five years old and that he understood the said Jack was a Slave, and that it was occasioned by his mother intermarrying with a Slave belonging to the aforesaid William Boarman, and farther this Deponent saith not</p>

<p>Taken before us the Subscribers two of his Lordships Justices for the County aforesaid this 18th day of September Anno Domini 1765.</p>

<p>Zach Bond<lb/>
Thos Bond</p>

<p>Test Reverdy Ghiselin Clk</p>

<note>Examd</note>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>