<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0019.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tom v. William M. Robertson. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Childs, Isabelle S." xml:id="isc">Isabelle S. Childs</name>
<name n="Hope, Gabrielle" xml:id="gh">Gabrielle Hope</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L. " xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2023</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0019.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0673</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1793-04-13">April 13, 1793</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Eastern Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S482-13</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1793-04">April 1793</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term xml:id="per.005429">Birckhead, Solomon</term>
<term xml:id="per.006955">Bromwell, Sped</term>
<term xml:id="per.006938">Brown, Samuel</term>
<term xml:id="per.006939">Caile</term><!-- Mr.  -->
<term xml:id="per.006940">Cole, Edward</term>
<term xml:id="per.006941">Dickinson, Henry</term>
<term xml:id="per.006922">Earle, James, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.007086">Goldsborough, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006943">Kelly, Patrick</term>
<term xml:id="per.006944">Kenny, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006954">Murray, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006945">Murray, William Littleton</term>
<term xml:id="per.007123">Murray, William V.</term>
<term xml:id="per.007087">Pattison</term><!-- Mr. -->
<term xml:id="per.006946">Resin, Rebecca</term>
<term xml:id="per.006947">Resin, Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006948">Stewart, Alexander</term>
<term xml:id="per.007011">Stewart, Sarah</term> 
<term xml:id="per.006949">Stewart, Woolford</term>
<term xml:id="per.006950">Sulivane, Daniel, Jr.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006951">Sulivane, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006952">Trippe, Margaret</term>
<term xml:id="per.006953">Tucker, William</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">  
<term>Caroline County (Md.)</term>
<term>Dorchester County (Md.)</term>  
<term>Baltimore (Md.)</term>
<term>Cambridge (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">    
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006934">Tom</persName> 
</person>
<person role="defendant"> 
<persName xml:id="per.006935">Robertson, William M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName xml:id="per.006932">Scott, Gustavus</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName xml:id="per.006936">Bayly, Josiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Eastern Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Easton (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>
<change when="2023-07-13" who="#kln">Reviewed, edited.</change>  
<change when="2023-06-12" who="#gh">Reviewed</change>
<change when="2023-06-07" who="#isc">Transcribed, encoded.</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p001" n="IMG_8124.jpg"/>

<p>Negro Tom<lb/> 
against<lb/>
William M. Robertson 
Exor of William L. Murray</p>

<p>And now here at this day
towit, the second Tuesday of
April, Anno Domini, one
thousand seven hundred &amp;
ninety three, come into our
General Court here, as well the said Negro Tom by Gustavus Scott
his Attorney, as the said William M. Robertson by Josiah
Bayly his Attorney: and the said parties by their said Attorneys
submitted this Cause to the opinion of the Judges of our said Court on the
following Case stated. The Counsel for the Plaintiff, and the
Counsel for the Defendant in this Cause, admit the facts herein after
mentioned, &amp; agree to submit the said Cause to the opinion of the Court upon
the Statement of the following Case, towit: That the said Tom, on the
first day of January, in the year seventeen hundred and ninety two, at
the County of Dorchester was the proper slave of the said Wm L. <sic>Murry</sic> and
was then and there in the possession of the said Murray: That the said Murray
had then &amp; there a right to dispose of the said Tom as his property in such
manner as he the said Murray thought proper: That the said Murray
in his lifetime, on the day and year afd, at the County afd, by a fair
and Bona fide contract in writing made between the said Murray &amp; a
certain Woolford Stewart at the County afd, for &amp; in consideration of the
sum of One hundred and twelve pounds, Current money of Maryland
to be paid to the said Murray on the thirty first day of December in
the year afd, did here and deliver the possession of the said Tom to the
said Woolford Stewart for &amp; during the <gap extent="several words" reason="incomplete image"/>

<pb xml:id="p002" n="IMG_8125.jpg"/>

fully to be complete and ended, and not by the day, Week or Month, and the
said Tom continued in the service of the said W. S for one year: That the said
Murray afterward, towit, on the ninth day of January, in the year seventeen
hundred and ninety two, made his last Will and Testament in writing as follows:
towit: In the name of God Amen, I William Littleton Murray of Dorchester
County &amp; State of Maryland being of sound disposing mind <del>and</del> memory &amp; understanding 
do make this my last Will and Testament in manner and form following,
towit: I give and bequeath unto my worthy Friend Doctor Daniel Sulivane
Junior, son of James Sulivane, my two Saddle Horses each known by the name
of Lofty, and also the sum of Two hundred pounds Current money of Maryland.
Item. I give and devise unto the said Daniel Sulivane Junior his Heirs &amp;
Assigns forever, all the Lot, Ground and Houses whereon Mr. Caile now lives
&amp; also the Lot, Ground and Houses whereon Mr. Brown now lives adjoining
Mr. Cailes beginning at the North eastward corner of Mr. Cailes front yard, &amp;
thence running with the Street towards the River to the North eastward corner
of the house in which Mr. Brown lives, then with a line parallel to the Lot on
which Mr. Caile dwells 'till it intersects a line drawn parallel with the Street
from the North Westward Corner of Mr. Caile's Garden, thence with the said
line to the said North Westward Corner, and thence to the place of beginning, to
him the said Daniel Sulivane his Heirs and Assigns forever. Item. I give and
devise unto the said Daniel Sulivane Junior his Heirs and Assigns forever all
that Lot, Ground and Houses whereon Edward Cole now lives which I purchased
of William Tucker. Item. I give and devise unto my Cousin John
Murray his Heirs and Assigns forever all that Lot, Ground &amp; Houses whereon
John Kenny &amp; Henry Dickinson now live, beginning at the first Corner
of the House in which the said Kenny, &amp; thence running with a straight
line until it intersects the Land of the late Mr. Pattison thence with the said
Land 'till it intersects the Land of William V. Murray, thence with the Land
of the said Wm V. Murray until it intersects the main Street &amp; thence to the
place of beginning, to him the said John Murray his Heirs &amp; Assigns.
Item. I give and bequeath unto the said John Murray the sum of Three
hundred pounds Current money of Maryland. Item. I give &amp; bequeath

<pb xml:id="p003" n="IMG_8126.jpg"/>

unto Samuel Brown the sum of One hundred &amp; fifty pounds Current
money of Maryland. Item. I give and devise unto my Aunt
Margaret Trippe during her natural life my Yellow dwelling House, &amp;
the Lot whereon it stands in Cambridge; and also all my Lots, Lands
&amp; Grounds in Cambridge not before devised to her the said Margaret during
her natural life &amp; after her decease to my Cousin William Robertson
his Heirs and Assigns forever. Item. I give and devise unto my
Aunt Margaret Trippe one half of my Woodland in the Swamp near 
Cambridge adjoining the Land of Gustavus Scott &amp; Wm V. Murray, also
my Plantation at the head of Fishing Creek, and also my other
Plantation at the mouth of Hunting Creek whereon Sped Bromwell
now lives, to her the said Margaret during her natural life, &amp; after
her decease, then to my Cousin William M. Robertson his heirs &amp;
Assigns forever. Item. I give and devise unto my Cousin
William Robertson his heirs and assigns forever all the rest &amp;
residue of my Lands &amp; Tenements of Dorchester County, not herein
before devised to him the said William Robertson his Heirs &amp;
Assigns forever. Item. I give and devise unto the said 
William Robertson his Heirs and Assigns forever my Mill
in Caroline County, &amp; all the Appurtenance thereunto belonging
&amp; also my two fields in Caroline County which lie on the Main road
between the afd Mill &amp; the Church, &amp; also the Tract of Land wherein
those two fields afd are contained, to him the said William Robertson
his Heirs and Assigns forever. Item. I give and devise unto my
Aunt Sarah Resin all my Lands in Caroline County not before
devised, to her the said Sarah during her natural life, &amp; after her
decease, then to the heirs of Sarah Stewart deceased, Wife of Doctor
Alexander Stewart in fee simple. Item. I give &amp; bequeath unto
my Cousin Rebecca Resin the sum of four hundred pounds Current
money of Maryland. Item. I give and bequeath unto my
Cousin William Robertson all my Household furniture, and also all

<pb xml:id="p004" n="IMG_8127.jpg"/>

my Crops on hand; and also all the rents of my plantations that may become
due on the first day of January next ensuing my decease, and in case my
personal Estate should not be sufficient to pay my Debts and the Legacies
before mentioned, then my Will is, that the said William Robertson shall
sell some of the Lands afd devised to him which ever may be most convenient
for him for the payment of Debts and the legacies afd, &amp; that the Lands afd
devised to him be liable &amp; chargeable for the payment thereof &amp; in case there
should be more than a sufficiency of personal Estate to pay off the Debts &amp;
legacies afd, then I give and bequeath the Surplusage and residue of my
personal Estate, except my Household furniture afd, unto my Cousin
John Murray, William Robertson &amp; Rebecca Resin to be equally divided
between them; &amp; my Will &amp; desire are that the several devisees before mentioned
shall not enter nor take possession of my Lands devised to them until the
first day of January next ensuing my decease. Item. It is my Will
&amp; desire that all my Negro Slaves be free immediately upon my decease:
I do therefore hereby liberate, manumit &amp; set free all my Negro Slaves, by
whatever Name or Names called, either in my possession or to which I have
any right or title according to the Act of Assembly in such case lately made
and provided. Item. I give and devise unto my Aunt Margaret
Trippe her heirs and Assigns forever my Lot, Ground &amp; Houses on Howard's hill
in Baltimore, &amp; also my Lot, Ground and Houses on Fell's point in Baltimore
&amp; also all the rest &amp; residue of my Lands &amp; Tenements not herein before devised,
to her the said Margaret Trippe her heirs &amp; Assigns forever. And lastly, I do
hereby nominate, appoint and constitute my Cousin William Robertson 
to be my whole &amp; sole Executor of this my last Will and Testament: In Testimony
whereof I have hereunto set my hand &amp; affixed my Seal this ninth
day of January in the year of our Lord, seventeen hundred ninety two. 
Signed, Sealed, Published &amp; Declared
by Wm L. Murray, the Testator, as for
his last Will &amp; Testament in the presence
of us, who at his request &amp; in his presence have
subscribed our names as Witnesses thereto.</p>

<p>Josiah Bayly. P. Kelly.<lb/>
Soln Birckhead</p>

<p>Wm L. Murray (Seal)</p>

<pb xml:id="p005" n="IMG_8128.jpg"/>

<p>Dorchester County Sct. On the 5th day of March, Anno Domini 1792
William Robertson the within appointed Executor made Oath on the holy
Evangels of Almighty God that the within Testament of Writing is the true
and whole Will and Testament of William L. Murray late of Dorchester
County, deceased that hath come to his hands or possession, and that he
doth not know of any other. Certified <unclear>ss</unclear>. Jno Goldsborough Regr W. D. C. 
Dorchester County Sct. On the 5th day of March, Anno Domini 1792.
Josiah Baily and Solomon Birckhead two of the Subscribing Witnesses
to the within last Will and Testament of William L Murray late of
Dorchester County deceased, severally made Oath on the holy Evangels
of Almighty God that they did see the <sic>Testater</sic> therein named Sign &amp;
Seal this Will, and that they heard him publish, pronounce and
declare the same to be his last Will and Testament, that at the time of his
so doing he was to the best of their Apprehension of sound and disposing
Mind, Memory and Understanding; and that they, together with
Patrick Kelly the other Witness respectively subscribed their names
as Witnesses to this Will in the presence and at the request of the Testator
and in the presence of each other.</p>

<p>Certified <unclear>ss</unclear><lb/>
Jno Goldsborough Regr W. D. C.</p>

<p>Dorchester County Sct. On the 27th day of March Anno Domini,
1792 Patrick Kelly one of the Subscribing Witnesses to the within
last Will and Testament of William L. Murray late of Dorchester
County, deceased, made Oath on the Holy Evangels of Almighty
God that he did see the Testator therein named Sign and Seal this
Will, and that he heard him publish, pronounce and declare
the same to be his last Will and Testament, that at the time of
his so doing he was to the best of his Apprehension of sound and
disposing Mind, Memory and Understanding, and that he, together
with Josiah Bailey and Solomon Birckhead, the other Witnesses
respectively subscribed their Names as Witnesses to this Will in the presence

<pb xml:id="p006" n="IMG_8129"></pb>

and at the request of the Testator and in the presence of each other.</p>

<p>Certified <unclear>ss</unclear> Jno Goldsborough Regr W. D. C.</p>

<p>(Seal.)</p>

<p>In Testimony that the aforegoing is a true Copy, I hereto set my
hand and affix the Seal of my Office this 16th day of August, Anno
Domini 1792. Jno Goldsborough Regr W. D. C.</p>

<p>That the said Murray died on the tenth day of February in the year
afd: That the said Murray by a clause in the said Will in general
Words liberated all his Negro Slaves immediately upon his decease; and
that the said William M. Robertson as Exor of the said <del>William</del> Murray
has received the said sum of money, and that the said Plaintiff claims
all the Wages to be apportioned since the death of the said Testator.
If upon the said Statement of facts above mentioned the Court should
be of opinion that the Plaintiff in this Cause is entitled to the said sum
of money or any part thereof, then the Counsel for the Defendant &amp; the 
Counsel for the Plff agree that Judgment shall be rendered for the said
Plaintiff against the said Defendant, to be released nevertheless upon the
payment of one pound of Tobacco: But if on the Contrary the Court
should be of opinion that the said Defendant as Executor of the last Will
of the said William L. Murray is entitled to the said sum of Money,
then the Counsel for the Defendant agrees that Judgment of Non pross
shall be immediately rendered against the said Plaintiff. Costs to be
released. Gusts Scott for Plff. Josiah Bayly for the Deft.</p>

<p>Whereupon all and singular the premises being seen &amp; by the Court
here fully understood and mature deliberation thereon had: It is
considered and Adjudged by our said Court that the said Negro Tom
do recover against the said William M. Robertson Executor as afd the
said sum of One hundred and twelve pounds Current money, and also
the quantity of Seven hundred and thirty four pounds of Tobacco for his
Costs &amp; charges by him about his Suit in this behalf expended. And
the said William M. Robertson Executor as afd in mercy &amp;c.</p>

<p>James Earle Junr Clk</p>

<p>Judgment was rendered in this Action on the 13th of April 1793 for <gap extent="unknown" reason="no further images"/></p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
