<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.supp.0005.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>American Anti-Slavery Society - Slave Market of America</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.supp.0006.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">American Anti-Slavery Society - Slave Market of America</title>
<date when="1836">1836</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Library of Congress</repository>
<collection>Library of Congress Rare Book and Special Collections Division</collection>
<idno>LC-DIG-ppmsca-19705</idno>
<altIdentifier type="url">
<idno>https://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/2008661294/</idno>
</altIdentifier>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Broadside</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people"> 
<term/>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>          
<change when="2020-06-22" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<pb xml:id="p001" facs="oscys.supp.0006.001.001.jpg"/>
               
<div1 type="document">

<p>SLAVE MARKET OF AMERICA.</p>

<p>THE WORD OF GOD.</p>

<p>"All things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them, for this is the law and the prophets."</p>

<p>"And they sighed by reason of the bondage, and they cried, and their cry came up unto God by reason of the bondage, and God heard their groaning."</p>

<p>"Thus saith the Lord, execute judgment in the morning, and deliver him that is spoiled out of the hands of the oppressor, lest my fury go out like fire, and burn that none can quench it, because of the evil of your doings."</p>

<p>THE DECLARATION OF AMERICAN INDEPENDENCE.</p>

<p>"We hold these truths to be self-evident;&#8212;that all men are created equal; that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights; that among these are Life, Liberty, and the pursuit of Happiness."</p>

<p>THE <sic>CONSITUTION</sic> OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>

<p>"The citizens of each state shall be entitled to all the privileges and immunities of citizens of the several states." Article 4, Section 2.</p>

<p>"Congress shall make no law abridging the freedom of speech or of the press, or of the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the government for a redress of grievances."&#8212;Article 1, Amendment.</p>

<p>"Congress shall have power to exercise exclusive legislation, in all cases whatsoever, over such District (not exceeding ten miles square) as may, by cession of particular states and the acceptance of Congress, become the seat of government of the United States."&#8212;Article 1, Section 8.</p>

<p>CONSTITUTIONS OF THE STATES.</p>

<p>"Every citizen may freely speak, write, and publish his sentiments on all subjects, being responsible for the abuse of that liberty." Constitutions of Maine, Connecticut, New York, Pennsylvania, Delaware, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Tennessee, Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi, and Missouri.</p>

<p>"The freedom of the press is one of the great bulwarks of liberty, and therefore ought never to be restrained."&#8212;North Carolina.</p>

<p>"The liberty of the press ought to be inviolably preserved."&#8212;Maryland.</p>

<p>"The freedom of the press is one of the great bulwarks of liberty, and can never be restrained but by despotic governments."&#8212;Virginia. Other States nearly the same.</p>

<p>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA.</p>

<table>
<row>
<cell>"The land of the free."</cell>
<cell>The residence of 7000 slaves.</cell>
<cell>"The home of the oppressed."</cell>
</row>
<row>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>Reading of the Declaration of Independence.</p>
</figure></cell>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>Part of Washington City.</p>
</figure></cell>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>Capitol of the United States. "Hail Columbia."</p>
</figure></cell>
</row>
</table>

<p>RIGHT TO INTERFERE.</p>

<p>People sometimes say we have no right to interfere for the abolition of Slavery in the District of Columbia. Now what are the facts in
the case? Article 1, Sec. 8, of the Constitution (see above) gives Congress "power to exercise <hi rend="italics">exclusive legislation</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps">in all cases whatsoever</hi>, over such district."</p>

<p>But the terms of Cession! On the 23d of December, 1788, Maryland passed an Act to cede to the Congress of the United States, any
district in the State, not exceeding ten miles square, which the Congress may fix upon, and accept for the Seat of Government of the
United States;" and this with no proviso. On the 3d of December, 1789, Virginia did the same, and in these words, "And the same is
hereby forever ceded and relinquished to the Congress and Government of the United states, <hi rend="italics">in full and absolute right</hi>, and <hi rend="smallcaps">exclusive 
jurisdiction</hi>, as well <hi rend="italics">of soil</hi> as of persons residing or to reside thereon, pursuant to the <hi rend="italics">tenor</hi> and <hi rend="smallcaps">effect</hi> of the eighth section of the first
article of the Constitution." This was accompanied with a provision touching the "Soil," "That nothing herein contained shall be construed
to vest in the United States any right of property in the <hi rend="italics">soil</hi>, or to affect the rights of individuals therein, otherwise than the same
shall or may be transferred by such individuals." There was also the provision, "That the jurisdiction of the Laws of this Commonwealth,
over <sic>presons</sic> and property of individuals residing within the limits of the cession, shall not cease <hi rend="smallcaps">until</hi> Congress, having accepted
the cession, shall, by law, provide for the government thereof, under <hi rend="italics">their</hi> jurisdiction in manner provided by the Article of the Constitution
before recited"&#8212;plainly implying that <hi rend="italics">then</hi> the jurisdiction of the State Laws <hi rend="italics">should</hi> cease, and Congress "exercise <hi rend="italics">exclusive legislation</hi>"
<hi rend="italics">over persons and property</hi>, "<hi rend="smallcaps">in all cases whatsoever</hi>." And July 16, 1790, Congress accepted the cession, providing that the Laws of
the State should remain in force "<hi rend="italics">until</hi> the time fixed on for the removal of the Government thereto, and <hi rend="smallcaps">until</hi> Congress shall otherwise
by law provide." It is therefore every Citizen's right, nay duty to interfere for the Abolition of Slavery in the District of Columbia.</p>

<p>[<hi rend="smallcaps">Note</hi>.&#8212;The Slave coffle marching by the Capitol is not fancy, but literal fact. Dr. Torrey in his account of the "American Slave Trade,"
states on the authority of a Member of the House of Representatives, Mr. <hi rend="smallcaps">Adgate</hi>, "That during the last Session of Congress, (1815-16,) as
several Members were standing in the street near the new Capitol, a drove of manacled colored people were passing by, and when just opposite,
one of them elevating his manacles as high as he could reach, commenced singing the favorite National Song, 'Hail Columbia! happy land,'" &amp;c. Page 64.]</p>

<p>PUBLIC PRISONS IN THE DISTRICT.</p>

<p>Built by Congress with $15,000 of the People's money; perverted from the purposes for which they were built, and used by Slaveholders for the confinement of refractory Slaves, by licensed Slave-dealers as depots for their victims, and by kidnappers for the imprisonment of Free Americans, seized and sold to pay their jail fees!</p>

<table>
<row>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>Jail in Alexandria.</p>
</figure></cell>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>Jail in Washington,&#8212;Sale of a free citizen to pay his jail fees!.</p>
</figure></cell>
<cell><figure n="illustration">
<p>View of the interior of the jail in Washington.&#8212;Fanny Jackson.</p>
</figure></cell>
</row>
</table>

<p>FACTS.</p>

<p>In 1826 Congress appropriated out of the public treasury $5000 "for the purpose of altering and repairing the jail in the city of Washington"
and $10,000 to build "a county jail for the city of county of Alexandria."</p>

<p>In 1820 "the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled," empowered the Corporation
of the City of Washington "to prescribe the terms and conditions upon which free negroes and mulattoes may reside in the city." On this
authority, in May 1827, that Corporation enacted that "every free negro or mulatto, whether male or female, who may come to the City of 
Washington to reside, shall within thirty days, exhibit to the Mayor satisfactory evidence of his or her title to freedom to be recorded, and
shall enter into bonds, with two freehold sureties, in the penalty of $500, conditioned on his or her good conduct, that they will not become
chargeable to the Corporation for the space of twelve months"&#8212;the bond "to be renewed <hi rend="italics">every year for</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps">three years</hi>. On failure of this, 
he or she must depart the city or be committed to the workhouse not exceeding <hi rend="italics">twelve months</hi> in <hi rend="italics">any</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps">one</hi> imprisonment." And all negroes
found residing in the city after the passage of this act who shall not be able to establish their title to freedom (except such as may be hired)
shall be committed to the jail, as absconding slaves."</p>

<p>By this law color is made a crime, which first robs citizens of their constitutional as well as inalienable rights and is then taken as evidence that
they are slaves; and then to crown all, a large posse of constables and other officers, some of them in the pay of government, are "charged"
with the execution of the laws, and "forfeit and pay for every neglect or failure a fine not exceeding twenty dollars." City Laws. p. 198.</p>

<p>The result is that free citizens are often arrested, plunged into prison and then sold for their jail fees as <hi rend="smallcaps">slaves for life</hi>. In 1829, Mr. Miner,
of Penn. declared in Congress, that in 1826-7, no less than <hi rend="italics">five persons</hi> were thus sold. In July, 1834, in a Washington paper was the following</p>

<p>NOTICE.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
