<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0013.006">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Maria Boston v. Benjamin Ogle. Judgement Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0013.006</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0547</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1793-05">May 1793</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-19 JG 19</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1793-05">May 1793</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Boston, Anthony</term>
<term>Boston, Lenah</term><!-- portuguese; family of Maria Boston -->
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.004367">Goldsmith, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term>Rawlings, Gassaway</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Plaintiff</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Boston, Maria</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Ogle, Benjamin</persName><!-- AAC  -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Jenings, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.004360">
<persName>Pinkney, William</persName><!-- add attorney to occupation -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001496">
<persName>Cooke, William</persName><!-- add attorney to occupation -->
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020-11" who="#kln">transcription and encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.006.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Maria Boston<lb/>
against<lb/>
Benjamin Ogle</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore, to wit, on the
twenty first day of November in the year of our lord one
thousand seven hundred and ninety one, the said
Maria Boston by George Jenings her attorney Exhibited
to the Court here her Petition for freedom against the said Benjamin Ogle
and which is of the tenor and form following, towit; To the Honourable
the Judges of the General Court, The Petition of Maria Boston, humbly sheweth
that your Petition is held in slavery by a certain Benjamin Ogle of Anne
Arundel County when she is entitled to her freedom being descended from
a free yellow woman being one of the <sic>Portugues</sic> whose name as your
Petitioner is informed was Lenah Boston, your Petitioner therefore pray
your honours to take her case into consideration and discharge her from 
the service of the said Benjamin Ogle and your Petition  as in duty
bound will pray &amp;c. G. Jenings for Petitioner</p>

<p>Thereupon the writ of the State of Maryland of Summons issued forth out
of the General Court here directed to the Sheriff of Anne Arundel County in
form following to wit. The State of Maryland to Wit; To the Sheriff of Ann
Arundel County, Greeting. We command you that you summons Benjamin Ogle
late of Ann Arundel County that all delays and excuses be set aside he be and
appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis
on the second tuesday of May next to answer unto the Petition of Maria
Boston preferred against him for freedom hereof he is not to fail and fail 
not at your peril and have you then and there this writ, Witness the Honourable
Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of our Court the 1st day of November Anno Domini 1791.
Issued the 21st day of November Anno Domini 1791. (G. Jgs.) Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the eighth day of the said
month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two,
and the return day of the said writ comes into the General Court here the
said Maria Boston by her attorney aforesaid; and the Sheriff of Anne
Arundel County aforesaid to whom the said writ was in form aforesaid directed
to wit; William Goldsmith Gentleman makes return thereof of the Court
here thereon endorsed to wit. "Summoned. Wm Goldsmith Shff."</p>

<p>Thereupon the said Benjamin Ogle appears in Court here by William
Cooke his attorney: thereupon further process of and upon the premises
aforesaid between the said parties in continued until the second Tuesday
of October next: the same day is given to the said parties then &amp;c.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of October being the ninth day of the
said month in the year of our lord one thousand seven hundred
and ninety two come again into the General Court here the
<catchwords>parties</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0013.006.002"/>

parties aforesaid by their attornies aforesaid: thereupon further process of and
upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid is further continued
until the second Tuesday of May next: the same day is given to the said
parties then &amp;c.</p>

<p>And now at this day to wit, the said second Tuesday of May being the
fourteenth day of the same month in the year of our lord one thousand
seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General Court
here as well the said Maria Boston by George Jenings, Gabriel Duvall,
and William Pinkney her attornies as the said Benjamin Ogle by his 
attorney aforesaid: Whereupon by consent of the parties aforesaid by the
attornies aforesaid it is agreed that the Depositions of Witnesses taken
and filed in the case determined at this Term in the General Court
here on an appeal from Anne Arundel County Court between Gassaway
Rawlings appellant and Anthony Boston appellee be received and
admitted as Evidence in this cause and which said Depositions are
in form following to wit.</p>

<p>(Here follow all the Depositions against Anthony Boston as recorded in
Liber J. G. No 18 folios 586 587 &amp;c)</p>

<p>Whereupon the said Benjamin Ogle by his attorney aforesaid saith
that he cannot deny the complaint of the said Maria Boston so as <unclear extent="one word"/>
made nor but that the said Maria Boston is entitled to her freedom
being descended from a free yellow woman, being one of the <sic>Portugese</sic>
whose name was <sic>Lenar</sic> Boston in manner and form as she the said
Maria Boston by her said Petition to the Court here preferred
against him the said Benjamin Ogle above hath alleged;</p>

<p>Therefore it is considered by the Court here that the said Maria
Boston the Petitioner aforesaid recover of and against the said Benjamin
Ogle her freedom and that she be hence freed and discharged of and
from the service of the said Benjamin Ogle and that she the said
Maria Boston the Petitioner aforesaid go freed and discharged
thereof without day &amp;c. And it is further considered by the Court
here that the said Maria Boston the Petitioner aforesaid recover
against the said Benjamin Ogle the quantity of five hundred
and ninety one pounds of Tobacco by the Court here unto the said
Maria Boston on her assent adjudged for her costs and charges
by her about the prosecution of her said Petition in this behalf
laid out and expended; and that she have thereof her execution.</p>

<p>Test. John Gwinn Clk.</p>

</div2>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>