<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.001">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Basil Shorter v. Henry Rozier. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0516</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>
Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1794-10">October 1794</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-23 JG 25</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1794-10">October 1794</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Andrew</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Andrew</term><!-- mulatto boy, abt 12; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Baden, Robert</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Bets</term><!-- negro woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Bets</term><!-- negro girl, 5 yr; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Betty</term><!-- negro girl, 6 yr; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Charles</term><!-- negro boy, abt 1 1/2; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Charles</term><!-- mulatto boy abt 9; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Chase, Samuel</term><!-- judge of General Court of the Western Shore -->
<term>Cherry</term><!-- negro woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Clements, John</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Craufurd, David</term>
<term>Cresap, James</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Crist, Henry</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Duckett, Thomas</term>
<term>Frank</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Gates, James</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Geulick, Nicholas</term><!-- Nicholass Gulick, Gewlich; priest -->
<term>Gordon, William</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Green, Giles</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Grey</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Guibert, Joshua</term>
<term>Gwinn, John</term><!-- clerk, General Court of the Western Shore -->
<term>Hall, Dorothy</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Hamilton, Patrick</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Hammond, William</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Hanson, Walter</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>Harrey</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Havett, William</term><!-- vestry clerk -->
<term>Hellen, Thomas</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Hungerford, Benjamim</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Hurley, Mary</term>
<term>Jackson, William John</term>
<term>Jane</term><!-- mulatto; daughter of Elizabeth and Robin; may be the same as Jenny -->
<term>Jeffery</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Jenny</term><!-- negro woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale; may be the same as Jane -->
<term>John</term><!-- mulatto boy, abt 14; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Jones, Stephen</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Kate</term><!-- mulatto girl abt 7; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Lingan, Thomas</term><!-- joror -->
<term>Magruder, John Read, Jr.</term><!-- clerk, Prince George's County Court -->
<term>Martha</term><!-- mulatto; daughter of Elizabeth and Robin--> 
<term>Mary</term><!-- mulatto; daughter of Elizabeth and Robin; maybe same as below -->
<term>Mary</term><!-- mulatto woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale; may be same as above -->
<term>McAtee, John</term><!-- deponent -->
<term>McComas, William</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Nacey</term><!-- negro boy; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Nan</term><!-- negro woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Nanny Girl</term><!-- negro girl, 11 yrs; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Neale, Anthony</term><!-- of Charles County; husband of Elizabeth Roswell; slaveholder of Elizabeth Shorter & Robin, gifted by William Roswell; slaveholder of SEE NAMES -->
<term>Ned</term><!-- mulatto boy abt 1/2 yr; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Nell</term><!-- negro woman; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Onion, John Barrett</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Pegg</term><!-- negro girl, about 12; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Pegg</term><!-- negro girl, 5 yr; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Peter</term><!-- mulatto boy abt 11 yrs; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Petter</term><!-- mulatta man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Polley</term><!-- mulatto girl abt 5; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Richardson, Benjamin</term><!-- juror -->
<term>Robin</term><!-- little Robin; negro man; married to Elizabeth Shorter abt 1681; enslaved by William Roswell; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Roswell, Elizabeth</term><!-- daughter of William and Ema; married Anthony Neale -->
<term>Roswell, Ema</term><!-- abt 70 in 15 June 1702; widow of William Roswell -->
<term>Roswell, William</term><!-- died before 15 June 1702; slaveholder of Elizabeth Shorter & Robin, then gifted to Anthony Neale -->
<term>Sam</term><!-- negro boy abt 1/2 yr; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Sarah</term><!-- negro girl, 8 yrs; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Shorter, Elizabeth</term><!-- white woman; married to Robin abt 1681; enslaved by William Roswell; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Sipeo</term><!-- negro man, old blind lame; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Stone, Michael Jenifer</term>
<term>Timboy</term><!-- negro boy, abt 10; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Tom</term><!-- negro man; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Tommy</term><!-- mulatto boy abt 1 1/2; enslaved by Anthony Neale -->
<term>Turner, Alexander</term><!-- register of King and Queen Parish -->
<term>Turner, John B.</term><!-- clerk of Charles County Court -->
<term>Wailes, Edward Lloyd</term><!-- sheriff of Prince George's County -->
<term>Young, Notley</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles Countu (Md.)</term>
<term>Prince George's County (Md.)</term>
<term>St. Mary's County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
<term>Upper Marlboro (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Verdict for Plaintiff</term>
<term>Appealed by Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Basil</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Rozer, Henry</persName><!-- Rozier -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gantt, John Mackall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pinkney, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Dorsey, William Hammond</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-06-05" who="#kln">reviewed and edited transcription; encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p020" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Henry Rozier</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Ha Cor. Petition for Freedom Issues Joined Jurors return and find for the Petitioner upon both Issues. Depositions filed Exception and Copy of a Record filed</p>

<p>Therefore it is considered by the Judges of the Court here that the Petitioner be free and discharged from all further servitude: And that the said Henry Rozier pay him the costs of prosecuting his petition.</p>

<p>Appeal prayed and granted to the High Court of Appeals. Ordered that the proceedings be transmitted.</p>

<list>
<item>1 John Barrett Onion</item>
<item>2 William Gordon</item>
<item>3 James Cresap</item>
<item>4 Henry Crist</item>
<item>5 Benja Hungerford</item>
<item>6 Thomas Hellen</item>
<item>7 Benja Richardson</item>
<item>8 William Hammond</item>
<item>9 Thomas Lingan</item>
<item>10 Robert Baden</item>
<item>11 William McComas</item>
<item>12 Stephen Jones</item>
</list>

</div2>

<gap extent="about 220 pages"/>

<pb xml:id="p242" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.002.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Henry Rozer</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore <unclear>towit</unclear> on the seventeenth day of June in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, the Petitioner by Gabriel Duvall his Attorney sued forth out of the General Court here the writ of the State of Maryland of Certiorari to the Justices of Prince Georges County directed in the words and of the tenor following, to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sct To the Justices of Prince Georges County, Greeting. Whereas lately in our said Court Henry Rozier late of Prince Georges County, was summoned to answer unto Basil Shorter of a Plea for Freedom which said Plea is still depending before you our said Justices in our said County Court, as it is said, undetermined and we being desirous for certain reasons, that the record and Proceeding in the plea aforesaid should by you be certified to us, do command you, that you send under your seals, the record of the Proceedings aforesaid in the Plea aforesaid, with all things touching the same, into our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis the second Tuesday of October next plainly and distinctly and in as full and ample manner, as it now remains before you, together with this Writ so that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what shall appear to us of right ought to be done. Witness the Honourable Samuel Chase Esquire, Chief Judge of our said Court the thirty first day of May Anno Domini 1794.</p>

<p>Issued the 17th day of June 1794.</p>

<p>Jno Gwinn Cl</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four comes here into the General Court the said Basil Shorter by his Attorney aforesaid and the Justices of Prince

<pb xml:id="p243" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.003.jpg"/>

Georges County in pursuance of the command of the said writ make return of a certain Record of Proceedings in the Plea aforesaid in the words and of the Tenor following, to wit</p>

<p>Prince Georges County, to wit.</p>

<p>At a County Court of the State of Maryland held for the County aforesaid at Upper Marlborough Town in said County on the first Monday in September being the first day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four.</p>

<p>Present.<lb/>
Michael Jenifer Stone Esquire Chief Justice<lb/>
David Craufurd and Thomas Duckett Esquires Associate Justices<lb/>
William John Jackson Esquire Sheriff<lb/>
John R Magruder Junr Clk.</p>

<p>In the Record of Proceedings of the same Court among others things is the following to wit.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Basil Shorter<lb/>
a<lb/>
Henry Rozer</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Prince Georges County, to wit</p>

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore, to wit on the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety one Basil Shorter by Gabriel Duvall and John Mackall Gantt his Attorney preferred to the Court here his Petition for Freedom against Henry Rozer in the words following, to wit.</p>

<p>To the Worshipful the Justices of Prince Georges County.</p>

<p>The Petition of Basil Shorter humbly sheweth that he is held in slavery by Henry Rozer Esquire of the County aforesaid although he considers himself entitled to his Freedom being lineally descended in the female line from Elizabeth Shorter a free white woman. He therefore prays your Worships to order summons to issue against the said Henry Rozer to attend this Court &amp; answer the Premises and he will pray and so forth.</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Pet.</p>

<p>Which said Petition being read and heard it was by the Court here ordered that summons issue against the said Henry Rozer that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear immediately before the Justices of our County Court now setting to answer the Petition aforesaid which said summons was accordingly issued and return thereof <fw type="catch">made</fw>

<pb xml:id="p244" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.004.jpg"/>

made by Edward Lloyd Wailes Gentleman Sheriff of the County aforesaid that he hath summoned the said Henry Rozer to appear and answer the Petition aforesaid according to the exigence of the said Summons as thereby he was directed.</p>

<p>And thereupon agreeable to the said summons comes the said Henry Rozer by Philip Barton Key and William Hammond Dorsey his Attorney and at the Prayer of the said Basil Shorter by his Attorneys aforesaid it is ordered by the Court here that the said Henry Rozer enter into Recognizance with one sufficient security in the sum of two hundred pounds current money not to transport the said Basil Shorter, but to suffer him to appear to prosecute his Petition for Freedom and at all times allow him a reasonable time to advise with his counsel on his said Petition &amp;ca</p>

<p>Whereupon Henry Rozer and Notley Young present here in Court in the proper persons acknowledge themselves to owe and stand justly indebted to the State of Maryland in the sum of two hundred pounds current money to be levied of their and each of their Bodies, goods and chattels Lands, and Tenements to the use of the said state into whosoever hands they shall come on condition that the said Henry Rozier shall not transport a certain Negro Basil Shorter from the State of Maryland but shall suffer and permit him the said Basil Shorter to appear at the next County Court to be held at Upper Marlborough Town in Prince Georges County on the first Monday in September next to prosecute the said Petition for Freedom and at all times suffer the said Basil Shorter to have a reasonable time to advise with his Counsel on his said Petition. The the above Recognizance to be void, otherwise of force.</p>

<p>And the said Basil Shorter and Henry Rozer by their Attorneys enter into the following agreement which is filed, to wit.</p>

<p>Ruled by the consent of Parties in this cause that the Depositions of Dorothy Hall, Giles Green, James Gates, Walter Hanson, John McAtee, John Clements, and Patrick Hamilton taken on ten days Notice to the adverse Party on their counsel be read as evidence in this cause and in the other Petitions against Notley Young Esqr &amp; Mary Hurley</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Pet.</p>
<gap extent="one signature line" reason="incomplete image"/>

<pb xml:id="p245" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.005.jpg"/>

<p>And thereupon day is given as well to the said Basil Shorter as to the said Henry Rozer by their Attorneys aforesaid to hear the allegation and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer of and upon the Premises aforesaid untill the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day, to wit, the first Monday in September in the year seventeen hundred and ninety one aforesaid come here again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid and at the prayer of the Parties <del>aforesaid</del> by their said Attorneys <del>aforesaid</del> leave is granted by the Court to take depositions on either side on giving five days Notice to the adverse Party.</p>

<p>And thereupon day is further given to the parties aforesaid to hear the Allegations and evidence as well on the Part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer of and upon the premises aforesaid until the first Monday in April next.</p>

<p>At which day, to wit, the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety two here come again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid and at the prayer of the said Parties by their said Attorneys leave is granted by the Court to take Depositions by either Party on giving ten days Notice to Notley Young and Henry Rozer on to either of them or either of their Attorneys and thereupon day is further given to the said Parties to hear the allegations, and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer of and upon the Premises aforesaid until the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day, to with the first Monday in September in the year last aforesaid here come again the parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid, and thereupon day is further given to the said parties to hear the Allegations and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer of and upon the Premises aforesaid until the first Monday in April next.</p>

<p>At which day, to wit, the first Monday in April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety three here come again the parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid And thereupon by consent of the said parties and their Attorneys aforesaid, day is further given to the said Parties <fw type="catch">to</fw>

<pb xml:id="p246" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.006.jpg"/>

to hear the allegations and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer untill the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day, to wit, the first Monday in September in the year last aforesaid here come again the Parties aforesaid by their Attornies aforesaid. And thereupon by Consent of the Parties and their Attorneys aforesaid, day is further given to the said Parties to hear the allegations and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer until the first Monday in April next.</p>

<p>At which day to with the first Monday in the April in the year seventeen hundred and ninety four here come again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid And thereupon by consent of the Parties and their Attorneys aforesaid day is further given to the said parties to hear the allegations and evidence as well on the part and behalf of the said Basil Shorter as the said Henry Rozer untill the first Monday in September next.</p>

<p>At which day, to wit the first Monday in September in the year last aforesaid here come again the Parties aforesaid by their Attorneys aforesaid. And the said Basil Shorter by his Attorneys aforesaid produces to the Court here the State of Maryland's Writ of Certiorari closed in the following words, to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sct To the Justices of Prince George County Greeting. Whereas lately in our said Court Henry Rozer late of Prince Georges County was summoned to answer unto Basil Shorter of a Plea of Freedom which said Plea is still depending before you our said Justices in our said County Court as it is said undetermined and We being desirous for certain reasons that the Record of Proceedings in the Plea aforesaid should by you be certified to us, do command you that you send under your seals the Record of the Proceedings aforesaid in the Plea aforesaid with all things touching the same unto our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis the second Tuesday of October next plainly and distinctly and in as full and ample manner as it now remains before you together with this Writ so that we may be able thereon to proceed and to do what shall appear to us of right ought to be done Witness the Honorable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of our said Court the thirty first

<pb xml:id="p247" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.007.jpg"/>

day of May Anno Domini 1794.</p>

<p>Issued the 17th day of June 1794.</p>

<p>Jno Gwinn Clk<lb/>
GD.</p>

<p>Which aforesaid Writ of Certiorari being by the Court here received and allowed. It is ordered that the record of Proceedings in the Plea aforesaid with all things relating to the same be transmitted to the Honorable the Judges of the General Court a Transcript whereof together with the Writ of Certiorari annexed is hereby transmitted accordingly.</p>

<p>Test John R. Magruder Junr Clk</p>

<p>In Testimony that the aforegoing is a true copy taken from the Record of Proceedings of Prince Georges County Court, I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal of my office this tenth day of October seventeen hundred and ninety four.</p>

<p>John Read Magruder Junr Clk of Prince Georges County Court</p>

<p>At which aforementioned second Tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four comes into the General Court here as well the aforesaid Basil Shorter the Petitioner aforesaid by Gabriel Duvall and William Pinkney his Attorneys as the said Henry Rozier by Philip Barton Key and William Hammond Dorsey his Attornies. And as well the aforesaid Basil Shorter the Petitioner aforesaid by his Attornies aforesaid as the said Henry Rozer by his Attornies aforesaid files in Court here the following Depositions, to wit.</p>

<p>At the request of Mr Anthony Neale the following Certificate and Deposition were recorded.</p>

<p>Maryland Sst Mary's County. These are to certify that in ye yeare one thousand six hundred and eighty one or near about that time I Nicholas Gulick Preist the subscriber hereof did Joyne together in the Holy Estate of Matrimony according to then Law a Negro Man (named to the best of my remembrance little Robin) to a white Woman whose name was Elizabeth Shorter which couple all that time were both servants unto Mr William Roswell (deceased) and was after as I am informed disposed of by the said Roswell unto Mr Anthony Neale of Charles County.</p>

<p>Certified under my hand this 15th day of June Anno 1702</p>
 
<p>Nicholas Geulick.</p>

<pb xml:id="p248" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.008.jpg"/>

<p>Memorandum. They day and yeare above came before me Mr Geulick and made Oath upon the Holy Evangelist that the above Affidavit is ye whole truth and nothing butt ye truth, Juratt coram me</p>

<p>Joshua Guibert.</p> 

<p>Maryland Ss. St Mary's County, Ema Roswell Widow aged seaventy years or thereabouts being sworne on ye Holy Evangelist declareth upon her Oath that she the said Deponant was present att the marriage of the above said couple and that the Seremony was performed by the above said Mr. Nicholass Gulick, Preist and that the Negro Man's name was little Robin, and the white woman's name Elizabeth Shorter and that they were at the time of their being marryed both servants unto this Deponants Husband, William Roswell decd and by him given and made over and delivered up unto Anthony Neale upon marriage of the said Neale wth Elizabeth the daughter of sd Roswell &amp; have remained in ye said Neales service ever since, &amp; yt after the marriage of ye sd Negro Man &amp; White Woman ye sd White Woman had three mollatto Girl Children named Mary, Jane, and Martha, who are now liveing to the best of this Deponant's knowledge</p>

<p>This 15th day of June Anno 1702.</p>

<p>Jurat coram me Joshua Guibert</p>

<p>Maryland St. Mary's County Ss. King &amp; Queen Parrish June 6th 1702. Then Recorded upon ye Record Book of the above said Parrish the two within affidavits, one of Mr Nicholass Gewlick Preist the other of Mrs Ema Roswell this being a true coppy as now Given under my hand the day and date above</p>

<p><unclear>P</unclear> Me Wm Havett Clk vestry 1702. Entred on the Records of Charles County June ye 25th 1703.</p>

<p>Maryland Charles County, to wit</p>

<p>In testimony that the aforegoing Certificates &amp; deposition are truly copied from Liber W No 1 Folios 225 &amp; 226 one of the Land Records of Charles County, I have hereunto set my hand &amp; affixed the seal of my office this 15th day of August 1791.</p>

<p>Jno B Turner Clk of Charles County Court</p>

<p>State if Maryland Charles County, to wit</p>

<p>I certify that I have made an accurate search for the original Certificate and Affidavits of Nicholas <fw type="catch">Guelick</fw>

<pb xml:id="p249" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.009.jpg"/>

Guelick and Ema Roswell respecting the marriage of a Negro Man by the name of little Robin to a white Woman named Elizabeth Shorter and that the same are not to be found among the Papers remaining in the Clerks office for the County aforesaid.</p>

<p>In Testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal of my office this 24 day of October Anna Domini 1794.</p>

<p>Jno B Turner Clk of Charles County</p>

<p>October 24th 1794.</p>

<p>Sir<lb/>
The Books which the vestry of King &amp; Queen Parish put in my Hands contains nothing recorded further back than 1744. It is possible the marriage you want might have been recorded in one of them as part of that which contains the marriages is destroyed. If there be any other Book or Books they have never come under my Notice nor have ever I heard of any other. I shall particularly inquire of the several Vestry Men whether they know of any other Book or Books belonging to the said Parish and if there should be any I will make a strict search and if should be successful in finding a Record of the Marriage you write for, I will forward a Certificat with all possible speed. I am yours &amp;c</p>

<p>Alexander Turner, Register King and Queen Parish</p>

<p>Mr G. Duvall, Annapolis</p> 

<p>An Inventory of the Goods and Chattels of Mr Anthony Neale late of Charles County deced. Appraised as follows (vizt) 1 Old Negro man called Harrey at £10. 1 old ditto called Frank £20 1 Lusty Negroe Man called Andrew £32. 1 Ditto called Grey £32. 1 Ditto called Tom £30. 1 Ditto called Jeffery £30. A Do called Robin £30. A Malatta Woman called Mary £28. 1 Negro Do called Cherry £25 1 Do Nell £25. 1 Do Bets, £25. 1 Do Nan, £22. 1 Do Jenny £28 1 Negro Girl abt 12 year old called Pegg £20 A Do 11 year old called Nanny Girl £18. 1 Do 8 year old Sarah £15 1 Do 6 year old Betty £12. 1 Do 5 year old Bets £10 1 Do 5 year old Pegg £10. 1 Do Boy named Timboy abt 10 year old £18. 1 Do abt 3 year old named Nacey £6 1 Do called Sam abt 1/2 year old £1 1 Do Charles abt 1 1/2 year old £2: 1 Malatta Man named Petter £35: 1 Do Boy John abt 14 year old £18: 1 Do Andrew abt 12 year old £16: 1 Do Peter abt 11 year old £17: 1 Do Charles abt 9 year old £15: <fw type="catch">1</fw>

<pb xml:id="p250" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.001.010.jpg"/>

1 Do Tommy abt 1 1/2 year old £2: 1 Do sick called Ned abt 1/2 year old £1: 1 Do Girl called Kate abt 7 year old £14: 1 Do called Polley abt 5 year old £10: 1 old Blind lame, Negroe, Man Sipeo worth nothing.</p>








In Testimony that the within is a true extract from the Inventory of Anthony Neale of Charles County ___? the 9th day of February 1723 and recorded among the Records of the late Prerogatives Office, and that it contains all the Negroes in said Inventory.the remainder consisting of stock, Provisions and Plantation utensils. I have hereto set my hand a affixed my seal of office this 27th day of March in the year of our Lord 1792.
Jn Gassaway Regr
will a Co?

Basil Shorter v. Henry Rozier
Pet. in Prince Georges County Court of Freedom
William Hill of Prince Georges County aged fifty eight years and upwards being sworn on the Holy Evangels of Almighty God deposits and saith that he knows Basil the Petitioner and he knew Linda the mother of Basil ever since he was five or six years old. That the Deponent served his Apprenticeship with Richard McHenry a Bricklayer, and the year after he was out of his apprenticeship, which was when he was twenty one years of age he was at work at the House of the defendant and reputed mother of Linda which Mary the Deponent always understood the Defendant got by his marriage with his wife the daughter of Mr.Neale. being asked what was the Christian name of the said Neale, answered Edward and the Deponent says he has often heard John Parnham of Charles County now deceased, when the Deponent was a boy and waited on him, say that Mary aforesaid the mother of Linda had as much right to her freedom as the mother of the Deponent had. That the Deponents mother was the daughter of a white woman and this the Deponent heard the said John Parnham says so to his wife several times that at the times aforesaid he called the said Mary old Mool short and that the said John Parnam was son of John Parnham and Uncle to Doctor John Parnham now living in Charles County and he thinks has been dead upwards of forty years. Being asked from whom he heard that Mr. Roger got the aforesaid Mol by marriage with the
















</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>