<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0012.019">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Patty Shorter v. Thomas Stone. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Hyman, Christy" xml:id="ch">Christy Hyman</name>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0012.019</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0534</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1795-10">October 1795</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-25 JG 29</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1795-10">October 1795</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term/>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Charles County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Patty</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Clement</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Ned</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Bett</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, Joseph</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shorter, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Stone, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019-08-02" who="#kln">reviewed and edited transcription; encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#ch">preliminary transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb xml:id="p110" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Patty Shorter and her Six children, Clement, Charles, Ned, Bett, Joseph, and James.<lb/>
against<lb/>
Thomas Stone</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit, on the twelfth day of May in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two; Patty Shorter for her self and her six children Clement, Charles, Ned, Bett, Joseph and James by Gabriel Duvall her attorney <sic>prefered</sic> and filed in the General Court here her petition for Freedom against Thomas Stone which is in form following to wit.</p>

<p>To the honourable the Judges of the General Court. The Petition of Patty Shorter humbly sheweth, that she (together with her six children Clement, Charles, Ned, Bett, Joseph, James) is held in slavery by Thomas Stone of Charles County, and she is advised that she is entitled to her Freedom being descended in the female line from a  free white woman she therefore prays your honours the premises being considered to discharge

<pb xml:id="p111" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.002"/>

them from the custody of the said Thomas Stone should they prove their descent as aforesaid and that summons may issue for the said Thomas Stone to answer unto this petition and she will pray and so forth. G Duvall for petr.</p>

<p>Whereupon in pursuance of the rule of the Court here in such cases made and provided, the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid, on the day and year aforesaid, prosecuted and sued forth out of the General Court here the writ of the State of Maryland of Subpoena ad respondendum against the said Thomas Stone directed to the sheriff of Charles County in form following to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland to wit. To the sheriff of Charles County Greeting. We command you that you summons Thomas Stone that all excuses and delays set aside he be and appear before the Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of May next to answer unto the petition of Patty Shorter and her children preferred against him for freedom hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril and have you then and there this writ. Witness the honourable Samuel Chase Esquire Chief Judge of our Said Court the Eighth day of May 1792.</p>

<p>Issued the 12th day of May Anno Domini 1792. GD. Jnp Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the ninth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two, and the day of the return of the aforegoing summons comes into the General Court here, the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid; And the sheriff of Charles County aforesaid to whom the said summons was in form aforesaid <sic>aforesaid</sic> directed makes no return thereof to the Court here: And the said Thomas Stone comes not into the General Court here: Whereupon the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid, afterwards to wit, on the twenty second day of December in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety two again prosecuted and sued forth out of the General Court here the writ of the State of Maryland of Subpoena ad respondendum against the said Thomas Stone directed to the sheriff of Charles County in form following to wit.</p>

<p>The State of Maryland to wit, To the sheriff of Charles County, Greeting. We command you that you summons Thomas Stone that all delays and Excuses set a side he be and appear before the Judges of our <catchwords>General</catchwords>

<pb xml:id="p112" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.003"/>

General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis on the second Tuesday of May next to answer unto the petition of Patty Shorter and her children <sic>prefered</sic> against him for freedom hereof he is not to fail and fail not at your peril have you then and there this writ. Witness the honourable Samuel Chase Esquire chief Judge of our said Court the 19th day of November 1792.</p>

<p>Issued the 22d day of December Anno Domini 1792. GD. Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the Fourteenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three, and the day of the return of the last aforegoing summons comes again into the General Court here the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid; And the sheriff of Charles County aforesaid to whom the said Summons was in form aforesaid directed, makes return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed to wit. Summoned James Simms Shff.</p>

<p>Whereupon comes into the General Court here the said Thomas stone by Philip Barton Key his attorney; And on motion of the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six Children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid it is ruled by the Court here that the said Thomas Stone enter into a recognizance to the State of Maryland in the usual form in such Cases made and provided. Whereupon a certain Thomas Andrew Dyson of Charles County comes into Court in his proper person and acknowledges himself to owe and stand justly indebted to the State of Maryland in the sum of three hundred pounds current money to be levied of his body Goods and Chattels lands and tenements to and for the use of the said State of Maryland on Condition that the said Thomas Stone do not remove the said Patty Shorter and her six children, Clement, Charles, Ned, Bett, Joseph and James out of the said State of Maryland nor obstruct the said Patty Shorter from attending this Court from time to time in support of her petition for freedom exhibited in the said court for herself and her six children aforesaid against the said Thomas Stone and his the mean time to feed cloath and use her the said Patty Shorter and her six children aforesaid, well and pay whatever

<pb xml:id="p113" facs="oscys.mdcase.0012.019.004"/>

satisfaction the Court shall adjudge for the service of the said Patty Shorter and her six children aforesaid from his Term to the time of the Judgement with costs. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is continued until the second Tuesday of October next, the same day is given to the parties aforesaid, then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eighth day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General Court here as well the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid, by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Thomas Stone by his attorney aforesaid; Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday of May next; the <sic>the</sic> same day its given to the said parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred an ninety four come again into the General Court here as well the said Patty Shorter for herself and her six children aforesaid, by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Thomas Stone by his attorney aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second tuesday of October next; the same day is given to the said Parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of October being the fourteenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, come again into the General Court here as well the said Patty Shorter for self and her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid as the said Thomas Stone by his attorney aforesaid; Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is further continued until the second tuesday of May next; the same day is given to the said parties then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second tuesday of May being the twelfth day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety five, come again into the General Court here as well the said Patty Shorter for self and her six children by her attorney aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid as the said Thomas Stone by his attorney aforesaid; Thereupon further <catchwords>process</catchwords>


</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
