<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.mdcase.0015.001">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Hannah, Mary, Anne, Hannah, Daniel, Silla, &amp; Peggy Hawkins v. Sarah Disney. Judgment Record</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>University of Maryland</sponsor>
<sponsor>National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>

<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.mdcase.0015.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0667</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>
Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Judgment Record</title>
<date when="1795-10">October 1795</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Maryland State Archives</repository>
<collection>General Court of the Western Shore (Judgment Record)</collection>
<idno>MSA S497-25 JG 29</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Judgment Record</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1795-10">October 1795</date></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.006871">Barnes, Eleanor</term>
<term xml:id="per.006877">Barry, Joshua</term>
<term xml:id="per.002083">Brice, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006878">Brookes, Daniel</term>
<term xml:id="per.004601">Bullen, J.</term>
<term xml:id="per.006884">Burgess, West</term>
<term xml:id="per.001514">Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811</term>
<term xml:id="per.006741">Disney, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006882">Disney, Rachel</term>
<term xml:id="per.000073">Disney, Richard</term>
<term xml:id="per.006872">Disney, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.004367">Goldsmith, William</term>
<term xml:id="per.001493">Gwinn, John</term>
<term xml:id="per.006881">Hawkins, Quash</term>
<term xml:id="per.006873">Hawkins, Sharpe</term>
<term xml:id="per.006879">Howard, Joseph</term>
<term xml:id="per.001507">Mackubin, James</term>
<term xml:id="per.006880">Nicholson, Stephen</term>
<term xml:id="per.001477">Quynn, Allen</term>
<term xml:id="per.006875">Snowden</term>
<term xml:id="per.006874">Stevenson, Eleanor</term>
<term xml:id="per.006883">Ward, Sarah</term>
<term xml:id="per.006876">Williams, Ennion</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Anne Arundel County (Md.)</term>
<term>Calvert County (Md.)</term>
<term>Annapolis (Md.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Petitioner</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>

<particDesc>
<listPerson>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006863">
<persName>Hawkins, Hannah</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006864">
<persName>Hawkins, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006865">
<persName>Hawkins, Anne</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006866">
<persName>Hawkins, Hannah</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006867">
<persName>Hawkins, Daniel</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006868">
<persName>Hawkins, Silla</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006869">
<persName>Hawkins, Peggy</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006870">
<persName>Disney, Sarah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.001393">
<persName>Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.001495">
<persName>Key, Philip Barton, 1757-1815</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Maryland. General Court of the Western Shore</orgName>
<placeName>Annapolis (Md.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2021-01-29" who="#kln">transcribed; encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>

<div1 type="case">

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.001"/>

<div2 type="caption">

<p>Hannah Hawkins and her
Six children Mary, Anne,
Hannah, Daniel, Silla and Peggy<lb/>
against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>Be it remembered that heretofore
to wit, one the Thirtieth day of May
in the year of our Lord one thousand 
seven hundred and ninety two;
Hannah Hawkins for herself and
her six children, Mary, Anne,
Hannah, Daniel, Silla and Peggy by Gabriel Duvall her attorney
preferred and filed in the General Court here, her petition for
Freedom against Sarah Disney, which is in form following to
wit.</p>

<p>To the honourable the Judges of the General Court. The petition
of Hannah Hawkins humbly sheweth, that she (together with
her six Children, Mary, Anne, Hannah, Daniel, Silla, Peggy) is
held in slavery by Sarah Disney of Ann Arundel County and
she is advised that they are entitled to their freedom, being
<sic>decended</sic> from a free woman. she therefore prays your honours

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.002"/>

(the premises be considered) to discharge them from the
further service of the said Sarah Disney, and that summons
may issue for the said Sarah Disney to answer unto
this petition and she will pray and so forth.</p>

<p>G. Duvall for Petnr</p>

<p>Whereupon, in pursuance of the rule and order of the
Court here in such case made on the day of preferring
and <sic>fileing</sic> the said Petition the said Hannah Hawkins
for herself and her six Children aforesaid by her attorney
aforesaid prosecuted and sued forth out of the General
Court here, the writ of the State of Maryland of Subpoena
ad respondendum against the said Sarah Disney directed
to the sheriff of Anne Arundel County in form following to wit</p>

<p>The State of Maryland Sc. To the sheriff of Ann Arundel
County, Greeting. We command you that you summons
Sarah Disney late of Ann Arundel County that all excuses
and delays be set a side she be and appear before the
Judges of our General Court to be held at the City of Annapolis
on the second Tuesday of October next, to answer the
petition of Hannah Hawkins and her six children,
Mary, Anne, Hannah, Daniel, Silla, and Peggy, prefered
against her for freedom. Hereof she is not to fail and
fail not at your peril and have you then and there
this writ. Witness the honourable Samuel Chase Esquire
Chief Judge of our said Court the 25th day of May Anno
Domini 1792.</p>

<p>Issued the 30th day of May 1792. G.D. Jno Gwinn Clk.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the
ninth day o the said month in the year of our Lord one
thousand seven hundred and ninety two, and the day
of the return of the aforegoing summons comes into the 
General Court here the said Hannah Hawkins for herself
and <sic>here</sic> six Children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid
and the sheriff of Anne Arundel County aforesaid to whom
the said Summons was in form aforesaid directed, makes
return thereof to the Court here thus endorsed to wit.</p>

<p>Summoned. William Goldsmith Sheriff.</p>

<p>Whereupon, comes into the General Court here the said Sarah
<catchwords>Disney</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.003"/>

Disney by Philip Barton Key her attorney, and on motion of the said
Hannah Hawkins for herself and her six children aforesaid by her
attorney aforesaid it is ruled by the Court here that the said Sarah
Disney enter into a Recognizance to the State of Maryland in the
usual form in such cases made and provided. Whereupon a
certain James Disney of Anne Arundel County comes into Court here in
his proper person, and acknowledges himself to owe and stand justly
indebted to the State of Maryland in the sum of two hundred pounds
Current money, to be levied of his body goods and Chattels, lands and 
tenements, to and for the use of the said State of Maryland, on
Condition that the said Hannah Hawkins and her six children
or either of them out of the said State of Maryland nor obstruct the
said Hannah Hawkins from attending this Court from time to time
in support of her petition for Freedom exhibited on behalf of herself and her six
Children aforesaid, in the said Court against the said Sarah Disney
and in the mean time to feed cloath and use her the said
Hannah Hawkins and her six children aforesaid well, and pay
whatever satisfaction the Court shall adjudge for the services of the said Hannah Hawkins and her six children aforesaid
from this Term to the time of the Judgment with costs.</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid,
between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is continued
between the parties aforesaid by order of the Court here is continued
until the second Tuesday of May next; the same day is given to the parties aforesaid then, and soforth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the fourteenth
day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand 
seven hundred and ninety three, come again into the General
Court here as well the said Hannah Hawkins for herself and
her six children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid as the
said Sarah Disney by her attorney aforesaid and the said
Hannah Hawkins for herself and her six children aforesaid by her Attorney aforesaid files in Court here the Depositions of Eleanor
Stevenson and Eleanor Barnes which are in form following towit</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins and her Children<lb/>
Against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in the
General Court.</p>

<p>The deposition of Eleanor Barnes
of Anne Arundel County
aged twenty nine years being sworn on the holy Evangely of
<catchwords>Almighty</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.004"/>

Almighty God deposeth and saith that she has lived a near
Neighbour for nearly two years to Mr Sarah Disney the
defendant in this cause, and saith that the said Sarah has
at several different times informed the deponent since her
acquaintance with her, that the mother of Hannah the
petitioner who is now present was a free woman, free as
the deponent is, and that she could take no rest, and could
not die easy untill she set them at their liberty for that they had
a right to be free, but her children would not let them go.
She further saith that the said Sarah Disney the defendant
informed the deponent that the mother of Hannah had a
son younger than Hannah and who was sucking at his mothers
Breast when her husband William Disney bought them, the
said Hannah and her brother whose name the deponent has
heard was Sharper, and that he is now a freeman in Calvert
County, and she further informed the deponent that they were
bought by her said Husband to serve him untill they come
of age; that they were brought in a vessel from new England
with their mother who was a sickly woman, and sold, (without the
mother) to the defendants Husband; that he bought them when
young as aforesaid and when he brought them home she asked
him why he bought two such young things, to which he answered
that he gave but a mere trifle for them and bought them only
until they came of age and did not buy them for life and
took them for pity's sake or charity's Sake or Words to that
effect. she further told her that the mother died soon after
somewhere in the Neighbourhood. This the said Sarah Disney
has repeated several times to the deponent of her own accord
and seemed to be very uneasy on account of her Children's
refusing to let them <sic>them</sic> have their liberty.</p>

<p>Sworn before me this 20th May 1793. Allen Quynn.</p>

<p>The deposition of Eleanor Stevenson a free mulatto woman
born free and living with Major Snowden of Anne Arundel
County aforesaid about fifty one years deposeth and saith
being first duly sworn in the Cause aforesaid saith that
she has heard Sarah Disney the defendant several times
Cry and say that she could have no rest and could never 
die easy untill Hannah the Petitioner and her Children <catchwords>were</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.005"/>

were free; for that her husband had bought them to serve until
they come of age and not for life, and that they were free, but
her children would not agree that they should be free.</p>

<p>Sworn before me this 20th May 1793. Allen Quynn.</p>

<p>Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid
between the parties aforesaid, by order of the Court here is further
continued until the second Tuesday of October next; the same
day is given to the parties aforesaid then and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the Eighth day
of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven
hundred and ninety three, come again into the General Court here
as well the said Hannah Hawkins for herself and her six Children
aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Sarah Disney by
her attorney aforesaid. Thereupon further process of and upon
the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid by order
of the Court here, is further continued untill the second tuesday
of May next; the same day is given to the parties aforesaid, then
and so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May being the thirteenth
day of the said month in the year of our Lord one thousand seven
hundred and ninety four, come again into the General Court
here as well the said Hannah Hawkins for herself and her six
Children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid, as the said Sarah
Disney by her attorney aforesaid: And the said Hannah Hawkins
for herself and her six Children aforesaid by her attorney aforesaid
files in Court here the Deposition of Ennion Williams, which
is in form following to wit.</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins<lb/>
against<lb/>
<sic>Rachel</sic> Disney</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in the General Court
Ennion Williams of Anne Arundel County,
aged about thirty eight years being one of the
People called Quakers did solemnly truly and
sincerely declare and affirm that he has known Eleanor Barnes a
witness sworn in this cause about ten years, that during the space of
two years the husband of the said Eleanor Barnes was employed
by this affirmant when they lived very near him, and he
never heard any thing against the Character of the said
Eleanor Barnes; that she appeared to conduct herself with
propriety, and he thinks deserving of Credit. Affirmed before me
this 15th May 1794. Allen Quynn.</p>

<p><catchwords>Thereupon</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.006"/>

Thereupon further process of and upon the premises aforesaid
between the parties aforesaid by order of the court here is
further continued until the second tuesday of October next 
the same day is given to the parties aforesaid, then, and
so forth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of October being the
fourteenth day of the said month in the year of our Lord
one thousand seven hundred and ninety four, come again
into the General Court here as well the said Hannah Hawkins
for herself and her six Children aforesaid by her attorney
aforesaid, as the said Sarah Disney by her attorney aforesaid
Thereupon further process of and upon the premises
aforesaid between the parties aforesaid, by order of the 
Court here is further continued until the second Tuesday
of May next; the same day is given to the parties aforesaid
then and soforth.</p>

<p>At which said second Tuesday of May, being the twelfth
day of the same month in the year of our Lord one thousand
seven hundred and ninety five; Thereupon further process
of and upon the premises aforesaid between the parties aforesaid
by order of the Court here is further continued until the second
Tuesday of October next; the same day is given to the parties
aforesaid then and so forth.</p>

<p>And now at this day to wit, the said second Tuesday of
October being the thirteenth day of the said month in the year
of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and ninety five come
again into the General Court here as well the said Hannah
Hawkins for herself and her six children aforesaid by her
attorney aforesaid, as the said Sarah Disney by her
attorney aforesaid; And the said Hannah Hawkins for
herself and her six children aforesaid by her attorney
aforesaid files in Court here the several Depositions in form
following to wit.</p>

<p>Richard Disney of Anne Arundel County of the age of
seventy seven years being sworn on the holy <sic>Evangils</sic> of
Almighty God, deposeth and says, That he remembers the
Petitioner <sic>Hanah</sic> was a little Girl and bought out of a
Vessel as he always understood and heard by his Nephew <catchwords>William</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.007"/>

William Disney now dead who was the husband of Sarah Disney
the defendant, This deponent has often heard and always understood
that the said Hanah was bought as a slave, as other negroes usually
are, and this deponent never heard untill about the time of the
present Petition or a little before anything to the contrary. This
deponent knows that his nephew William Disney always claimed and
possessed the said Hanah as a slave, and that after the death of
said William his wife Sarah claimed and possessed Hanah and her
Children as slaves, and gave them as slaves to her children. This
deponent has understood that Mrs Sarah Disney changed her religion
and became a Methodist two or three years ago, and since that
time this Deponent has heard of a claim of said Hannah to be free
but this deponent in the course of a very intimate acquaintance
with the family of his Nephew William for forty years, never
heard of any claim of the said Hanah to her freedom before Mrs
Sarah Disney changed her Religion. Sworn to this 19th day of Octo
1793. Before me, James Maccubin</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins<lb/>
against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

<p>Joshua Barry in the 20th year of his age being
sworn on the holy Evangely of Almighty God
deposeth and saith, that about two months
ago he was at the plantation where Mrs Disney
the defendant lives, and in conversation with her she told him
that when the petitioner was small and was offered for sale at the
Inspection house point, one Daniel Brooke went down to the
Vessel and asked the old woman (who was the petitioners Mother
if she and her Children were to be sold, and she answered no
she was not to be sold, as Brooke told her, he then returned to
William Disney's (the defendants husband) and William Disney
asked him where his two little negroes were; he answered he
was not going to buy free negroes, and said she (Hannah's
mother) and her children were as free as he was That a few
days afterwards William Disney went down and bought the
Children, the old woman was gone; William Disney brought them
home and in two days afterwards Joseph Howard came over
and asked William Disney why he bought those two negroes
and said they were free, and as the new England Vessels were
going backwards and forwards they would be known and
taken away; William Disney answered, may be no, they will soon
<catchwords>grow</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.008"/>

grow out of knowledge and no one will know they had free
parents. The deponent being asked if he knows Eleanor Barnes
sworn in this cause, answers he does. Being asked her
general Character, answers he does not know much about her,
but believes she keeps low company; and says he has seen
Negroes at her house and laughing and talking with her and
he has seen them setting on her bed. And he further says that
as he was <sic>comming</sic> from Mill about a month ago he stopped
at Eleanor Barnes's house and she asked the deponent if Hannah
had come home, he answered no, and asked her if she had been to
Court and was sworn, she answered yes; he then asked her
what she had sworn and she replied that she had sworn that
Mrs Disney had told her that she would have set her negroes free long
ago had it not been for her Children he then went on and when
he got home he related to Mrs Disney what had passed, and
she said she did not say so, and if Eleanor Barnes had sworn
that, she swore false. Being asked if he knew what negroes
he had seen at Eleanor Barnes's answers they were the forge negroes
and on Sundays he had seen Strange Negroes but did not
know to whom they belonged. Being asked if Eleanor Barnes
lives on Land which belongs to the Messrs Snowden's answers she does
This deponent says that he did not understand from Mrs Disney
that she was present or not when the conversation passed
between her Husband and Howard above related, and that
Mrs Disney was in a great passion at the time she mentioned this
conversation. That Mrs Disney, is a Queer old woman she will
say one thing to day, and if affronted another tomorrow.</p>

<p>Sworn to before me this 24th Octo 1793. James Mackubin.</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins and others<lb/>
against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

<p>Ennion Williams of Anne Arundel
County aged thirty eight years being
one of the people called Quakers, and 
being called on to declare his knowledge
of this dispute did solemnly declare and affirm that some time in last
month he in conversation with the defendant Sarah Disney heard
her say that the mother of the Petitioner Hannah Hawkins
was a free person and died as such; and that when they
were brought from New England into the neighbourhood for
sale, Daniel Brookes one of the Neighbours said he would not
<catchwords>buy</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.009"/>

buy them for they were free; and she said that she the said Sarah
Disney had never denied them their freedom; and mentioned at the 
same time that she had understood that Joshua Barry a young
man had testified to the contrary; and further he saith not.</p>

<p>Affirmed before me this 22 October 1794. Allen Quynn.</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins
and her Children<lb/>
against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

<p>The Deposition of Stephen Nicholson aged
thirty six years being sworn on the holy 
Evangely of Almighty God in this cause saith
that he has heard that old Daniel Brookes
who lived near south river <sic>Chruch</sic> in Anne
Arundel County many years ago, and before William Disney the
late husband of the defendant bought Hannah the petitioner went
to Hannah's mother Quash Hawkins to buy Hannah and Sharper
<sic>he</sic> brother, and Brooks asked Quash the mother if she would sell
her two Children for life, and she answered no, she would not, the
said Brookes returned and would not buy them and went to the
house of William Disney aforesaid and told Disney of the circumstances
and that he would not buy them as they were not to serve for life
and were to be free at twenty one years of age; that the said William
Disney went down and bought them both, and when he bought
them home his brother asked him his reason for buying the Children
as they were to serve no longer than until they were twenty one years
of age; he replied he did not care as he gave but a <sic>trife</sic> for them. Being 
asked of whom he heard such conversation, answers he does not
remember, but that he has frequently heard the same over and over
again from white people; and he has heard Sarah Disney the
defendant say she wished they could be free, and when it come to
the point she would put in a good word for them; and he further
saith that he has heard in the neighbourhood that Sarah Disney the
defendant has said that Hannah was free, but that she could not set
her free, for if she did the Children would fall upon her for the Estate
that had been wasted, but he cannot recollect the persons of whom he
had this information; and he also says that he has always understood 
that the said Negroes were bought and sold at the inspecting house
Point on South river and that they were brought there by water
This <sic>Deponant</sic> doth not know that Quash Hawkins was the 
mother of Hannah and Sharper, but hath heard so and he
believes the said Quash Hawkins to have been a negro woman
<catchwords>and</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.010"/>

and this deponant knoweth nothing of the Petitioners right to
Freedom, but from flying reports. Sworn to before me this 22d
October 1792. Jno Brice.</p>

<p>Stephen Nicholson being again sworn in the presence of the
Counsel on both sides, saith that about ten years ago he heard
Mrs Disney the defendant and her daughter Rachel say that
Daniel Brookes went to Hannah's Mother, Quash Hawkins to buy
Hannah and Sharpe her brother, and asked Quash if she would
sell them for life to which she answered that she would not. upon 
which Brookes returned and would not buy them, and that
he went to the house of William Disney and told him of the
circumstances; that the said William Disney went down and
bought them both, and when he brought them home his brother
James asked him the reason why he bought them as they were to serve
no longer than until they were twenty one years of age, he replied
he did not care as he gave but a trifle for them. This he has heard from
them often and first about ten years ago which was about two years
after he was acquainted in the Disney family.</p>

<p>Sworn before me this 14th October 1795. Allen Quynn.</p>

<p>Hannah Hawkins<lb/>
against<lb/>
Sarah Disney</p>

<p>Petition for freedom in the General Court.
Sarah Ward a free Mulatto woman as said
of Anne Arundel County aged between forty
and fifty years being sworn on the holy
Evangely of Almighty God to testify the truth of her knowledge in
<sic>in</sic> this cause deposeth and saith that when she was a young
woman she went to the house of William Disney husband of the
defendant Sarah Disney, the day after the said William Disney
had bought and brought home two small negro children,
Hannah the Petitioner and her brother, as he informed the deponent
and West Burgess brother in Law of said William Disney was
there, and asked said Disney why he bought two such small
Children that would be of no service to him, he answered that
he gave but a trifle for them as they were free born, and as soon
as they came of age he should discharge them; upon which his wife
murmured; he told her he had bought them and should keep
them until they were of age, and then should discharge them
as they were free this deponent thinks she was about 12 or 13
years old at the time the above conversation passed between
<catchwords>her</catchwords>

<pb n="oscys.mdcase.0015.001.011"/>

her and Mr Disney. J Bullen.</p>

<p>Whereupon all and singular the premises aforesaid between the
Parties aforesaid by the Court here being seen heard and fully
understood, and mature deliberation thereupon had, for that it
appears to the Court here, that the said Hannah Hawkins the
Petitioner aforesaid and her six Children Mary, Anne, Hannah,
Daniel, Silla and Peggy are entitled to their Freedom, being
descended in the female line, from a Free woman, as she the said
Hannah Hawkins for herself and her six children aforesaid by her
said Petition to the Court here hath alledged; Therefore it is
considered by the Court here that the said Hannah Hawkins the
Petitioner aforesaid and her six Children Mary Anne, Hannah
Daniel, Silla and Peggy be free and discharged of and from the
service of the said Sarah Disney, and that she the said Hannah
Hawkins the Petitioner aforesaid and her six Children aforesaid
go thereof without day and so forth: It is also Considered by the
Court here, that the said Hannah Hawkins the Petitioner aforesaid
for herself and her six Children aforesaid, recover against the
said Sarah Disney the quantity of two thousand one hundred and
nine pounds of tobacco by the Court here unto her the said Hannah
Hawkins for herself and her six Children aforesaid, on her assent
adjudged for her costs and charges by her about the prosecution
of her petition aforesaid laid out and expended, and that she have
thereof her Execution and so forth.</p>

<p>Test John Gwinn Clk.</p>

</div2>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>