<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="oscys.report.0088.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Joseph Brown v. Mary Wingard. Court Report</title>
<principal n="Thomas, William G., 1964-" xml:id="wgt">William G. Thomas III</principal> 
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Nash, Kaci L." xml:id="kln">Kaci L. Nash</name>
</respStmt>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>O Say Can You See</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&amp;#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.report.0088.001</idno>
<idno type="case">oscys.caseid.0669</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to O Say Can You See, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Reports of Cases Civil and Criminal in the United States Circuit Court of the District of Columbia, from 1801 to 1841</title>
<author n="Cranch, William, 1769-1855">William Cranch</author>
<publisher>Little, Brown and Company</publisher>
<biblScope>Volume II</biblScope>
<date when="1852">1852</date>
<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Supplementary Documents</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Court Report</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Petition for Freedom</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1822-04">April 1822</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term xml:id="per.004262">Wingard, Abraham</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="outcome">
<term>Judgment for Defendant</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>          
 
<particDesc>   
<listPerson> 
<person role="petitioner" xml:id="per.006901">
<persName>Brown, Joseph</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant" xml:id="per.006902">
<persName>Wingard, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.000001">
<persName>Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner" xml:id="per.000435">
<persName>Jones, Walter, 1776-1861</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant" xml:id="per.000460">
<persName>Taney, Augustus</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>            

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States. Circuit Court (District of Columbia)</orgName>
<placeName>Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc> 
<change when="2022-07-14" who="#kln">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="report">

<pb n="p300" facs="oscys.report.0088.001.001.jpg"/>

<div2 type="caption"> 

<p>Joseph Brown, (Negro,) v. Mary Wingard.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="syllabus"> 

<p>No executory contract between a master and his slave can be enforced, either at law or in equity.</p>

</div2>

<div2 type="body">

<p>The petition of negro Joseph Brown, stated, that before the

<pb n="p301" facs="oscys.report.0088.001.002.jpg"/>

year 1818, he then being the slave of Abraham Wingard, the 
defendant's testator, entered into an agreement with the said
Abraham, at his, the said Abraham's request, for the purchase of
his freedom, at and for the sum of nine hundred dollars, to be
paid by the petitioner. That the said Abraham immediately
suffered the petitioner to go at large and labor for his own use;
and in the course of that year he paid the said Abraham $300,
and in the next year, $550, expressly as the purchase-money of
the petitioner's freedom, leaving a balance of fifty dollars due, as
appears by the receipt of the said Abraham, in his handwriting,
and signed by him, in these words. "1819. Received from
Joseph Brown five hundred and fifty dollars in part payment of
his freedom. Abraham Wingard. Due me now, from Joseph
Brown, fifty dollars, which, when paid, will be in full. A. W."</p>

<p>The petition further stated, that he could prove, by the most 
respectable testimony, that the said A. Wingard, in his lifetime,
after the year 1818, always spoke of him as entitled to his freedom,
upon payment of the said fifty dollars; and that he had
solemnly contracted with the petitioner for his freedom. It states,
further, that he brings into Court the fifty dollars, ready to be
paid to the defendant, the executrix of the said Abraham's will,
but she refuses to manumit him; he therefore prays the Court to
decree that she should, by a good deed, manumit him, and set
him free.</p>

<p>The jury, in a special verdict, found the facts to be nearly as
stated in the petition; and further, that in 1816 and 1817, about 
the time the agreement was made, the said Abraham Wingard
was largely indebted, but believed not to be insolvent; that in
1818 and 1819 property in Georgetown fell, and there was more
doubt of his solvency. That he died about January, 1820, and 
his estate has been found to be largely insolvent. That the defendant
holds the petitioner, as executrix, to be accounted for
according to law. That the petitioner is under forty-five years
of age, and able to gain a livelihood by labor; whereupon the
jury say, that if, upon the facts above stated and found, the Court
should be of opinion that the petitioner has any claim, in law or
equity, to his freedom, then they find for the petitioner, and if
otherwise, then for the defendant.</p>

<p>Mr. Key and Mr. Jones, for the petitioner. Equity will not
regard the want of an intervening trustee between the master and 
slave. As in a case of a contract directly between husband and
wife, equity will enforce the contract. So, it will not regard the
want of a legal deed of manumission. It considers that done
which ought to be done. There being a valuable consideration,
equity will consider the master himself as a trustee for the benefit

<pb n="p302" facs="oscys.report.0088.001.003.jpg"/>

of the slave. There is no law to prevent a verbal manumission.
In England a villein may be enfranchised by implication. They
<bibl type="code">Act of Maryland, 1752, c. 1</bibl>, which prohibited manumission by
verbal order, was repealed by the <bibl type="code">Act of 1796, c. 67</bibl>. Such manumission
was lawful before the Act of 1752, or it would not have
been necessary to pass that act to prohibit it. The opinion of
Mr. Dulany, in <bibl type="case">1 Har. &amp; McHenry, 563</bibl>, that slaves "could
have no legal remedy against their master for any matter anterior 
to their manumission," is not law now. The Act of 1796 does 
not forbid such a manumission. The only restraints in that act
are, the age and capacity of the slave, and the interfering rights
of creditors. This was not a contract in fraud of creditors. The
case of <bibl type="case">Kettletas v. Fleet, 7 Johns. 328, 375</bibl>, shows that the Court
will enforce an executory contract with a slave; and the case of
<bibl type="case">Sally v. Beatty</bibl>, from South Carolina, in <bibl type="case">1 Bay's Rep. 260</bibl>, shows
that a slave may acquire property. Here the contract is carried
into effect. The slave has been actually set free, and the consideration
money has been paid.</p>

<p>Mr. Augustus Taney, contrà.</p>

<p>There is no case under the Maryland law in which a verbal
order has been deemed a manumission, either in law or equity.
A villein, in England, could not be enfranchised without deed, or
matter of record. A suit by the lord, against his villein, was a
record-acknowledgement of his freedom. The laws of slavery, in
New York, differ from the laws of Maryland. The New York
cases, therefore, do not apply. Besides, there is a difference between
a contract and a benevolence. This is a mere benevolence.
There was no consideration; for all that the slave could earn belonged
to the master. A mere benevolence must be completely
executed. It cannot be enforced as a contract.</p>

<p>The statute requiring certain solemnities, as necessary to the
validity of manumission, is virtually negative of all other modes
of manumission. General policy requires such a restriction.</p>

<p>If Abraham Wingard himself were now present, and a party
to this suit, and were insolvent, the contract could not be carried
into effect to the prejudice of creditors. Their rights intervene
before the contract is executed, and must prevail.</p>

<p>To every contract there must be two parties competent to contract.
The petitioner is still a slave, and, in law, incapable of contracting.</p>

<p>The Court, having taken time to consider, ordered judgment
to be entered up for the defendant.</p>

</div2>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
